Wired

May 31, 2020 | Author: Flavie HalaisFlavie Halais Want to Fix Urban Sprawl? Ditch the Cul-de-Sac Streets arranged in grids, with few dead-ends, encourage walking and transit. But in developing countries, growing cities are taking the opposite route. https://www.wired.com/story/fix-urban-sprawl-ditch-cul-de-sac/

May 30, 2020 | Author: Flavie HalaisFlavie Halais In the Walking Capitals of the World, Drivers Still Rule the Road In sub-Saharan Africa, about half of travelers move around by foot. Yet in its cities, conditions for pedestrians remain incredibly dangerous. https://www.wired.com/story/in-the-walking-capitals-of-the-world-drivers-still-rule-the-road/

May 24, 2020 | Author: Flavie HalaisFlavie Halais Informal Transit Is Crucial for Some. Can It Weather Covid-19? The pandemic highlights the vulnerability of workers for private transportation services, which are essential to mobility in global south cities. https://www.wired.com/story/informal-transit-crucial-can-weather-covid-19/

May 19, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A Lawmaker Wants Fast Trains to Rev Up the US Economy US representative Seth Moulton of Massachusetts proposes spending $205 billion over 5 years to connect Chicago with Atlanta, Portland with Vancouver. https://www.wired.com/story/lawmaker-wants-fast-trains-rev-us-economy/

May 11, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Elon Musk Defies Lockdown Orders and Reopens Tesla’s Factory The CEO sued a California county over the weekend and threatened to move the company to Texas—his latest tangle with government authorities. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-defies-lockdown-orders-reopens-tesla-factory/

May 11, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Pandemic Strands Some Ship Crews at Sea, Others On Shore Travel restrictions are blocking some marine workers from reaching their assigned ships. That’s forcing others on extended tours.  https://www.wired.com/story/pandemic-strands-ship-crews-sea-others-shore/

May 10, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Fantastical Plans Are on Hold, and More Car News This Week The Covid-19 pandemic will delay the arrival of flying cars, and Google sibling Sidewalk Labs abandons plans to remake part of Toronto’s waterfront. https://www.wired.com/story/fantastical-plans-hold-car-news/

May 9, 2020 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Covid-19 Casts a Dark Cloud Over the Flying Car Future An economic slump is no good for a long shot business that’s just starting to take off.  https://www.wired.com/story/coronavirus-covid-air-taxi-flying-car-impact/

May 7, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Alphabet’s Sidewalk Labs Scraps Its Ambitious Toronto Project The Google sibling envisioned a tech-enabled and eco-friendly neighborhood. But residents rebelled over plans to collect and use their data, among other things. https://www.wired.com/story/alphabets-sidewalk-labs-scraps-ambitious-toronto-project/

May 7, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall As Cities Reopen, Outdoor Dining May Provide a Lifeline Restaurants are anxious to expand beyond takeout, and some researchers believe open-air transmission of the coronavirus is rare. https://www.wired.com/story/cities-reopen-outdoor-dining-lifeline/

May 6, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Sleeker Lidar Moves Volvo Closer to Selling a Self-Driving Car Using technology from Silicon Valley’s Luminar, the Swedish automaker plans to offer completely autonomous highway driving by 2022.  https://www.wired.com/story/sleeker-lidar-moves-volvo-closer-selling-self-driving-car/

May 5, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall California Sues Uber and Lyft to Classify Drivers as Employees The state and three cities say the ride-hail companies are violating a new state law. The suit could lead to tens of millions of dollars in fines. https://www.wired.com/story/california-sues-uber-lyft-classify-drivers-employees/

May 4, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Covid-19 Spurs a Road Repair Boom—and Threatens a Bust Empty highways clear the way for speedier construction projects, but loss of fuel taxes could bring them to a halt.  https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-spurs-road-repair-boom-threatens-bust/

May 3, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Fewer Wrecks, Grounded Planes, and More Car News This Week Stay-at-home orders mean less traffic and fewer serious crashes, saving lives and money. Plus, Elon Musk does it again.  https://www.wired.com/story/fewer-wrecks-grounded-planes-more-car-news-this-week/

May 1, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Elon Musk Says Tesla Stock Is ‘Too High’—and It Quickly Falls An early-morning tweet punctuates a week in which the CEO has complained loudly and often about coronavirus-induced lockdowns. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-tesla-stock-too-high-falls/

April 30, 2020 | Author: Jonathan M. Gitlin, Ars TechnicaJonathan M. Gitlin, Ars Technica Jaguar Envisions Car Design for a Post-Pandemic World Julian Thomson, the automaker’s director of design, shares his predictions for what drivers can look forward to. https://www.wired.com/story/jaguar-envisions-car-design-for-a-post-pandemic-world/

April 29, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla Posts Another Profit as Musk Slams Virus Restrictions The CEO has criticized shelter-in-place orders, which have forced the closure of the company’s California assembly plant. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-posts-profit-musk-slams-virus-restrictions/

April 29, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Planes Are Still Flying, but Covid-19 Recovery Will Be Tough Air travel is down more than 90 percent from last year, and analysts say the rebound will be slower than following 9/11 or the financial crisis. https://www.wired.com/story/planes-flying-covid-19-recovery-tough/

April 28, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Delivery Robots Aren’t Ready—When They Could Be Needed Most Sheltering in place has driven up demand for deliveries, but machines still have trouble confronting the unpredictability of the real world. https://www.wired.com/story/delivery-robots-arent-ready-when-needed-most/

April 27, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies A Coronavirus Silver Lining: Less Driving, Fewer Crashes A study finds that California lockdown restrictions reduced crashes that kill or seriously injure people to 200 a day, down from 400 in the same period last year. https://www.wired.com/story/coronavirus-silver-lining-less-driving-fewer-crashes/

April 26, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Drone Deliveries, Food Supplies, and More Car News This Week US-based Zipline is using drones to deliver virus tests and supplies in Ghana. Plus: Rerouting the nation’s food supply is proving difficult. https://www.wired.com/story/drone-deliveries-food-supplies-more-car-news/

April 22, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Drones Take Flight to Carry Covid-19 Tests to Labs in Africa Zipline, whose pilotless craft are ferrying kits and protective gear in Ghana, wants to launch a similar service in North Carolina.  https://www.wired.com/story/drones-flight-carry-covid-tests-labs-africa/

April 19, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Closed Streets, Pumping Air, and More Car News This Week Cities are remaking themselves for pedestrians and bikes, while hospitals are shape-shifting to handle the tide of Covid-19 patients. https://www.wired.com/story/closed-streets-pumping-air-more-car-news/

April 18, 2020 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The Air Force’s Venerable F-15 Gets a Makeover An upgrade to the fighter jet, to be first deployed with Qatar’s Air Force, is designed to complement the newer F-35 in combat missions.  https://www.wired.com/story/air-forces-venerable-f-15-gets-makeover/

April 15, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Hospitals Quickly Reshape to Treat Covid-19 Patients Health care facilities are hastily constructing new entrances and testing facilities, installing glass doors, and crafting face shields to protect workers. https://www.wired.com/story/hospitals-quickly-reshape-treat-covid-19-patients/

April 14, 2020 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams As Other Carmakers Retrench, Volvo’s Battery Lab Plugs Away Despite Covid-19, an economic slowdown, and low gas prices,  the Swedish carmaker pushes forward with its electrification plans. https://www.wired.com/story/other-carmakers-retrench-volvos-battery-lab/

April 13, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Pandemic Could Be an Opportunity to Remake Cities Cities from Bogota to Oakland are closing streets to make room for pedestrians and bikers. Urbanists think we’d be healthier if such changes were permanent. https://www.wired.com/story/pandemic-opportunity-remake-cities/

April 12, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Gig Work Relief, Auto Care, and More Car News This Week Ride-sharing drivers qualify for jobless benefits—with a catch. Plus, Google and Apple say they can track Covid-19 patients and still protect privacy. https://www.wired.com/story/gig-work-relief-auto-care-more-car-news/

April 8, 2020 | Author: Jonathan M. Gitlin, Ars TechnicaJonathan M. Gitlin, Ars Technica How to Care for Your Car While Sheltering in Place Being completely sedentary isn’t just bad for people—it’s bad for vehicles, too. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-care-for-your-car-while-sheltering-in-place/

April 8, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Gig Workers’ New Unemployment Benefits Won’t Come Quickly The $2 trillion coronavirus relief bill makes contractors eligible for unemployment insurance. But states want pay stubs that ride-hail drivers don’t have. https://www.wired.com/story/gig-workers-unemployment-benefits-wont-come-quickly/

April 5, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall GM Pivots to Building Ventilators, and More Car News This Week The automaker is among several industrial companies applying their mass-manufacturing know-how to making much-needed medical equipment. https://www.wired.com/story/gm-pivots-building-ventilators-more-car-news/

April 2, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The High-Stakes Race to Build More Ventilators The US is short of ventilators to help Covid-19 patients breathe. Ford, GM, and satellite-launch company Virgin Orbit are trying to fill the gap. https://www.wired.com/story/race-build-more-ventilators-coronavirus/

April 1, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Trump Eases the Way for More Gas Guzzlers  The administration reversed Obama-era rules that set strict fuel-economy standards, setting up a fight with states including California. https://www.wired.com/story/trump-eases-way-more-gas-guzzlers/

April 1, 2020 | Author: Jon GertnerJon Gertner Rivian Wants to Bring Electric Trucks to the Masses Can the automotive upstart break America’s addiction to carbon-spewing pickups and SUVs? With Amazon on its side, it might have a chance. https://www.wired.com/story/rivian-race-design-all-electric-pickup-truck/

April 1, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies To Cut Carbon, Ditch Air Travel—and Get on the Right Track Some environmentally conscious people are trying to give up flying. For some trips, there’s a great, cleaner alternative: It’s called a train. https://www.wired.com/story/cut-carbon-ditch-planes-take-trains/

April 1, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Build Cities for Bikes, Buses, and Feet—Not Cars San Francisco’s MTA boss Jeff Tumlin is one of a new breed of planner trying to kick cars out of the city. That’s good for business, good for people, and amazing for the planet. https://www.wired.com/story/cities-without-cars-san-francisco-jeff-tumlin/

April 1, 2020 | Author: Christie AschwandenChristie Aschwanden How Airlines Are Trying to Boost Efficiency and Cut Emissions Winglets. Better engines. Lighter materials. The industry is trying everything it can. But the best fix for the planet would be for us to stop flying so much. https://www.wired.com/story/planes-airlines-increase-fuel-efficiency-cut-emissions/

April 1, 2020 | Author: Samanth SubramanianSamanth Subramanian The Cargo Industry’s Quest to Curb Carbon-Belching Ships Container ships burn some of the dirtiest fuel there is and spew out huge amounts of greenhouse gas. But the business is poised for a dramatic shift. https://www.wired.com/story/cargo-industry-decarbonize-carbon-belching-ships/

March 30, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Covid-19 Pandemic Aggravates Disputes Around Gig Work Workers want more compensation and better protection against illness from companies that don’t consider them employees. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-pandemic-aggravates-disputes-gig-work/

March 30, 2020 | Author: Alex Davies, Aarian MarshallAlex Davies and Aarian Marshall Public Transit Cuts Hurt ‘Essential’ Workers Who Need It Most Bus and train systems are trimming schedules amid plummeting ridership and mounting losses. But riders are being forced to choose between health and financial security. https://www.wired.com/story/transit-cuts-hurt-workers-who-need-most/

March 29, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A Hospital Train, DIY Face Shields, and More Car News This Week The French repurpose a high-speed TGV to ferry coronavirus patients,  while engineers and automakers step up to help those on the medical front line. https://www.wired.com/story/hospital-train-diy-face-shields-more-car-news/

March 29, 2020 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams A Rest Stop Where Flying Cars Can Recharge Beta Technologies’ prototype helipad and base station for electric air taxis could also help route emergency supplies in a crisis. https://www.wired.com/story/rest-stop-flying-cars-recharge/

March 28, 2020 | Author: Brett BerkBrett Berk BMW’s i4 Electric Concept Comes With a Hans Zimmer Score To fill the aural vacuum left by the disappearance of the engine, BMW brought in a ringer.  https://www.wired.com/story/bmw-i4-electric-score-hans-zimmer/

March 26, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies France’s Virus Train Moves Patients to Less Hard-Hit Areas The national railroad system converted a TGV high-speed train to move 20 Covid-19 patients from Strasbourg to calmer hospitals in the Loire Valley. https://www.wired.com/story/frances-virus-train-patients-less-hard-hit-areas/

March 26, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall New Rules Could Finally Clear the Way for Self-Driving Cars For the first time, the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration is weighing in on autonomous vehicles with no driver behind the wheel—or no wheel at all. https://www.wired.com/story/news-rules-clear-way-self-driving-cars/

March 26, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies What World War II Can Teach Us About Fighting the Coronavirus Some manufacturers are racing to make ventilators, respirators, and face shields. But the situation is nothing like it was in the 1940s. https://www.wired.com/story/what-wwii-can-teach-fighting-coronavirus/

March 24, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall We’re Not Going to Run Out of Food—so Don’t Panic Shop Food producers, distributors, and warehouse operators say supplies are plentiful, so long as stores can be restocked. https://www.wired.com/story/not-going-run-out-food-dont-panic-shop/

March 22, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Plant Shutdowns, Vital Truckers, and More Car News This Week Coronavirus fears lead the big automakers—including a stubborn Tesla—to suspend operations, while airlines are hauling more goods, fewer people. https://www.wired.com/story/plant-shutdowns-vital-truckers-more-car-news/

March 20, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall As Covid-19 Spreads, Truckers Need to Keep on Trucking The demand for hospital equipment, groceries and, yes, toilet paper has big rigs rolling and truck stops adapting. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-spreads-truckers-keep-trucking/

March 19, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Anthony Levandowski Pleads Guilty to Stealing Waymo Secrets The cofounder of Google’s self-driving car program will likely go to prison for taking confidential company documents before he left in 2016. https://www.wired.com/story/anthony-levandowski-pleads-guilty-stealing-waymo-secrets/

March 19, 2020 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Covid-19 Is Bad for the Auto Industry—and Even Worse for EVs Factory shutdowns signal a troubled road ahead for carmakers, while low gas prices could hit electric vehicles hard.  https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-bad-for-auto-industry-worse-for-evs/

March 18, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Navy Deploys Two Hospital Ships as the Coronavirus Spreads The Comfort and the Mercy won’t handle Covid-19 patients because of their close quarters. An ER doctor questions if they should be used at all.  https://www.wired.com/story/navy-deploys-2-hospital-ships-coronavirus-spreads/

March 17, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Sheriff Tells Tesla It’s Not as ‘Essential’ as Musk Thinks The company operated its California factory normally Tuesday, despite a “shelter-in-place” order. Then, county officials said it had to close. https://www.wired.com/story/sheriff-tells-tesla-not-essential-musk-thinks/

March 17, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Airlines Use Empty Passenger Jets to Ease the Cargo Crunch People aren’t flying because of the Covid-19 pandemic. Now, some carriers are putting planes back in service to carry freight instead. https://www.wired.com/story/airlines-use-empty-passenger-jets-ease-cargo-crunch/

March 15, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A Travel Ban, Gig Economy Risks, and More Car News This Week Already ailing airlines are hit with new woes as Trump bars visitors from Europe for 30 days. Plus, is anything not canceled?  https://www.wired.com/story/travel-ban-gig-economy-risks-more-car-news/

March 13, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Trump’s Europe Travel Ban Delivers Another Blow to Airlines Americans can still get home, but it will be tougher to find a seat as airlines cut flights and lay off workers. https://www.wired.com/story/trumps-europe-travel-ban-delivers-blow-airlines/

March 12, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Coronavirus Will Make the 2020 Census Even Trickier Funding is tight, and a proposed citizenship question has made some people wary. Minorities and low-income Americans are most at risk of being missed.  https://www.wired.com/story/coronavirus-make-2020-census-trickier/

March 8, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Canceled Flights, New Waymo Sensors, and More Car News This Week Airlines are trimming their schedules and cleaning their remaining planes more thoroughly, as fears of Covid-19 cut air travel. https://www.wired.com/story/cancelled-flights-new-waymo-sensors-car-news/

March 7, 2020 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Goodyear’s Concept Tire Regenerates Burned-Off Rubber The reCharge tire works like a stick of lip balm, pushing up new tread as the old stuff wears away. https://www.wired.com/story/goodyear-recharge-tire-concept/

March 6, 2020 | Author: Aarian Marshall, Alex DaviesAarian Marshall and Alex Davies In Planes and Trains, Mini-Mops and Fog Machines Battle Coronavirus  Airlines and transit agencies are responding to the health emergency with gloved attendants, less touching, and deeper, more frequent cleaning. https://www.wired.com/story/planes-trains-mini-mops-fog-machines-battle-coronavirus/

March 4, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Waymo’s Self-Driving Jaguars Arrive With New, Homegrown Tech The Google sibling company’s own engineers redesigned the lidar, radar, and cameras that guide the car. https://www.wired.com/story/waymos-self-driving-jaguars-arrive-new-homegrown-tech/

March 4, 2020 | Author: Flavie HalaisFlavie Halais Is Your Data Being Collected? These Signs Will Tell You Where Alphabet’s Sidewalk Labs is testing icons that provide “digital transparency” when information is collected in public spaces.  https://www.wired.com/story/data-collected-signs-will-tell-where/

March 2, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Plane Contrails Have a Surprising Effect on Global Warming The wispy ice clouds formed by jet exhaust help trap heat near the Earth’s surface. But small changes in altitude can dampen the effect, a study says. https://www.wired.com/story/plane-contrails-surprising-effect-global-warming/

March 1, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Fits and Starts for Autonomous Vehicles, and More Car News This Week A federal safety board criticizes regulators’ laissez-faire approach to AVs, as California reports 2.9 million miles of robot driving in the state last year.  https://www.wired.com/story/fits-starts-autonomous-vehicles-more-car-news/

March 1, 2020 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Flying Car Developers Get a Boost From the Air Force The Pentagon wants to make sure the fledgling electric aviation industry doesn’t follow the path of small drones and move offshore. https://www.wired.com/story/flying-car-developers-get-boost-air-force/

February 29, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Feds Ban a Self-Driving Shuttle Fleet From Carrying People Regulators have been hands-off on autonomous vehicles, even after deaths and injuries. But they acted quickly after a woman was hurt in Columbus this week.  https://www.wired.com/story/feds-ban-self-driving-shuttle-fleet-carrying-people/

February 27, 2020 | Author: Alex Davies, Aarian MarshallAlex Davies and Aarian Marshall In California, Which Self-Driving Cars Log the Most Miles? New reports show autonomous vehicles from 36 companies covered 2.9 million miles in the state last year, up from 2.1 million in 2018. https://www.wired.com/story/california-self-driving-cars-log-most-miles/

February 26, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies How Self-Driving Car Makers Measure Their Own Progress New reports track how often humans need to take control of autonomous vehicles being tested. That’s a lousy way to assess the nascent industry. https://www.wired.com/story/how-self-driving-car-makers-measure-progress/

February 26, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Your Ad Here—Uber Moves Into Car-Top Digital Billboards Uber’s ad program gives drivers a chance to earn more, and gives the ride-hailing company a new revenue stream as it struggles to become profitable. https://www.wired.com/story/your-ad-here-uber-car-top-digital-billboards/

February 25, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A Safety Board Faults Tesla and Regulators in a Fatal 2018 Crash The National Transportation Safety Board says the automaker should restrict use of its Autopilot feature and better detect when drivers are paying attention. https://www.wired.com/story/safety-board-faults-tesla-regulators-fatal-2018-crash/

February 23, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A Cruise Ship Quarantine, a Hunt for Cheaters, and More Car News This Week Plus: A new helicopter ditches the traditional tail rotor for four fans, which could make the devices safer and quieter. https://www.wired.com/story/cruise-ship-quarantine-hunt-cheaters-car-news/

February 22, 2020 | Author: Nicole Kobie, WIRED UKNicole Kobie, WIRED UK A Cobalt Crisis Could Put the Brakes on Electric Car Sales First it was lithium, now it’s cobalt. Factories are churning out only so many batteries, and it’s creating a bottleneck.  https://www.wired.com/story/a-cobalt-crisis-could-put-the-brakes-on-electric-car-sales/

February 22, 2020 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Bell’s New Design Could Make Helicopters Quieter—and Safer The new aircraft, which ditches the noisy tail rotor for four fans, may also be a step toward electric-powered flight. https://www.wired.com/story/bells-design-helicopters-quieter-safer/

February 18, 2020 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb New Uber Rules, Bomber-Inspired Jet Design, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-rule-changes-airbus-maverick/

February 18, 2020 | Author: Timothy B. Lee, Ars TechnicaTimothy B. Lee, Ars Technica New Data Backs Up Details in a Fatal 2018 Tesla Model X Crash Newly released documents confirm that the driver experienced a glitch multiple times before the deadly crash, though it’s unclear whether he reported it to Tesla. https://www.wired.com/story/new-data-backs-up-details-in-a-fatal-2018-tesla-model-x-crash/

February 18, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber Changes Its Rules, and Drivers Adjust Their Strategies In response to a new law, the ride-hail service shows California drivers where a ride would go and how much it would pay. Drivers are learning when to say “No.” https://www.wired.com/story/uber-changes-rules-drivers-adjust-strategies/

February 17, 2020 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams How a Street-Smart Supercar Got Ready for the Racetrack To build an NSX for racing, Acura had to “dumb down” its model by omitting its smartest part: the electric motor. https://www.wired.com/story/acura-nsx-street-smart-supercar-racetrack/

February 16, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Augmented Reality From the Driver’s Seat, and More Car News This Week Plus: Retailers aim to improve delivery performance, and Airbus displays a model of a new blended-wing plane. https://www.wired.com/story/augmented-reality-drivers-seat-more-car-news/

February 16, 2020 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Airbus’ Maveric Brings B-2 Bomber Style to Passenger Jets Starting with the small-scale model Maveric, the planemaker says this new design could produce major efficiency gains.  https://www.wired.com/story/airbus-maveric-blended-wing-jet/

February 15, 2020 | Author: Flavie HalaisFlavie Halais Vexed by Missed Deliveries? Data-Savvy Tech Can Help New services aim to ensure packages reach the right destination, on time, and preferably where someone is there to accept them.  https://www.wired.com/story/missed-deliveries-data-savvy-tech-can-help/

February 12, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber and Lyft’s Financials Reveal Two Ride-Hailing Strategies For the moment, investors prefer Uber’s broader global footprint and side hustles such as its Eats food delivery business. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-lyfts-financials-reveal-two-ride-hailing-strategies/

February 12, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies With In-Car AR, Drivers Get a New View of the Road Ahead Navigation screens with augmented reality are the latest in an arms race among upscale auto makers like Mercedes and Cadillac. https://www.wired.com/story/in-car-ar-drivers-get-new-view-road-ahead/

February 11, 2020 | Author: Jonathan M. Gitlin, Ars TechnicaJonathan M. Gitlin, Ars Technica A 747 Set a New Record for Crossing the Atlantic Thanks to Storm Ciara, the British Airways flight made it from New York to London in just 4 hours and 56 minutes. https://www.wired.com/story/747-set-new-record-for-crossing-the-atlantic/

February 9, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Faked Traffic Jams, Soaring Tesla Stock, and Other Auto News A German artist tricks Google Maps into seeing gridlock, and the market shows Elon Musk love. https://www.wired.com/story/faked-traffic-jams-soaring-tesla-stock-auto-news/

February 9, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Investors Hit the Brakes on Automotive Startups Fervor for self-driving tech cools, and an accelerator in Detroit shuts down. https://www.wired.com/story/investors-hit-brakes-automotive-startups/

February 8, 2020 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Cadillac Brings Self-Driving Smarts to the New Escalade Adding Super Cruise to the ever-popular SUV means more drivers can hit the highway, no hands needed. https://www.wired.com/story/2021-escalade-super-cruise-self-driving/

February 6, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies This Vehicle Has No Side-View Mirrors—and It’s Legal Self-driving startup Nuro is the first company to win an exemption from federal safety requirements. It won’t be the last. https://www.wired.com/story/vehicle-no-side-view-mirrors-legal/

February 6, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla Is Finally Cruising, and Investors Are Going for a Joyride The electric-auto maker is valued more highly than Volkswagen, which makes roughly 20 times as many cars. Tesla’s stock is also up 71 percent this year alone. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-cruising-investors-going-joyride/

February 3, 2020 | Author: Will KnightWill Knight Snow and Ice Pose a Vexing Obstacle for Self-Driving Cars Most testing of autonomous vehicles until now has been in sunny, dry climates. That will have to change before the technology will be useful everywhere. https://www.wired.com/story/snow-ice-pose-vexing-obstacle-self-driving-cars/

February 2, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber in Vancouver, a Vehicle Ban in SF, and Other Car News British Columbia finally welcomes ride hail, while San Francisco’s main drag goes car-free. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-vancouver-vehicle-ban-other-car-news/

February 1, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Vancouver Wants to Avoid Other Cities’ Mistakes With Uber and Lyft Canadian officials approve ride-hailing long after it’s become a staple elsewhere, with tough rules on fares and driver licensing. https://www.wired.com/story/vancouver-wants-avoid-other-cities-mistakes-uber-lyft/

January 29, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla Reports Strong Results, but Challenges Loom Ahead The electric-auto maker posted $105 million in fourth-quarter profit on $7.4 billion in revenue. It delivered a record 112,000 vehicles.  https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-strong-results-challenges-ahead/

January 29, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies San Francisco Joins the Move to Ban Cars From a Major Street New York has cleared Times Square and 14th Street, while Oslo is banishing drivers from its city center. https://www.wired.com/story/san-francisco-ban-cars-major-street/

January 28, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The World’s Most Traffic-Choked Cities, Ranked Cities in Asia and South America dominate the “top” of the list. Los Angeles, the US’s worst, finishes 31st. https://www.wired.com/story/worlds-most-traffic-choked-cities-ranked/

January 27, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Probe of the Kobe Bryant Crash Will Examine If Fog Played a Role The helicopter was flying under “special visual flight rules” that allow pilots to fly through low-visibility conditions. https://www.wired.com/story/probe-kobe-bryant-crash-fog-role/

January 26, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall An Origin Story, Smart Headlights, and Other Car News General Motors’ Cruise unit shows off its self-driving concept vehicle, while Hyundai smothers road noise.  https://www.wired.com/story/origin-story-smart-headlights-car-news/

January 26, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies New Safety Gizmos Are Making Car Insurance More Expensive The high cost of repairing sensor-packed vehicles outpaces the savings from fewer crashes. https://www.wired.com/story/safety-gizmos-making-car-insurance-more-expensive/

January 23, 2020 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Hyundai’s Luxury SUV Mixes Mics and Math for a Silent Ride The Genesis GV80 comes with noise-canceling tech to do away with the annoying hum of rolling rubber. https://www.wired.com/story/hyundai-genesis-gv80-suv-noise-cancelling/

January 22, 2020 | Author: Sean Gallagher, Ars TechnicaSean Gallagher, Ars Technica The 737 MAX Delay Is Just One of Boeing’s Many Problems Issues inside the company aren’t limited to its commercial airliner business—even the space and defense divisions are suffering.  https://www.wired.com/story/the-737-max-delay-is-just-one-of-boeings-many-problems/

January 22, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Feds Want to Rein In ‘Emotional Service’ Animals on Planes The viral photos of mini-horses in cabin seats may be numbered, as the Transportation Department announces an effort to ground “Noah’s Ark in the air.” https://www.wired.com/story/feds-rein-emotional-service-animals-planes/

January 22, 2020 | Author: Brett BerkBrett Berk Laser Headlights Can Make Roads Brighter—and Cars Smarter The new lamps in BMW’s M5 are more precise and efficient than their predecessors, and could someday broadcast data.  https://www.wired.com/story/laser-headlights-can-make-roads-brighter-and-cars-smarter/

January 21, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies GM’s Latest Has Sensors and Room for 6, but No Steering Wheel Cruise reveals the Origin, its planned self-driving vehicle, meant to be shared by riders in a ride-hail service. https://www.wired.com/story/gms-sensors-room-6-no-steering-wheel/

January 21, 2020 | Author: Flavie HalaisFlavie Halais Making Public Transit Fairer to Women Demands Way More Data Most transit systems aren’t designed for women, who tend to run errands and care for children. But cities can’t fix a problem they don’t understand. https://www.wired.com/story/making-public-transit-fairer-to-women-demands-data/

January 20, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A Move to Make Auto-Safety Features Speak the Same Language Super Cruise? Traffic Jam Assist? Autopilot? Translation for all of the above: Keep your eyes on the road! https://www.wired.com/story/auto-safety-features-speak-same-language/

January 19, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Electric Delivery Vans, Tesla Stock, and Other Car News Home delivery is where the action is for real estate developers and EV startups.  https://www.wired.com/story/electric-delivery-vans-tesla-stock-car-news/

January 18, 2020 | Author: Jennifer Ouellette, Ars TechnicaJennifer Ouellette, Ars Technica At Last, Physicists Confirm the Fastest Way to Board a Plane Turns out letting slower passengers board first—like travelers with small children, or those who need assistance—really is faster. https://www.wired.com/story/study-confirms-how-to-optimize-airplane-boarding/

January 18, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall In Paris, Ecommerce Warehouses Get a Chic Makeover Online ordering means more deliveries to more places. One Paris hub sports a data center, offices, sports facilities like tennis courts, and an urban farm.  https://www.wired.com/story/paris-ecommerce-warehouses-get-chic-makeover/

January 16, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies A $100 Million Investment Pulls an EV Startup Out of Stealth Mode Hyundai and Kia are backing Arrival, a startup British maker of electric delivery vans, a good use case for EVs. https://www.wired.com/story/investment-pulls-ev-startup-out-stealth/

January 14, 2020 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Aston Martin’s $189,000 DBX SUV Conquers the Arabian Desert The luxury brand wants its first SUV to be a multi-terrain all-star, and that means leaving the pavement behind. https://www.wired.com/story/aston-martin-dbx-suv-off-road/

January 14, 2020 | Author: Timothy B. Lee, Ars TechnicaTimothy B. Lee, Ars Technica Tesla Is Now Worth More Than Ford and GM—Combined Its stock has soared past $500 per share. That’s a hopeful sign that the company might finally be executing smoothly. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-worth-more-than-ford-gm-combined/

January 12, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A Sony Concept, Flying Taxis, and More Car News This Week It’s déjà vu all over again at CES, where the future of transportation isn’t that different from what we have now. https://www.wired.com/story/sony-concept-flying-taxis-car-news/

January 10, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A New Law for Gig Workers Reaches Beyond Ride-Hail Drivers AB 5 was designed to support Uber and Lyft contractors. But it also leaves therapists, truckers, and psychologists struggling to understand their new role. https://www.wired.com/story/law-gig-workers-reaches-beyond-rideshare/

January 9, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Feds Are Content to Let Cars Drive, and Regulate, Themselves  A new Transportation Department policy on self-driving cars is long on boosting the industry and short on ensuring its safety. https://www.wired.com/story/feds-content-cars-drive-regulate-themselves/

January 8, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Sony’s Concept Car Puts Entertainment in the Driver’s Seat The Vision-S showcases big screens, sensors, and a supremely comfortable ride. https://www.wired.com/story/sony-concept-car-puts-entertainment-drivers-seat/

January 8, 2020 | Author: Andrew ZaleskiAndrew Zaleski Meet Charpu, the Drone-Racing Megastar Who Doesn’t Feel Like Racing The only problem with the drone world’s best-known pilot? He doesn’t really want to race. In fact, he finds it kind of boring. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/meet-charpu-drone-racing-megastar-doesnt-feel-like-racing/

January 8, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies How GM Beat Tesla to the First True Mass-Market Electric Car The true significance of the Bolt: An old-school company with immense manufacturing capacity has gotten to the 200-mile, $30K electric vehicle first. https://www.wired.com/2016/01/gm-electric-car-chevy-bolt-mary-barra/

January 8, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies There Are Too Many Lidar Companies. They Can’t All Survive A few years ago, scores of startups promised to build the hardware that grants self-driving cars the gift of sight. Now comes the shakeout. https://www.wired.com/story/too-many-lidar-companies-cant-all-survive/

January 7, 2020 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Bell and Hyundai Soar Into the Air Taxi Race  At CES, the helicopter maker and the global manufacturing giant unveil their concepts for flying urban mobility. https://www.wired.com/story/bell-hyundai-air-taxi-race/

January 5, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A Strange New Decade, Tesla’s Strong Sales, and More Car News This Week Tesla delivered 367,500 cars last year, a 50 percent jump from 2018. The company’s stock also surpassed $420, a symbolic figure for CEO Elon Musk. https://www.wired.com/story/strange-new-decade-teslas-strong-sales/

January 4, 2020 | Author: Jonathan M. Gitlin, Ars TechnicaJonathan M. Gitlin, Ars Technica The Former CEO of Nissan Was Likely Smuggled Out of Japan The Japanese government still doesn’t know exactly how Carlos Ghosn, who was under house arrest, managed to flee to Lebanon. https://www.wired.com/story/former-ceo-nissan-smuggled-out-of-japan/

January 3, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Now the Courts Will Decide Whether Uber Drivers Are Employees A California law aimed at requiring gig economy companies to classify workers as employees took effect January 1. That hardly settled the matter. https://www.wired.com/story/courts-decide-uber-drivers-employees/

January 3, 2020 | Author: Adrienne SoAdrienne So Segway Is Bringing the Hoverchairs From WALL-E to Life You’ll soon be able to scoot around town—at 24 mph—without even having to stand up. https://www.wired.com/story/segway-bringing-hoverchairs-wall-e-life/

January 2, 2020 | Author: Flavie HalaisFlavie Halais Cities Struggle to Boost Ridership With ‘Uber for Transit’ Schemes Helsinki, Los Angeles, Shanghai, Singapore, and other metros have been experimenting with on-demand buses—and not seeing a lot of success. https://www.wired.com/story/cities-on-demand-transit-buses/

January 1, 2020 | Author: Flavie HalaisFlavie Halais Cities Race to Slow Climate Change—and Improve Life for All Mayors across the world say we all need to consider how urban planning and climate intersect with well-being. https://www.wired.com/story/cities-climate-change-equity-paris-agreement/

December 26, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies When the Transportation Revolution Hit the Real World Ten years ago, they promised us self-driving cars. We got a scooter surge, clashes with regulators, and the brutal realities of mobility. https://www.wired.com/story/when-transportation-revolution-hit-real-world/

December 22, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Car Share Shrinks, a Tax Break Vanishes, and More Car News This Week Share Now says it is leaving North America, and Tesla buyers will no longer get help from Uncle Sam for their EVs (and GM buyers are next). https://www.wired.com/story/car-share-shrinks-tax-break-vanishes-more-car-news/

December 20, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Feds Call Helicopter That Crashed in NYC River a ‘Death Trap’ An NTSB investigation faults the companies behind the sightseeing flight for a slew of safety failures, which resulted in five deaths. https://www.wired.com/story/ntsb-flynyon-nyc-crash-investigation-report/

December 19, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Share Now Is the Latest Car-Share Service to Fold The Daimler- and BMW-owned service says it will leave North America as part of an ongoing shakeout in the industry. https://www.wired.com/story/share-now-latest-car-share-service-fold/

December 18, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Want a Tax Credit for Buying an Electric Vehicle? Move Fast Congress declines to extend the EV credit program beyond January 1—meaning Tesla buyers won’t be eligible for credits for the first time since 2009.  https://www.wired.com/story/want-tax-credit-buying-electric-vehicle-move-fast/

December 16, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies A Racing Champ Critiques Cinema’s Greatest Driving Scenes Wyatt Knox, an instructor at the Team O’Neil driving school, analyzes key scenes from The Fast and the Furious, Baby Driver, and The Man With the Golden Gun. https://www.wired.com/story/racing-champ-critiques-cinemas-greatest-driving-scenes/

December 15, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Robotic Drones, a New Flight Simulator, and More Car News This Week Cities get the okay to speed up buses, while Seattle tries to slow traffic.  https://www.wired.com/story/robotic-drones-flight-simulator-car-news/

December 15, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Bing Maps Make the Revived Flight Simulator Eerily Realistic The 3D mapping, along with data and technical guidance from avionics manufacturers, make Microsoft’s long-loved flying program more than just a game. https://www.wired.com/story/microsoft-flight-simulator-2020/

December 14, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Sometimes Red Means Go—When It Comes to Bus Rides New Federal Highway Administration rules give cities more leeway to create special bus lanes. https://www.wired.com/story/sometimes-red-means-go-bus-rides/

December 13, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Seattle Joins the Rush to Slow Down Traffic on City Streets The city plans to lower the speed limit on major roads to 25 mph in hopes of boosting safety, following similar moves in New York, Philadelphia, and Boston.  https://www.wired.com/story/seattle-joins-rush-slow-traffic-city-streets/

December 9, 2019 | Author: Mark DentMark Dent It’s Coders Versus Human Pilots in This Drone Race A drone directed by artificial intelligence takes on a leading pro racer, in a contest that may help shape future humanitarian efforts. https://www.wired.com/story/coders-versus-human-pilots-drone-race/

December 8, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Elon Musk’s ‘Pedo Guy’ Trial, Uber’s Crime Report, and More Car News This Week Plus, the Air Force 3D prints parts for old planes, flying car execs consider the little people, and self-driving cars learn about selfish humans. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-pedo-guy-trial-verdict-uber-crime-report/

December 7, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies 3D Printing Can Keep Aging Air Force Aircraft Flying And the military wants you—to help it make spare parts for decades-old B-52 bombers and other planes.  https://www.wired.com/story/air-force-3d-printing-parts-manufacturing-olympics/

December 6, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Elon Musk Wins in Defamation Suit by British Diver The verdict in favor of the Tesla CEO capped a four-day trial in Los Angeles over insults Musk tweeted in 2018. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-wins-defamation-suit-british-diver/

December 6, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Uber’s Alarming Crime Report, T-Mobile’s 5G Test, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-sexual-assault-report-tmobile-5g-nationwide/

December 6, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A Criminologist Says Uber’s Crime Report Is ‘Highly Alarming’ In its first compilation, the ride-hail service says there were more than 3,000 sexual assaults related to Uber rides last year, up 4% from the year before.  https://www.wired.com/story/criminologist-uber-crime-report-highly-alarming/

December 6, 2019 | Author: Will Bedingfield, WIRED UKWill Bedingfield, WIRED UK Physics Explains Why You Can’t Open a Plane Door in the Air A British Airways passenger caused chaos after trying to open the aircraft door during a flight, but air pressure and clever design make it impossible.  https://www.wired.com/story/physics-explains-why-you-cant-open-a-plane-door-mid-flight/

December 5, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Now iPhone Users Can Tap Waymo’s Self-Driving Ride-Hail App The Google sibling says it has 1,500 monthly riders, including some who are chauffeured without a human backup driver. https://www.wired.com/story/iphone-users-waymos-self-driving-ride-hail/

December 4, 2019 | Author: Michael WatersMichael Waters Elon Musk on the Stand: ‘Pedo Guy’ Doesn’t Mean ‘Pedophile’ The Tesla CEO defended himself by arguing semantics on the first day of a defamation trial that stems from an insult Musk made on Twitter. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-pedo-guy-doesnt-mean-pedophile/

December 4, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Flying Car Leaders Talk Public Perception at a Secret Summit At a Texas conference hosted by Ross Perot Jr., air taxi innovators focused on how to get the public onboard with their ideas. https://www.wired.com/story/texas-up-evtol-flying-car-conference/

December 4, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Teaching Self-Driving Cars to Watch for Unpredictable Humans You drive differently for Sunday errands than when you’re late to pick up the kids. Researchers are teaching robots how to grapple with that. https://www.wired.com/story/teaching-self-driving-cars-watch-unpredictable-humans/

December 3, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Elon Musk’s Slander Trial, Offensive Ornaments on Amazon, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-slander-diver-trial-amazon-auschwitz-ornaments/

December 3, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Elon Musk to Testify as Diver’s Slander Trial Gets Under Way A trial beginning in Los Angeles is the latest chapter in a saga that began with Musk’s plan to use a mini-sub to rescue a trapped soccer team. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-testify-divers-slander-trial/

December 3, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Tesla Has Found a Use for Lasers—Cleaning Glass The electric automaker shuns lasers for its self-driving features. But a patent application foresees using the technology to clean windshields and cameras. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-use-lasers-clean-glass/

December 2, 2019 | Author: Flavie HalaisFlavie Halais NYC Has an Old-Timey Plan to Fix Its Traffic Future As the city plans out its congestion charge, critics are already saying it would do well to take a few lessons from London.  https://www.wired.com/story/nyc-london-congestion-charge/

December 2, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies How Airports Are Protecting Themselves Against Rising Seas Many of the nation’s busiest airports are subject to increased flooding from climate change. So they’re building seawalls and relocating sensitive equipment. https://www.wired.com/story/how-airports-protecting-rising-seas/

November 30, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies How to Change the Tires on a Race Car—at Zero Gravity The Red Bull Formula 1 team executed a pit stop aboard a Russian plane used to train cosmonauts. It required some adjustments. https://www.wired.com/story/change-tires-race-car-zero-gravity/

November 29, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Air Travel in 2019 Saw Big Projects and Belly Flops The number of Americans flying around Thanksgiving is projected to rise 3.7% this year. Just don’t stash gun magazines in your carry-on.  https://www.wired.com/story/air-travel-2019-big-projects-belly-flops/

November 28, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Yet Another Challenge for Air Travelers: Finding Your Uber Airports including LAX are setting up pickup areas a ways removed from terminals to address the congestion created by popular ride-hail apps. https://www.wired.com/story/challenge-air-travelers-finding-your-uber/

November 27, 2019 | Author: Amit Katwala, WIRED UKAmit Katwala, WIRED UK Uber’s London Rivals Are Plotting Its Downfall Irresistible deals for drivers and passengers are creating a frenetic race as fellow ride-hailing services try to cash in on uncertainty. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-london-rivals-plotting-its-downfall/

November 27, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Who’s Regulating Self-Driving Cars? Often, No One Two hearings reveal that neither the federal government nor many states are monitoring the hundreds of self-driving vehicles being tested on US roads. https://www.wired.com/story/regulating-self-driving-cars-no-one/

November 26, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams To Train Foreign Service Agents, You Must Build a Fake Town At a new State Department training center, survival lessons include fleeing ambushes, escaping burning buildings, and handling bomb threats. https://www.wired.com/story/state-department-virginia-training-center/

November 25, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb London Could Ban Uber; Women and Climate Change; and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-ban-london-climate-change-women/

November 25, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber May Be Banned From London, One of Its Biggest Markets The ride-hail company has 21 days to appeal the city’s ruling, which cited a “pattern of failures” on safety. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-banned-london-biggest-markets/

November 24, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla’s Cybertruck, an Aston Martin SUV, and More Car News This Week One design expert called Tesla’s electric pickup truck “horrifying.” And a black lab who drove in circles for an hour.  https://www.wired.com/story/teslas-cybertruck-aston-martin-suv-more-car-news/

November 23, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Why the Tesla Cybertruck Looks So Weird The pickup truck Elon Musk unveiled Thursday night features sharp angles, but no side mirrors or “crumple zone” to absorb the force of a collision. https://www.wired.com/story/why-tesla-cybertruck-looks-weird/

November 22, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Tesla Cybertruck Mishap, a Massive Data Leak, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-cybertruck-window-ball-billion-records-exposed-online/

November 22, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Is Tesla’s Cybertruck Pickup for Real? Let’s Investigate Elon Musk showed off a new vehicle. But the presentation lacked familiar Musk flourishes.  https://www.wired.com/story/is-teslas-cybertruck-pickup-real/

November 21, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Meet the Cybertruck, Tesla’s Ford-Fighting Pickup Elon Musk has revealed the latest Tesla model, promising hundreds of miles of range for about $40,000.  https://www.wired.com/story/electric-tesla-pickup-truck-announcement-specs-cost-photos/

November 21, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb An Electric Tesla Truck, the 8-Hour Workday Lie, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-cyber-truck-elon-musk-eight-hour-workday-myth/

November 21, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall What the Heck Is the Tesla Cybertruck? Let’s Watch Eager to challenge the dominance of Ford’s F-150, Elon Musk and company plan to unveil a pickup truck Thursday at 8 pm PT. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-cybertruck-watch/

November 21, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies More Powerful Batteries Make This a True Electric Car Race Drivers in the 2019-2020 Formula E series now have enough juice to avoid swapping cars midway through a race. https://www.wired.com/story/more-powerful-batteries-make-true-electric-car-race/

November 19, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The $189,000 DBX SUV Is Here to Save Aston Martin The esteemed brand is following the luxury SUV trend in a bid to expand and diversify its customer base. https://www.wired.com/story/dbx-suv-is-here-save-aston-martin/

November 19, 2019 | Author: Alex Davies, Aarian MarshallAlex Davies and Aarian Marshall Feds Pin Uber Crash on Human Operator, Call for Better Rules For starters, self-driving car companies should be required to submit safety evaluation letters—and those letters should be formally assessed. https://www.wired.com/story/feds-blame-uber-crash-on-human-driver-call-for-better-rules/

November 19, 2019 | Author: Laura MalloneeLaura Mallonee What It Takes to Turn a Vintage F-16 Into a Drone The US Air Force is resurrecting old fighter jets from a boneyard in Arizona as moving targets for live-fire exercises in the Gulf of Mexico. https://www.wired.com/story/what-it-takes-vintage-f-16-drone/

November 18, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Ford’s Electric Mustang, A Gadget-Stealing Hack, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/ford-electric-mustang-mach-e-bluetooth-burglars/

November 18, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Real ID Is Nearly Here, and You Can’t Fly Home Without It Next October, the TSA will stop accepting standard driver’s licenses as ID. Here’s how to get the Real ID—and why some people hate the idea. https://www.wired.com/story/the-real-id-is-nearly-here-and-you-cant-fly-home-without-it/

November 17, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams How Ford Created the Mach-E, Its Fully Electric Mustang SUV The Mach-E, Ford’s first serious attempt at a zero-emissions car, came to life in a two-year sprint to catch up with an electrifying industry. https://www.wired.com/story/ford-mach-e-mustang-electric/

November 17, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber’s ‘Mistakes,’ Ford v Ferrari, and More Car News The deadly design flaws of the B-17 Flying Fortress and a sneaky cat swap. https://www.wired.com/story/ubers-mistakes-ford-v-ferrari-and-more-car-news/

November 15, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Ford v Ferrari Overlooks the Best Part of the Racing Rivalry It’s a good time, but it skips the feats of engineering that made 1966’s historic 24 Hours of Le Mans race possible.  https://www.wired.com/story/ford-v-ferrari-review/

November 11, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Uber CEO’s Mistaken Notion of What a Mistake Is Attention, Dara Khosrowshahi: The killing of a woman in Arizona by your company’s self-driving car is not a “mistake.” https://www.wired.com/story/uber-ceos-mistaken-notion-of-what-mistake-is/

November 10, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Failure of Uber’s Self-Driving Car, Polestar’s Debut, and More Car News This Week Plus, a call to require helmets for cyclists, Paris battles e-scooters, and more.  https://www.wired.com/story/uber-self-driving-crash-volvo-polestar-1-roundup/

November 9, 2019 | Author: Brett BerkBrett Berk Electric Cars—and Irrationality—Just Might Save the Stick Shift Some people are so passionate about doing their own shifting, they keep manual transmissions in cars converted to run on electric power. https://www.wired.com/story/aston-martin-electric-cars-stick-shift-manual/

November 8, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Bike Safety Means Having New Lanes and Helmet Laws, US Says A government panel wants officials to build better cycling infrastructure, but its call to mandate helmets is already rankling cycling advocates.  https://www.wired.com/story/ntsb-cycling-safety-report-bike-lanes-helmet-laws/

November 8, 2019 | Author: Flavie HalaisFlavie Halais Paris Ends an E-Scooter Melee With New Rules of the Road France is moving to crack down on scooter sharing, but questions linger about how micromobility affects cities and citizens. https://www.wired.com/story/paris-escooters-regulation/

November 6, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Mind-Boggling Uber Oversight, a Firefox Scam, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-self-driving-arizona-crash-firefox-scam/

November 5, 2019 | Author: Aarian Marshall, Alex DaviesAarian Marshall and Alex Davies Uber’s Self-Driving Car Didn’t Know Pedestrians Could Jaywalk The National Transportation Safety Board releases hundreds of pages related to the 2018 crash in Tempe, Arizona, that killed Elaine Herzberg. https://www.wired.com/story/ubers-self-driving-car-didnt-know-pedestrians-could-jaywalk/

November 5, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Polestar 1 Is a Powerful Throwback Treat—Like Licorice The pricey plug-in hybrid is a little retro and a whole lot of fun to drive. https://www.wired.com/story/volvos-polestar-1-is-powerful-throwback-treat/

November 3, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Drones That Work for Food, a Self-Landing Plane, and More News This Week Uber Eats unveils its latest drone, which may begin deliveries next summer, and our reporter lands a $2 million plane with the help of new tech.  https://www.wired.com/story/drones-work-food-self-landing-plane/

November 2, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Need to Run Errands Really Quickly? Try This Lamborghini SUV That is, if you have $200,000. With the Urus, Lamborghini joins the rush to luxury SUVs, while staying true to its sports-car heritage. https://www.wired.com/story/need-errands-really-quickly-lamborghini-suv/

October 31, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber and Lyft Fight a Law They Say Doesn’t Apply to Them The ride-hail companies are backing a ballot measure to overturn a California law intended to transform gig-economy workers from contractors to employees. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-lyft-fight-law-say-doesnt-apply/

October 31, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Cirrus’ Private Jet Can Now Land Itself, No Pilot Needed The Safe Return Emergency Autoland System lets passengers hit a big red button to bring the plane to safety if the pilot’s incapacitated. https://www.wired.com/story/cirrus-garmin-vision-jet-autoland-safe-return/

October 31, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Delicate Art—and Evolving Science—of Wildfire Evacuations The still-burning Kincade Fire prompted one of the largest wildfire-related evacuations in California history—a legacy, in part, of two earlier deadly blazes. https://www.wired.com/story/delicate-art-evolving-science-wildfire-evacuations/

October 30, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Ford Screens Go Big, a WhatsApp Hacking Case, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/whatsapp-hacking-case-ford-screens/

October 30, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Ford Is Bringing Huge Screens—and Live Updates—to Its Cars The bigger screens can display a map, phone, and radio simultaneously. Ford says it won’t be too distracting.  https://www.wired.com/story/ford-huge-screens-live-updates-cars/

October 28, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Uber Eats Hopes Drones Can Lift It to Profitability Uber reveals the design of a drone with six rotors that change position for vertical takeoffs and landings. It can stay aloft for 18 minutes, with a range of 18 miles. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-eats-drones-lift-profitability/

October 28, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Why Are Parking Lots So Tricky for Self-Driving Cars? Here’s why Tesla’s “Smart Summon” feature is taking them on anyway. https://www.wired.com/story/why-are-parking-lots-so-tricky-for-self-driving-cars/

October 27, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Danger for Pedestrians, a Tesla Profit, and More Car News This Week The US government said pedestrian fatalities rose for a second consecutive year. But, hey, Tesla’s back in the black, and promising record deliveries this quarter.  https://www.wired.com/story/danger-pedestrians-tesla-profit-car-news/

October 26, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Tesla Has a New Solar Roof—and Musk Says This One Will Work Elon Musk revealed Version 3.0 of the Solar Glass Roof, which is made of solar panels, but looks like slate. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-new-solar-roof-musk-says-will-work/

October 25, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Uber Tipping Behavior Revealed, Apple App Store Malware, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-tipping-apple-malware-app-store/

October 25, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Your Secret Uber Tipping Behavior, Exposed A study of 40 million trips finds that men tip more than women, that women drivers get bigger tips, and that riders tip more on repeat rides with a driver. https://www.wired.com/story/your-secret-uber-tipping-behavior-exposed/

October 24, 2019 | Author: Lydia HorneLydia Horne Tesla Profits, Health Care Algorithm Bias, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-profits-health-care-algorithm-bias-and-more-news/

October 24, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies American Roads Are Getting Safer—Unless You’re Walking A government report finds that vehicle-related deaths fell 2.4% last year. But pedestrian deaths are up 50% in the past decade, and no one knows why. https://www.wired.com/story/american-roads-safer-unless-walking/

October 23, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla Turns a Profit—and Builds a Chinese Factory Very Fast The Shanghai Gigafactory, which Tesla says can produce 150,000 Model 3 sedans a year, was completed in 168 working days.  https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-turns-profit-builds-chinese-factory-fast/

October 23, 2019 | Author: Daniel C. VockDaniel C. Vock As Pedestrian Deaths Spike, Feds Take on Fanciful Crosswalks The federal government wants an Iowa city to revert a crosswalk celebrating the LGBTQ community to the standard zebra design. It’s a growing pattern. https://www.wired.com/story/pedestrian-deaths-feds-crosswalks/

October 22, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Polestar’s First EV Is a Track-Happy Challenge to Tesla’s Model 3 With its first fully electric car, Polestar delivers a fully evolved sedan engineered for economy and more than enough performance. https://www.wired.com/story/polestar-2-review-volvo-electric-car/

October 22, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Drugstores Are in the Sweet Spot for Drone Deliveries UPS has a deal with CVS, and Google sibling Wing is making deliveries for Walgreens in Virginia. https://www.wired.com/story/drugstores-sweet-spot-drone-deliveries/

October 20, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Cars Aren’t Going Anywhere, and More Transportation News This Week Plus, we investigate a new, tiny jet engine for cargo-touting drones, and check out Volvo’s first electric car.  https://www.wired.com/story/volvo-xc40-recharge-car-news-roundup/

October 18, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Rolls-Royce Turns a 747 Into a Flying Lab for New Engines The engine maker and its contractor AeroTec plan to strip a Qantas jetliner and stuff it with instruments to test new models. https://www.wired.com/story/rolls-royce-turns-747-flying-lab-new-engines/

October 17, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The Plan to Boost Drone Batteries With a Teensy Jet Engine A Florida aviation startup wants to supplement electric power with its watermelon-sized “microturbine.” https://www.wired.com/story/uav-turbines-microturbine-jet-engine-drone/

October 16, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Volvo’s First Electric Car Kicks Off a Plan to Cut Emissions The Swedish automaker introduced the XC40 Recharge, which can go from 0 to 60 mph in 4.9 seconds and reach about 200 miles on a charge. https://www.wired.com/story/volvos-first-electric-car-plan-cut-emissions/

October 16, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Death of Cars Was Greatly Exaggerated The founders of Uber and Lyft, among others, declared that people would no longer need to own cars. Instead, car ownership is rising.  https://www.wired.com/story/death-cars-greatly-exaggerated/

October 13, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Vacuum That’s Not a Car and Other Transportation News This Week Dyson scrubs plans to build an EV, Tesla owners learn the cars can’t power their homes, and lightning that follows shipping lanes. https://www.wired.com/story/vacuum-not-car-other-transportation-news/

October 10, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Dyson Sucks the Air Out of Its Electric-Car Dreams The British household-products maker had promised to invest $2.5 billion in EVs. Now, it says it can’t produce one that’s “commercially viable.”  https://www.wired.com/story/dyson-sucks-air-out-electric-car-dreams/

October 9, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies No, You Can’t Power Your House With Your Electric Car California’s power outages might have some residents looking for backups. But that juicy Tesla battery pack isn’t it—at least not yet. https://www.wired.com/story/no-you-cant-power-your-house-with-your-electric-car/

October 9, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Why Lightning Strikes Twice as Much Over Shipping Lanes It might sound crazy, but it’s true: The heavens cast their wrath and fury on the ships more than on the fishes. https://www.wired.com/story/why-lightning-strikes-twice-as-much-over-shipping-lanes/

October 8, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Elon Musk’s Mouth, and Tweets, Land Him in Trouble Again Newly released court documents reveal more backstory to a tweet that became a defamation suit. “I’m a fucking idiot,” the Tesla CEO said in an email. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musks-mouth-tweets-trouble-again/

October 8, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Bollinger’s Electric Pickup and SUV Are Made for the Mud The EV startup is packing the battery-driven duo with all the features they need to conquer field and stream. https://www.wired.com/story/bollinger-electric-pickup-suv-b1-b2-off-road/

October 6, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Smart Summons From Tesla, Drones From UPS, and More Car News Plus: A new “flying car” from Kitty Hawk. https://www.wired.com/story/teslas-smart-summon-upss-drone-airline-and-more-car-news/

October 6, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies EVs Fire Up Pyroswitches to Cut Risk of Shock After a Crash Electric cars run on 400 volts or more. So automakers are designing systems to protect EMTs and others from exposed wires following a collision. https://www.wired.com/story/evs-fire-pyroswitches-cut-risk-shock-crash/

October 5, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall These Small Cars Can Help Drive the Autonomous Future Researchers are using 1/10th-size models to test self-driving technology more cheaply and easily than full-size vehicles. https://www.wired.com/story/small-cars-help-drive-autonomous-future/

October 4, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Kitty Hawk’s New Flying Car Promises a (Near) Silent Flight Larry Page’s aviation outfit, helmed by Sebastian Thrun, built the Heaviside with eight motors and a big wing to help generate lift. https://www.wired.com/story/kitty-hawk-heaviside-larry-page-flying-car/

October 2, 2019 | Author: Flavie HalaisFlavie Halais Rio’s Defunct Gondola Tells a Tale of Transit Style Over Substance Favela residents once enjoyed easy access to the heart of the Brazilian city. But poor planning and financial trouble led to the service’s suspension. https://www.wired.com/story/rio-de-janeiro-favela-cable-car-gondola/

October 2, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla’s ‘Smart Summon’ Will Fetch Your Car—Sometimes Tesla introduced a feature that allows drivers to call the car to come to them. What could go wrong? https://www.wired.com/story/teslas-smart-summon-fetch-your-car/

October 1, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb The First Drone Airline, a Critical Device Vulnerability, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/ups-drone-airline-urgent-11-ipnet-vulnerable-devices/

October 1, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies UPS Now Runs the First Official Drone Airline The FAA has granted a Part 135 certification for the logistics giant’s drone business, propelling the little fliers closer to a commercial future. https://www.wired.com/story/ups-drone-airline-faa-certification-delivery/

September 29, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Quieter Landings, Stranded Tourists, and More Transport News This Week Researchers want to train pilots to make less noise when they land planes, and the bankruptcy of Britain’s Thomas Cook prompted a mass mobilization. https://www.wired.com/story/quieter-landings-stranded-tourists-transport-news/

September 28, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Porsche’s Taycan Is the Best Electric Car $150,000 Can Buy The all-new sport sedan may be the world’s most advanced car—we just wish it felt more like a Porsche of old. https://www.wired.com/story/porsche-taycan-review/

September 27, 2019 | Author: Tidal W. McCoyTidal W. McCoy The Dangers of Delaying FAA Modernization Opinion: Grounded by mid-20th-century technology, air traffic controllers cannot handle the ongoing demands of commercial airlines and drones. https://www.wired.com/story/the-dangers-of-delaying-faa-modernization/

September 26, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Feds Say Boeing 737s Need to Be Better Designed for Humans A National Transportation Safety Board review of two fatal crashes suggests pilots may have been overwhelmed by multiple alerts and warnings. https://www.wired.com/story/feds-boeing-737s-better-designed-humans/

September 26, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber’s New Features Put a Focus on Rider Safety Passengers will be able to text 911 from inside the app. Uber also is offering new ways to confirm a driver’s identity. https://www.wired.com/story/ubers-new-features-focus-rider-safety/

September 26, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Teaching Pilots a New Trick: Landing Quietly Researchers want to reduce the noise from planes approaching a runway. The key is a smooth descent. https://www.wired.com/story/teaching-pilots-new-trick-landing-quietly/

September 25, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall An Effort to Punish China Could Slow the Roll of Electric Buses China’s BYD supplies about one-third of the electric buses in the US, but it would be effectively barred under a provision in a national defense bill. https://www.wired.com/story/punish-china-slow-electric-buses/

September 25, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers How to Get 150,000 Stranded People Home in Two Weeks The UK has a fund to bring home passengers left hanging after the collapse of travel agency Thomas Cook. In the US, travelers wouldn’t be so lucky. https://www.wired.com/story/get-150000-stranded-people-home-2-weeks/

September 24, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Hyundai Makes Another Match in the Self-Driving Game Hyundai will partner with an industry supplier called Aptiv to deliver robotaxis, in addition to an ongoing deal with Aurora. https://www.wired.com/story/another-self-driving-car-couple-ties-knot/

September 24, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Speed Is Killing the Planet. Time to Focus on Efficiency The climate crisis is rushing at us like a bullet train. We have to stop obsessing over velocity and become efficiency fanatics. https://www.wired.com/story/speed-is-killing-the-planet-focus-on-efficiency/

September 24, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Future Face of High-Speed Rail in the Northeast Corridor Amtrak’s popular Acela line is getting a $2.4 billion upgrade—and 10 mph faster. The new trains have to prove they can take the curves quickly and comfortably. https://www.wired.com/story/future-face-high-speed-rail-amtrak-northeast-corridor/

September 23, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Cleaner Ships May Mean More Expensive Holidays New rules designed to reduce sulfur pollution from ocean-going ships will increase demand for low-sulfur fuel, boosting the cost of some imported goods. https://www.wired.com/story/cleaner-ships-more-expensive-holidays/

September 23, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Tesla May Soon Have a Battery That Can Last a Million Miles Elon Musk promised Tesla would soon have a million-mile battery, more than double what drivers can expect today. A new paper suggests he wasn’t exaggerating. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-may-soon-have-a-battery-that-can-last-a-million-miles/

September 22, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Trump’s Emissions Fight, Amazon’s EVs, and Other Car News This Week Plus: A GM strike and a post-petroleum running shoe. https://www.wired.com/story/trumps-emissions-fight-amazons-evs/

September 21, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Amazon and the All-Electric Future of Fleet Vehicles Fleets, like the 100,000 delivery vans the retailer ordered from startup Rivian, will make electrics more commonplace and easier to charge. https://www.wired.com/story/amazon-all-electric-future-fleet-vehicles/

September 19, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Amazon Puts a Charge Into Startup Automaker Rivian The retail giant says it will buy 100,000 electric vans by 2030 from a company that doesn’t yet have a single vehicle on the road. https://www.wired.com/story/amazon-puts-charge-startup-automaker-rivian/

September 19, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Trump Threatens California’s Role as a Clean-Air Pioneer From the catalytic converter to electric vehicles, the Golden State has pushed automakers to build cleaner cars. https://www.wired.com/story/trump-threatens-californias-role-clean-air-pioneer/

September 18, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Fight Over California’s Emissions Rules Just Got Real The Trump administration plans to revoke California’s authority to set regulations for vehicle fuel economy and emissions, likely setting up a court fight. https://www.wired.com/story/fight-californias-emissions-rules-real/

September 17, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Massive GM Strike, a LastPass Vulnerability, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/gm-strike-electric-car-lastpass-password-bug/

September 17, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Shift to Electric Vehicles Propels a Strike Against GM Like other automakers, General Motors is preparing for a mostly electric future. The catch is that building those cars requires a lot fewer workers. https://www.wired.com/story/shift-electric-vehicles-strike-gm/

September 15, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall New Electrics, New Laws, and Other Car News This Week Automakers show off their latest in Frankfurt, and California lawmakers rewrite the rules of the road for Uber and Lyft. https://www.wired.com/story/new-electrics-new-laws-car-news/

September 13, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Fight Over Fuel Economy Rules Gets Messy The Justice Department is investigating automakers who struck a deal with California. Some in Congress want to investigate the investigators. https://www.wired.com/story/fight-fuel-economy-rules-messy/

September 12, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The Land Rover Defender Is Back—With a Softer, Smarter Look The angular off-roader returns to Land Rover’s lineup with a few rounded corners and a lot of tech-heavy features. https://www.wired.com/story/land-rover-defender-2020/

September 12, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Why Uber Thinks It Can Still Call Its Drivers Contractors A pending California law was designed to make ride-hail companies classify drivers as employees. Uber says it can evade the requirement. https://www.wired.com/story/why-uber-still-call-drivers-contractors/

September 11, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall In California, Gig Workers Are About to Become Employees A bill would change the rules for classifying workers as employees, rather than contractors. It would affect Uber and Lyft, but also truckers and musicians. https://www.wired.com/story/california-gig-workers-become-employees/

September 11, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Why Your Flight to San Francisco Was Three Hours Late San Francisco International Airport is rebuilding one of its four runways, down to the gravel under the asphalt. Throw in some wind, and it’s hard to keep planes on time. https://www.wired.com/story/why-flight-san-francisco-three-hours-late/

September 10, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Forget Driving. You’ll Wish You Could Watch TV in This Car An electric SUV from Chinese startup Byton features a 4-foot-wide curved screen, as well as 270 horsepower and a 224-mile range. https://www.wired.com/story/forget-driving-watch-tv-car/

September 9, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Cities Are Trying—Again—to Plan for Autonomous Vehicles The bloom is off the rose for self-driving tech among urban transportation officials, who are planning for a future with fewer private cars. https://www.wired.com/story/cities-trying-again-plan-autonomous-vehicles/

September 8, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall An Electric Porsche, a Tesla Probe, and More Car News This Week Porsche’s battery-powered Taycan can go 0 to 60 in 2.6 seconds and features a two-speed gearbox that’s the first of its kind. https://www.wired.com/story/electric-porsche-tesla-probe-car-news/

September 8, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Imagine the Views From This Italian-Designed Swiss Train Italian design firm Pininfarina has designed the new rail cars with nearly floor-to-ceiling windows for a line in the Swiss Alps. https://www.wired.com/story/imagine-views-italian-designed-swiss-train/

September 7, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies GM’s Search for In-Car Tech Lands on Google The automaker and the tech giant say Google’s Android software will underpin the infotainment systems in future GM cars. https://www.wired.com/story/gms-search-car-tech-lands-google/

September 5, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Why the Porsche Taycan’s Two-Speed Gearbox Is Such a Big Deal Want to improve an EV’s range by 5 percent, or pump up its top speed? Trying shifting gears. https://www.wired.com/story/electric-car-two-speed-transmission-gearbox/

September 4, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Feds Say Tesla Autopilot Is Partly to Blame for a 2018 Crash The National Transportation Safety Board says the design of Tesla’s Autopilot contributed to a crash in which the driver did not actively steer for 13 minutes. https://www.wired.com/story/feds-tesla-autopilot-partly-blame-2018-crash/

September 4, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams With the Taycan, Porsche Launches Into the Electric Future The German automaker’s new all-electric sports sedan has the specs and techs to make even petrol-chugging gearheads drool. https://www.wired.com/story/porsche-taycan-electric-specs/

September 4, 2019 | Author: Phillip Burgoyne-AllenPhillip Burgoyne-Allen The Red Lights Stopping Yellow School Buses from Going Green Opinion: Pilot programs show that electric buses, pricey today, offer long-term savings and crucial learning opportunities. https://www.wired.com/story/the-red-lights-stopping-yellow-school-buses-from-going-green/

September 4, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Why the Feds Want to Block a Flight-Booking Software Deal Airlines think Sabre, the industry leader in booking software, is stodgy. Now Sabre wants to acquire upstart rival Farelogix, which would leave carriers fewer choices. https://www.wired.com/story/why-feds-block-flight-booking-software-deal/

September 3, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Bugatti’s Chiron Clocks 305 MPH Thanks to Top-Notch Tires Clever engineering and x-rayed tires pushed the latest version of the Chiron past the 300 mph barrier. https://www.wired.com/story/bugatti-chiron-speed-record-305-mph/

September 2, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies London Is Changing Its Skyscraper Designs—to Favor Cyclists Wind tunnels and downdrafts can make life difficult for cyclists and pedestrians. London’s new design rules aim to reduce headwinds. https://www.wired.com/story/london-changing-skyscraper-designs-favor-cyclists/

September 1, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A Tesla Security Bug, Levandowski Indicted, and More Car News Plus: A California bill takes aim at Uber drivers, and a cargo drone flies itself https://www.wired.com/story/a-tesla-security-bug-levandowski-indicted-and-more-car-news/

September 1, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Bell’s New, Self-Flying Cargo Drone Hauls a Heavy Load The all-electric APT 70 can tote up to 70 pounds, cruise at 75 mph, and cover 35 miles with a fully charged battery. https://www.wired.com/story/bell-apt-70-cargo-drone-test-flight/

August 30, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A California Bill Has Uber and Lyft Running Scared The ride-hail companies offer more pay and benefits to drivers—and threaten a ballot measure to prevent those same drivers from being classified as employees. https://www.wired.com/story/california-bill-uber-lyft-running-scared/

August 29, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies How Anthony Levandowski Put Himself at the Center of an Industry Levandowski has been part of key developments in self-driving tech, from the Darpa Grand Challenge to his time at Google and Otto and Uber. https://www.wired.com/story/anthony-levandowski-put-himself-center-industry/

August 29, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Levandowski’s Fate May Turn on the Meaning of ‘Trade Secret’ Former Google and Uber engineer Anthony Levandowski was indicted on charges of stealing trade secrets. But what exactly are those, anyway? https://www.wired.com/story/levandowskis-fate-turn-meaning-trade-secret/

August 27, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Ex-Uber Engineer Levandowski Charged With Trade-Secret Theft Prosecutors say Anthony Levandowski took drawings and designs for self-driving technology from Google to Uber in 2016. https://www.wired.com/story/ex-uber-engineer-levandowski-charged-trade-secret-theft/

August 27, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies A Novelist Takes Self-Driving to Its Illogical Conclusion In John Marrs’ sixth novel, The Passengers, a hacker traps eight people in self-driving cars—with results as revealing as they are ridiculous. https://www.wired.com/story/book-review-the-passengers-john-marrs/

August 25, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A Bank-Busting Bugatti, VW’s EV Dune Buggy, and More Car News Plus, an inside look at Netflix’s crazy new car show and Ford’s plan to gather data from college scooter riders. https://www.wired.com/story/bugatti-centodieci-vw-ev-dune-buggy-roundup/

August 24, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Honda’s New Airbag Catches Your Head to Save Your Brain The automaker’s got a brand new bag, and it could reduce the chances of brain injury in some crashes by 75 percent. https://www.wired.com/story/honda-new-airbag-catches-your-head-to-save-your-brain/

August 21, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Ford’s Bid for Safer Scooters? Sensors Everywhere Partnering with Virginia Tech, Ford-owned Spin is gathering data from its scooters to see where things get dangerous and how to keep riders safe. https://www.wired.com/story/spin-ford-virginia-tech-research-project-scooters/

August 21, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Netflix’s Hyperdrive Is American Ninja Warrior for Cars The new show pits amateur drivers against a plethora of pitfalls, from a giant seesaw to a “rail slide.” https://www.wired.com/story/netflixs-hyperdrive-american-ninja-warrior-cars/

August 19, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Want to Burn $9 Million to Go 236 MPH? Try the New Bugatti The Bugatti Centodieci pays homage to the EB110, and packs 1,600 horsepower into a W16 engine (basically two V8s). https://www.wired.com/story/burn-dollar9-million-236-mph-new-bugatti/

August 19, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber’s NYC Troubles, Gyrocopters Take Flight, and More News Plus: A crippled plane lands in a cornfield, and a clever license plate goes awry. https://www.wired.com/story/ubers-dollar5-billion-loss-boeings-787-trouble-and-more-car-news/

August 17, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams VW Revives the Classic Dune Buggy as an All-Electric Blast The concept car shows that flexible EV platforms are steering us toward a very fun future of driving. https://www.wired.com/story/vw-id-electric-buggy/

August 16, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Heroic Plane Landing, Instagram’s New Fact Checkers, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/russian-plane-cornfield-instagram-fact-checkers/

August 16, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies How to Land a Busted Airliner in a Russian Cornfield A Ural Airlines plane executed an emergency landing after a bird strike, summoning memories of 2009’s “Miracle on the Hudson.” https://www.wired.com/story/how-land-busted-airliner-russian-cornfield/

August 16, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Surprise! Uber and Lyft Don’t Like NYC’s New Ride-Hail Rules The regulations are particularly less than ideal for the companies because New York is among their largest urban markets. https://www.wired.com/story/surprise-uber-and-lyft-dont-like-nycs-new-ride-hail-rules/

August 15, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Truckers Gain More Freedom, Thanks to Tech’s Watchful Eye Proposed federal rules would give truckers more leeway in taking breaks—because regulators already know when drivers are driving and not driving. https://www.wired.com/story/truckers-gain-more-freedom-techs-watchful-eye/

August 14, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall No More Screen Time! The Navy Reverts to Physical Throttles The US Navy will eliminate touchscreen controls in destroyers after reports found many sailors did not know how to work them, contributing to accidents. https://www.wired.com/story/no-more-screen-time-navy-reverts-physical-throttles/

August 13, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies How Many Uber and Lyft Drivers Are in Recalled Cars? The Center for Auto Safety wants ride-hail companies to crack down on drivers whose cars have been recalled. https://www.wired.com/story/how-many-uber-lyft-drivers-recalled-cars/

August 12, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Old Gyrocopters Could Be the Funky Flying Cars of the Future Electric flight advocates say that with a few modern tweaks, the helicopter’s predecessor could make a return to the sky. https://www.wired.com/story/gyrocopter-jaunt-skyworks-flying-car/

August 11, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Uber’s Big Loss, Boeing’s 787 Trouble, and More Car News This Week Uber reports its biggest loss and slowest growth in its first public quarter. An auto supplier pivots hard to electrics, and EVs appear on used car lots. https://www.wired.com/story/ubers-big-loss-boeings-787-trouble-more-car-news/

August 10, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers How ‘Microcracks’ Undermined San Francisco’s New Bus Terminal A cracked beam forced the $2.2 billion terminal’s closure after six weeks. Unraveling why required physics, metallurgy, and engineers with nerves of steel. https://www.wired.com/story/microcracks-undermined-san-franciscos-new-bus-terminal/

August 9, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Free Bus Rides in Salt Lake City Might Not Be So Far-Fetched A leading mayoral candidate proposes eliminating fares on buses and light rail. Free rides are unusual in the US, but more common overseas. https://www.wired.com/story/free-bus-rides-salt-lake-city-not-far-fetched/

August 9, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb The End of Cheap Ride-Hail, a Teen Hacker, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-lyft-earnings-teen-hacker-blackboard-follett/

August 8, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber and Lyft Suggest the Days of Cheap Rides Could Be Over Both continue to record big losses, but executives at the companies hinted in recent calls that they are trying to cut back on discounts and subtly raise prices. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-lyft-suggest-cheap-rides-could-be-over/

August 8, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies An Old-School Auto Supplier Is Betting on an Electric Future Germany’s Continental, the world’s fourth-largest auto-parts maker, says it will stop investing in parts for internal combustion engines. https://www.wired.com/story/auto-supplier-betting-electric-future/

August 6, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies A Boeing 737 MAX Test Flight Had Its Ups and Downs The aircraft flying loops off the Oregon Coast on Monday was likely testing potential fixes for the troubled MCAS system, implicated in two crashes. https://www.wired.com/story/boeing-737-max-test-flight-ups-and-downs/

August 6, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Self-Driving Trucks Are Ready to Do Business in Texas Kodiak Robotics will begin commercial service between Dallas and Houston, though a host of other self-driving startups have already been testing in the state. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-trucks-ready-business-texas/

August 5, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Now on Used Car Lots: Great Electric Vehicles for Cheap Used-car shopping site Shift says EVs accounted for 4 percent of sales in the first half of 2019, triple their share of a year ago. https://www.wired.com/story/now-used-car-lot-great-electric-vehicles-cheap/

August 4, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Hand-Crafted Bentleys, a Climate Bill, and More Car News This Week A $287 billion transportation bill approved by a Senate committee includes $10 billion for preventing and mitigating the effects of climate change. https://www.wired.com/story/hand-crafted-bentleys-climate-bill-more-car-news/

August 3, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Startup Wants to Tame the Chaos of City Street Parking Everyone vies for curb space: taxis, Ubers, delivery trucks, buses, bicycles, and residents. In Washington, DC, CurbFlow is testing spots reserved via app. https://www.wired.com/story/startup-tame-chaos-city-street-parking/

August 1, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Senate’s Transportation Plan Reckons With Climate Change America’s Transportation Infrastructure Act, approved by a Senate committee this week, includes $10 billion to prevent and mitigate the effects of climate change. https://www.wired.com/story/senates-transportation-plan-reckons-climate-change/

July 28, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Self-Parking Garages, Robovans, and More Car News This Week Bosch and Daimler introduce a garage where cars park themselves, carmakers sign on to tough mileage standards, and a Ford F-150 tows a train. https://www.wired.com/story/self-parking-garages-robovans-more-car-news-this-week/

July 27, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Tour the Factory Where Bentley Handcrafts Its Luxury Rides While a major auto plant can stamp out thousands of cars a day, Bentley makes just a few dozen, with a heavy dose of TLC. https://www.wired.com/story/bentley-crew-factory-photo-tour/

July 26, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies This Robo-Van Startup Will Handle Walmart’s ‘Middle Mile’ Gatik isn’t a long-haul trucker and doesn’t want to transport people. It’s hoping to carve a niche moving goods from warehouses to stores. https://www.wired.com/story/robo-van-startup-handle-walmarts-middle-mile/

July 25, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall California’s Auto-Emissions Deal Could Trump the Feds’ Plans Ford, Honda, Volkswagen, and BMW agree to tougher California mileage standards, potentially disrupting Trump’s proposal to relax US rules. https://www.wired.com/story/californias-auto-emissions-deal-could-trump-feds-plans/

July 25, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb UPS Wants to Unleash Drones, a Galaxy Fold Relaunch, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/ups-drone-samsung-galaxy-fold-fix/

July 25, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams UPS Wants to Go Full-Scale With Its Drone Deliveries The delivery giant is done experimenting and is petitioning the FAA for the right to launch revenue-generating drone flights without today’s restrictions. https://www.wired.com/story/ups-drone-deliveries-faa-license-part-135/

July 24, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla Delivers More Cars—and More Losses The electric vehicle maker said it set a record for deliveries, which more than doubled from a year earlier. But few were luxury models, leading to a quarterly loss. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-delivers-more-cars-more-losses/

July 24, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies GM’s Cruise Rolls Back Its Target for Self-Driving Cars The automaker’s robo-taxi service nixes its planned launch this year and expands testing. https://www.wired.com/story/gms-cruise-rolls-back-target-self-driving-cars/

July 23, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Who Needs a Valet? Cars in This Garage Can Park Themselves Daimler and Bosch say they’ve gained approval for cars to park—no safety drivers needed—at the Mercedes-Benz Museum in Stuttgart. https://www.wired.com/story/who-needs-valet-cars-garage-can-park-themselves/

July 23, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies How Loon’s Balloons Find Their Way to Deliver the Internet Computer programs can direct Alphabet’s high-altitude balloons to tack against the wind, and move in figure eights, where humans might plot a circle. https://www.wired.com/story/how-loons-balloons-find-way-deliver-internet/

July 23, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Ford Will Make an Electric F-150 Pickup, but Won’t Say When Ford, which has lagged rivals when it comes to all-electric vehicles, finally shows off an all-electric pickup—towing a 1.3-million-pound train. https://www.wired.com/story/ford-make-electric-f150-pickup-wont-say-when/

July 21, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A Meditation on Moon Shots, a Mid-Engine Corvette, and More Car News This Week We debate the use of the term “moon shot,” digitally drive the first mid-engine ’Vette, and check in how on Formula E is fueling an all-electric future. https://www.wired.com/story/moon-shot-mid-engine-corvette-roundup/

July 20, 2019 | Author: Brett BerkBrett Berk How Formula E Racing Makes Electric Cars Faster, Smarter, Funner For automakers like BMW, Audi, and Jaguar, making EVs for the track is a natural way to hone EVs for the streets. https://www.wired.com/story/formula-e-electric-car-tech-transfer/

July 19, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The Air Force’s New Rescue Chopper Flies Farther Than Ever Sikorsky’s Combat Rescue Helicopter trades the missiles and rockets for extra fuel capacity and room for more wounded warriors. https://www.wired.com/story/sikorsky-hh-60w-helicopter-search-rescue/

July 18, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies How It Feels to Drive—and Crash—the First-Ever Mid-Engine Corvette Car buffs have waited decades for Chevy’s new Corvette Stingray, with its relocated engine. WIRED got to test the beast in a simulator GM used to help build it. https://www.wired.com/story/how-feels-drive-first-mid-engine-corvette/

July 17, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies This Food-Delivery Robot Wants to Share the Bike Lane Refraction AI, founded by two researchers at the University of Michigan, joins a crowded field of self-driving delivery vehicles. https://www.wired.com/story/food-delivery-robot-wants-share-bike-lane/

July 16, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Why ‘Moon Shot’ Has No Place in the 21st Century Today’s challenges are vast and nebulous—and demand a different kind of ambition and approach. We need a new name for them. https://www.wired.com/story/apollo-11-moonshot-21st-century/

July 14, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Cheaper Lidar, a Self-Driving Deal, and Other Car News This Week Sikorsky has a nimble new helicopter and a Colorado startup has designed an airplane middle seat you might actually want to sit in. https://www.wired.com/story/cheaper-lidar-self-driving-deal-other-car-news/

July 12, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Ford and VW Hitch Their Self-Driving Efforts Together Volkswagen said it is investing $2.6 billion in Argo, a self-driving-car startup in which Ford has a big stake. The companies are jointly developing pickups and an EV. https://www.wired.com/story/ford-vw-hitch-self-driving-efforts-together/

July 11, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies This Lidar Is So Cheap It Could Make Self-Driving a Reality Luminar says its new lidar sensor will sell for as little as $500, compared with $75,000 for the industry leader. https://www.wired.com/story/lidar-cheap-make-self-driving-reality/

July 10, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies This Neat Design Could Make a Plane’s Middle Seats Tolerable Molon Labe designed a middle seat for airplanes that is set lower and three inches back from the seats on either side. https://www.wired.com/story/neat-design-make-planes-middle-seats-tolerable/

July 10, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall In New York, Friendships Run Along Subway Lines A study finds New Yorkers are more likely to be Facebook friends if they live along the same subway line. https://www.wired.com/story/new-york-friendships-along-subway-lines/

July 8, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Waze Data Can Help Predict Car Crashes and Cut Response Time Waze users notify the app of crashes an average of 2 minutes, 41 seconds before anyone alerts law enforcement. https://www.wired.com/story/waze-data-help-predict-car-crashes-cut-response-time/

July 7, 2019 | Author: David ZipperDavid Zipper Public Transit Agencies Think Rewards Programs Can Bring Back Riders Following the example set by airlines, Uber, and Lyft, public transportation officials are creating frequent-flier-like systems to goose ridership. https://www.wired.com/story/public-transit-agencies-rewards-programs/

July 6, 2019 | Author: Brett BerkBrett Berk Norway Invites You to Explore Its Electric Vehicle Paradise The Land of the Midnight Sun—and one of Tesla’s biggest markets—wants you to come experience the transportation future. https://www.wired.com/story/norway-electric-vehicles-tourism/

July 5, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The Pirouetting S-97 Raider Makes Your Helicopter Look Lazy The funky, speedy whirlybird is Sikorksy’s bid to win a major new contract from the Army. https://www.wired.com/story/sikorsky-s-97-raider/

July 4, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Why Bigger Roads Make Traffic Worse, and Other Summer Travel News Your airline stranded you. What do you do now? And what does July 4th shopping have to do with traffic congestion? https://www.wired.com/story/why-bigger-roads-make-traffic-worse-summer-travel-news/

July 3, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Tesla Model 3 Crash Results, Europe’s Record Heat, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-model-3-crash-europe-heatwave-climate-change/

July 3, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Tesla Model 3 Can Survive a Crash—and Avoid One Too The Model 3 scores well in European crash testing, a day after Tesla reported a quarterly record for deliveries. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-model-3-can-survive-crash-avoid-one-too/

July 2, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Bentley’s New Hybrid Hides Its Luxury From the Masses The Bentley Bentayga Hybrid can go from 0 to 60 mph in 5.2 seconds and deliver more than 500 pound-feet of torque. And the windshield wipers are hidden. https://www.wired.com/story/bentleys-new-hybrid-hides-luxury-from-masses/

June 30, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Bike-Friendly Cities, a New Urbanism, and More Car News This Week Copenhagenize Design published its list of the world’s top 20 cities for cyclists, and Sidewalk Labs unveiled a plan to remake part of Toronto. https://www.wired.com/story/bike-friendly-cities-new-urbanism-more-car-news/

June 30, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall What Boeing’s 737 MAX Has to Do With Cars: Software Investigators believe faulty software contributed to two fatal crashes. A newly discovered fault will likely will keep the 737 MAX grounded until the fall. https://www.wired.com/story/boeings-737-max-cars-software/

June 29, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Transit Agencies Turn to Uber for the Last Mile Transit systems worry about losing passengers to ride-hail services. But some agencies are also testing using Uber in place of low-ridership lines. https://www.wired.com/story/transit-agencies-turn-uber-last-mile/

June 27, 2019 | Author: Copenhagenize Design Co.Copenhagenize Design Co. The 20 Most Bike-Friendly Cities on the Planet, Ranked The 2019 Copenhagenize Index ranks the world’s urban hubs on how much they’re doing to promote life on two wheels. https://www.wired.com/story/most-bike-friendly-cities-2019-copenhagenize-design-index/

June 25, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Arnold Schwarzenegger Stars in a New Ad Plugging Electric Cars The former Terminator and California governor poses as a sleazy car salesman and makes patently ridiculous arguments against going electric. https://www.wired.com/story/arnold-schwarzenegger-stars-new-ad-plugging-electric-cars/

June 25, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall These Cities Will Track Scooters to Get a Handle on Regulation The cities, including New York, Los Angeles, and San Francisco, will use the same tool to keep track of where scooters go and where they are parked. https://www.wired.com/story/these-cities-will-track-scooters-handle-regulation/

June 24, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Alphabet’s Plan for Toronto Depends on Huge Amounts of Data Google sister company Sidewalk Labs outlines a plan for a 12-acre lot with affordable housing, a pneumatic tube for garbage, and room for autonomous vehicles. https://www.wired.com/story/alphabets-plan-toronto-depends-huge-amounts-data/

June 23, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A Tesla ‘Truckla,’ Robotic Pizza Delivery, and More Car News This Week A DIY-er DIY-ed a Tesla pickup truck, Domino’s has a deal for self-driving delivery, and an electric plane designed to train pilots. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-truckla-robotic-pizza-delivery-more-car-news/

June 21, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies An Aviation Pioneer Goes All In on Electric Planes André Borschberg, one of two men to fly around the world in a solar-powered plane, launched a new company called H55. https://www.wired.com/story/aviation-pioneer-goes-all-electric-planes/

June 20, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Waymo Goes Global With Renault-Nissan Partnership But don’t expect les voitures autonomes de Waymo to roam international roads just yet. https://www.wired.com/story/waymo-goes-global-renault-nissan-partnership/

June 19, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Bored Charging Your Tesla? Play a Videogame Right in Your Car Tesla gives drivers access to games they can play on the center screen, including Beach Buggy Racing 2. The car has to be in park, however. https://www.wired.com/story/bored-charging-your-tesla-play-videogame-your-car/

June 19, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Korean Cars Are Officially the Best, a Blood-Powered Robot, and More News Catch up on the most important news today in 2 minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/robot-fish-jd-power-korean-cars-taylor-swift-todays-news/

June 19, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies JD Power Says Korean Cars Beat US and Europe in Quality New car owners report fewer problems than in past years. But infotainment systems are proving troublesome. https://www.wired.com/story/jd-power-korean-cars-beat-us-europe-quality/

June 18, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Shitty Robot Tesla Truck, Facebook’s New Cryptocurrency, and More News Catch up on the most important news today in 2 minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/facebook-cryptocurrency-libra-tesla-truck-simone-giertz/

June 18, 2019 | Author: Lauren GoodeLauren Goode YouTube’s ‘Shitty Robot’ Queen Made Her Own Tesla Pickup Truck Simone Giertz hacked her Model 3 into a ride she calls the “Truckla,” and it does donuts. https://www.wired.com/story/simone-giertz-tesla-pickup-model-3-truckla/

June 18, 2019 | Author: Levi Tillemann , Anthony EggertLevi Tillemann and Anthony Eggert Is American Micromobility a Bust? Opinion: China’s e-biking masses offer a model for our struggling scoot-scape. https://www.wired.com/story/is-micromobility-a-bust/

June 17, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Nuro’s Pizza Robot Will Bring You a Domino’s Pie It’s about half the size of a sedan, and for now it needs a chase car with a babysitter. For now. https://www.wired.com/story/nuro-dominos-pizza-delivery-self-driving-robot-houston/

June 16, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Audi Recall, Shifting Alliances, and More Car News This Week Audi issued a voluntary recall of its E-Tron SUV; self-driving tech startup Aurora broke up with VW and joined up with Fiat Chrysler. https://www.wired.com/story/audi-recall-shifting-alliances-more-car-news/

June 15, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall New York City Flexes Again, Extending Cap on Uber and Lyft Officials want to extend the city’s limit on the number of for-hire vehicles, and may consider a congestion charge. https://www.wired.com/story/new-york-city-flexes-extending-cap-uber-lyft/

June 15, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Lamborghini’s Huracán EVO Sees the Future—And Makes You Look Great The super smart supercar predicts what you’ll do next—and helps you make it happen. https://www.wired.com/story/lamborghini-huracan-evo/

June 12, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Strange Mating Rituals of Self-Driving Car Companies Aurora hooked up with Chrysler on Monday, ditched VW on Tuesday, and doubled down with Hyundai on Wednesday. https://www.wired.com/story/strange-mating-rituals-self-driving-car-companies/

June 11, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Your Cadillac Can Now Drive Itself More Places Cadillac’s Super Cruise will shut itself off when the car reaches a tricky spot where a driver needs to pay attention. https://www.wired.com/story/your-cadillac-can-now-drive-itself-more-places/

June 10, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Aurora’s Latest Deal Will Be a Heavy-Duty Test With Chrysler Startup Aurora is putting its self-driving technology into commercial vehicles from Fiat Chrysler Automobiles, expanding its long list of partnerships. https://www.wired.com/story/auroras-latest-deal-heavy-duty-test-chrysler/

June 10, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Audi Recalls Some E-Tron SUVs Over a Battery Issue The E-Tron competes against Tesla’s Model X, as well as Jaguar’s I-Pace and the forthcoming Mercedes-Benz EQC. https://www.wired.com/story/audi-recalls-e-tron-suvs-battery-issue/

June 10, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies A Very Fast Spin Through the Hills in a Hybrid Porsche 911 Vonnen’s Shadow Drive system adds an electric motor—and a whole lot of power—to the venerable sports car. https://www.wired.com/story/vonnen-shadow-drive-porsche-911-hybrid/

June 9, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Electric Buses, Quiet Tires, and More Car News This Week Why haven’t electric buses caught on? And how does Mattel shrink car designs to make Hot Wheels? https://www.wired.com/story/electric-buses-quiet-tires-more-car-news/

June 7, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Lyft’s Lawsuit Against San Francisco Is Bigger Than Bike-Share Lyft’s bike-share company, Motivate, had an exclusive contract with the city for its docked bike program. But if San Francisco allows a dockless bike program, Uber could muscle in on Lyft’s territory. https://www.wired.com/story/lyfts-sues-san-francisco-bike-share-motivate/

June 7, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Why Electric Buses Haven’t Taken Over the World—Yet Here’s what stands between you and a cleaner commute. https://www.wired.com/story/electric-buses-havent-taken-over-world/

June 6, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies This Startup Wants to Remake the Last Mile of Parcel Delivery Boxbot is building self-driving delivery vans, plus an automatic loading system. Humans would still help when needed to open gates or climb stairs. https://www.wired.com/story/startup-wants-remake-last-mile-parcel-delivery/

June 5, 2019 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton Bridgestone’s New Tire Makes Driving Electric as Quiet as It Should Be The Turanza QuietTrack has specially designed threads to hush the pesky “pattern noise” that’s especially noticeable in cars without loud engines. https://www.wired.com/story/bridgestone-turanza-quiettrack-tire/

June 4, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall How Mattel Shrinks Cars Into Hot Wheels (Crash Test Included) Before a Hot Wheels car hits a store shelf, it must pass the “launcher on speed 2” test and the “side slam launcher” test, among others. https://www.wired.com/story/how-mattel-shrinks-cars-hot-wheels-crash-tests-included/

June 3, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall What a Bay Area Dispute Says About the Future of Bike Share Lyft’s Motivate has exclusive bike-share contracts with several cities. San Francisco officials are debating what “exclusive” means. https://www.wired.com/story/what-bay-area-dispute-future-bike-share/

June 2, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Hybrid Ferraris! Flying Cars! And More Car News This Week Plus: You can now pay for some NYC subway rides with your iPhone, but the system is about more than just fast taps. https://www.wired.com/story/hybrid-ferraris-flying-cars-more-car-news-this-week/

May 31, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall New York Transit Edges Into a Future Without MetroCards Beginning Friday, you can get into select subway stations by waving your phone. By 2023, MetroCards will go the way of the token. https://www.wired.com/story/new-york-transit-edges-future-without-metrocards/

May 30, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Ferrari’s 986-HP Hybrid, Disney’s Message to Georgia, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/ferrari-hybrid-netflix-disney-georgia-abortion/

May 30, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Flying Car Startup Alaka’i Bets Hydrogen Can Outdo Batteries The new aviation player is showing off a boxy electric six-rotor air taxi powered by hydrogen fuel cells. https://www.wired.com/story/alakai-flying-car-air-taxi-evtol-hydrogen/

May 30, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Ferrari’s Latest Goes 211 MPH With 986 HP—and It’s a Hybrid The SF90 Stradale is Ferrari’s most powerful production vehicle: a plug-in hybrid electric that goes 0 to 62 mph in 2.5 seconds. https://www.wired.com/story/ferraris-latest-goes-211-mph-986-hp-hybrid/

May 29, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Don’t Overestimate the ‘Semi’ in Semiautonomous Cars A new report shows more cars in the US can guide themselves down the highway—but drivers often don’t know what those systems can and can’t do. https://www.wired.com/story/dont-overestimate-semi-semi-autonomous-cars/

May 27, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Dyson Patent Applications Offer Hints at Its Electric Car Appliance maker Dyson has offered few details of its promised electric car. Newly public filings reveal some of the company’s thinking. https://www.wired.com/story/dyson-patent-applications-offer-hints-electric-car/

May 26, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Elon Musk Gets a Boring Customer and More This Week in Car News Las Vegas goes into the digging biz with Musk, GM unveils a new electric nervous system for its cars—plus the Rolls-Royce Champagne Chest of the Week. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-boring-las-vegas-roundup/

May 25, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The ‘Hingeless’ Mechanics of a Stunt Helicopter Flight Over NYC For a stomach-twisting performance above Manhattan, Red Bull brought in an elite pilot and an unusual sort of helicopter. https://www.wired.com/story/red-bull-nyc-aerobatic-helicopter/

May 24, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Hiking or Camping? Take the Bus to the Trail This Summer Transit agencies and nonprofits are teaming up to expand access to parks and recreation areas. https://www.wired.com/story/hiking-camping-take-bus-trail-summer/

May 23, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Self-Driving Startup Aurora Buys Speed-Sensing Lidar Company Aurora is buying Blackmore, whose “Doppler lidar” system can determine how far away an object it, and its speed. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-startup-aurora-buys-speed-sensing-lidar/

May 23, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies VW’s ‘Dieselgate’ Settlement Isn’t Buying Many Electric Vehicles States were given almost $3 billion from Volkswagen’s diesel scandal settlement to buy cleaner vehicles. But many are buying more diesels, a report shows. https://www.wired.com/story/vws-dieselgate-settlement-isnt-buying-many-electric-vehicles/

May 22, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Las Vegas Orders Up a Boring Company Loop Which means Elon Musk’s “mass transit” tunneling company has its first official customer. https://www.wired.com/story/las-vegas-orders-up-boring-company-loop/

May 21, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The USPS Tests Out Self-Driving Trucks for Hauling Mail In a two-week test, startup TuSimple will transport mail for the US Postal Service between Phoenix and Dallas. https://www.wired.com/story/usps-tests-self-driving-trucks-hauling-mail/

May 20, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb GM’s Big Upgrade, Game of Thrones’ Unsatisfying End, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/gm-new-computer-game-of-thrones-finale/

May 20, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies GM Gives All Its Vehicles a New Soul GM’s new “electronic platform” offers five times the bandwidth and compute power of its predecessor, to deliver better maps and new accessories. https://www.wired.com/story/gm-gives-vehicles-new-soul/

May 19, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Want to Bike Cross-Country? Some Old Rails Could Get You There The Rails to Trails Conservancy is trying to assemble a 3,700-mile route that crosses 12 states. It needs help in Wyoming. https://www.wired.com/story/bike-cross-country-old-rails-get-you-there/

May 19, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Another Fatal Tesla Autopilot Crash and More Car News This Week The NTSB said a Tesla Model 3 had its Autopilot engaged when it collided with a truck in Florida in March, killing the driver. https://www.wired.com/story/another-fatal-tesla-autopilot-crash-more-car-news/

May 18, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Building a Bus Map When There Are No Fixed Routes—or Stops Citizen groups in Beirut, Nairobi, Cairo, and other cities are crowdsourcing maps of informal bus networks to encourage transit use. https://www.wired.com/story/building-bus-map-when-no-fixed-routes-stops/

May 16, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Fatal Tesla Autopilot Crash, Rising Methane Levels, and More News Catch up on the most important news today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-autopilot-crash-methane-climate-change-todays-news/

May 16, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Tesla’s Latest Autopilot Death Looks Just Like a Prior Crash A Florida man was killed March 1 when his Tesla collided with a tractor trailer that was crossing its path. A government report says the Autopilot feature was activated. https://www.wired.com/story/teslas-latest-autopilot-death-looks-like-prior-crash/

May 16, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Lilium’s 36-Motor Flying Taxi Takes Off for the First Time The latest aircraft vying for a piece of the not-quite-realized aeromobility space takes a big step toward becoming a reality. https://www.wired.com/story/lilium-electric-aircraft-prototype-first-flight-jet/

May 15, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies VW Will Make Its Own Batteries to Power an Electric Future The German automaker plans 70 electric models by 2028. So it’s building a gigafactory to ensure it has enough batteries. https://www.wired.com/story/vw-make-batteries-power-electric-future/

May 14, 2019 | Author: Alexander C. KaufmanAlexander C. Kaufman Daimler Plans to Make Its Cars Carbon Neutral by 2039 The carmaker’s new climate plan is bold—for a company. But it falls short of recommended emissions cuts and shows the limits of corporate self-policing. https://www.wired.com/story/daimler-plans-to-make-its-cars-carbon-neutral-by-2039/

May 13, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Why Uber Is Fighting Cities Over Data on Scooter Trips Los Angeles and other cities want data on shared scooters. Uber and Lyft claim that could compromise user privacy—and their own trade secrets. https://www.wired.com/story/why-uber-fighting-cities-data-about-scooters/

May 12, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber’s Underwhelming IPO, Lyft Earnings and More Car News This Week A decade after it was founded, Uber went public. Its shares fell almost 8% on their first day of trading. https://www.wired.com/story/ubers-underwhelming-ipo-lyft-earnings-more-car-news/

May 10, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Uber’s IPO, the Call to Break Up Facebook, and More News Catch up on the most important news today in 2 minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-ipo-facebook-breakup-democratic-candidates-climate-change/

May 10, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A Bet on Uber Is a Bet on Self-Driving Uber is scheduled to go public Friday, at an initial valuation of $82 billion, the largest for an IPO since 2014. But its future may rest on eliminating drivers. https://www.wired.com/story/bet-uber-bet-self-driving/

May 8, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall On Eve of Uber’s IPO, Ride-Hail Drivers Stage Protests Uber and Lyft drivers shut their apps Wednesday to protest for better pay and benefits, and recognition as employees rather than contractors. https://www.wired.com/story/eve-ubers-ipo-ride-hail-drivers-stage-protests/

May 8, 2019 | Author: Antonio García MartínezAntonio García Martínez My Wild Ride in a Robot Race Car On a track in Northern California, our writer tags along with the scrappy tinkerers of the autonomous-vehicle gold rush, who gather to share tech and race their robot cars. It’s the Homebrew Computer Club on wheels. https://www.wired.com/story/my-wild-ride-in-robot-race-car/

May 7, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Lyft’s Loss Grows, but Execs Say the Bleeding Will Stop Soon In its first quarterly results as a public company, Lyft said revenue almost doubled, but its loss grew even faster. https://www.wired.com/story/lyfts-loss-grows-execs-say-bleeding-stop-soon/

May 7, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Cruise’s $1 Billion Infusion Shows the Stakes in Self-Driving Tech Cruise, majority owned by GM, is at least the fourth company working on self-driving technology to raise $500 million or more in the past six months. https://www.wired.com/story/cruises-billion-infusion-shows-stakes-self-driving-tech/

May 5, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla Raises Money, Drones Get Certified, and More Car News This Week Tesla says it will raise up to $2.7 billion in new capital, and Uber prepares for its IPO. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-raises-money-drones-get-certified-more-car-news/

May 3, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Riding a Scooter? Protect Your Head Half of injuries to 190 scooter riders in Austin last fall were to the head; only one of the injured riders was wearing a helmet. https://www.wired.com/story/riding-scooter-protect-your-head/

April 29, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall How Tactical Drivers Learn Crazy-Ass Maneuvers And you thought you could maneuver out of dangerous situations. https://www.wired.com/story/how-tactical-drivers-learn-crazy-ass-maneuvers/

April 28, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla’s Robotaxis, Ugly Earnings, and More Car News This Week The electric automaker reported a $700 million quarterly loss and faces a strengthened rival after Ford pumped $500 million into startup Rivian. https://www.wired.com/story/teslas-robotaxis-ugly-earnings-more-car-news-this-week/

April 27, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Drone Delivery Services Are Actually, Finally Almost Here The FAA just gave Google spinoff Wing permission to start deliveries, and cool new tech keeps the buzzy birds flying. But (of course) challenges remain. https://www.wired.com/story/drone-delivery-services-are-actually-finally-almost-here/

April 26, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Elon’s Court-Approved Twitter-Sitter, Measles in LA, and More News Catch up on the most important news today in 2 minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-sec-measles-la-outbreak/

April 26, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla CEO Elon Musk Will Get a Stricter Twitter Babysitter Musk and the SEC settled their latest dispute over his not-always-truthful tweets, with stricter standards for what’s permissible in missives. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-ceo-elon-musk-stricter-twitter-babysitter/

April 26, 2019 | Author: Chris MellonChris Mellon Why a Geocode Is Not an Address Opinion: Geocodes have been suggested as a solution for Puerto Rico’s address problem. But there’s more to an address than determining location. https://www.wired.com/story/geocode-address-puerto-rico-hurricane-maria/

April 24, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla Is Losing Money Again As Deliveries Decline After two quarters of profitability, the electric automaker reported a $702 million loss in the first quarter. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-losing-money-again-deliveries-decline/

April 24, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Tesla’s Robotaxi Pledge, a Browser That Pays You, and More News Catch up on the most important news today in 2 minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-robotaxi-elon-musk-brave-browser-golden-state-killer/

April 24, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Old Promises Broken, Musk Offers New Pledges on Self-Driving Ahead of what’s expected to be a disappointing earnings report, Tesla CEO Elon Musk predicts 1 million “robotaxis” on the road by next year. https://www.wired.com/story/promises-broken-musk-offers-new-pledges-self-driving/

April 24, 2019 | Author: Tom SimoniteTom Simonite Tesla’s New Chip Holds the Key to ‘Full Self-Driving’ CEO Elon Musk says that in a year more than 1 million Teslas will be capable of driving themselves while a person sleeps in the driver’s seat. https://www.wired.com/story/teslas-new-chip-holds-key-full-self-driving/

April 22, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers LA’s Plan to Reboot Its Bus System—Using Cell Phone Data Ridership on the city’s bus system is plummeting, so the transit agency is redesigning it—with the help of location data from about 5 million cell phones. https://www.wired.com/story/future-of-transportation-los-angeles-bus-cell-phone-data/

April 22, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Waze Wants to Help All of Us Win at Carpooling The world’s premier traffic-busting app has a plan for when traffic never ever gets better: get us all to share commutes, and become … friends? https://www.wired.com/story/future-of-transportation-waze-carpool-app/

April 22, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Kitty Hawk, Flying Cars, and the Challenges of ‘Going 3D’ At a startup run by autonomous vehicle mastermind Sebastian Thrun, the dream of flying cars is starting to become reality. But expect flight delays. https://www.wired.com/story/future-of-transportation-kitty-hawk-self-flying-cars/

April 22, 2019 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton EV Upstart Rivian Is Helping to Drive a New Auto Tech Boom A explosion of new technologies has companies flooding the auto industry en masse—again. https://www.wired.com/story/future-of-transportation-rivian-auto-tech-boom/

April 22, 2019 | Author: Alex Davies, Aarian MarshallAlex Davies and Aarian Marshall Are We There Yet? A Reality Check on Self-Driving Cars Fully autonomous cars may never arrive. But we’ll all benefit from self-driving tech while we wait. https://www.wired.com/story/future-of-transportation-self-driving-cars-reality-check/

April 22, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies EV and Self-Driving Tech Let Auto Designers Go Wild A back seat that transforms into a throne, front seats that swivel to face one another—Nissan’s IMs concept shows what designers do when tech liberates them. https://www.wired.com/story/future-of-transportation-nissan-ims-ev-auto-design/

April 21, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Punny SUVs at the NY Auto Show and More Car News This Week Genesis shows off an electric two-seater it may never build, Elon Musk takes a step toward a really big tunnel, and Uber gets another $1 billion investment. https://www.wired.com/story/punny-suvs-ny-auto-show-more-car-news/

April 20, 2019 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton British Beach-Goers Could Get a Bigger Road Through Stonehenge It’s a tunnel that passes underneath it, to be more specific. Conservationists have their reservations. https://www.wired.com/story/british-beach-goers-could-get-bigger-road-through-stonehenge/

April 19, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber Recruits Some Rich Friends to Drive its Autonomous Cars Toyota, Japanese auto supplier Denso, and the Softbank Vision Fund are investing $1 billion in Uber’s self-driving car unit. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-recruits-some-rich-friends-drive-autonomous-cars/

April 19, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Elon Musk’s Boring Company Inches Closer to Making Hyperloop a Reality The company filed a sprawling environmental report for the Loop, a proposed network of tunnels that would move people from Baltimore to Washington in 15 minutes. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musks-boring-company-takes-small-step-toward-reality/

April 18, 2019 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton Climate Change Threatens Ice Roads. Satellites Could Help Diamond mines in Canada have a short window in which to truck in their equipment—satellite sensors could help ice roads keep on truckin’. https://www.wired.com/story/climate-change-threatens-ice-roads-satellites-could-help/

April 17, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Injuries Force Lyft to Hit the Brakes on Its E-Bike Ambitions Lyft’s Motivate subsidiary pulled its e-bikes from New York, Washington, and San Francisco after riders reported injuries resulting from unexpectedly strong front brakes. https://www.wired.com/story/injuries-force-lyft-hit-brakes-e-bikes-ambitions/

April 16, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Boeing 737 Crashes May Make It Harder for Air Taxis to Take Off Observers expect the FAA to slow approval of new technologies in the wake of two fatal crashes. That could affect development of nascent “air taxis.” https://www.wired.com/story/boeing-737-crashes-harder-air-taxis-take-off/

April 14, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber Hails a Ride to Wall Street, and More Car News This Week Uber revealed its filing for an initial public offering, Tesla changes its sales strategy again, and Ford’s CEO joins the caution chorus on fully self-driving cars. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-hails-ride-wall-street-more-car-news/

April 13, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Stratolaunch, the World’s Biggest Airplane, Takes Flight Microsoft cofounder Paul Allen’s legacy moon shot, an aircraft to carry rockets to space, hits 17,000 feet. https://www.wired.com/story/stratolaunch-flight/

April 12, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla Shifts Gears, Again, and Some Fans Are Losing Patience Tesla said it would remove the $35,000 version of its Model 3 sedan from online ordering forms, weeks after a back-and-forth over closing showrooms. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-shifts-gears-again-some-fans-losing-patience/

April 11, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber’s Losing Less Money—but Growing Less Too Uber revealed its plans to go public just weeks after Lyft. The filing shows that Uber dwarfs its rival, but the company continues to post operating losses. https://www.wired.com/story/ubers-losing-less-moneybut-growing-less-too/

April 9, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Ford Taps the Brakes on the Arrival of Self-Driving Cars Ford CEO Jim Hackett joined the growing ranks of executives saying that fully self-driving cars won’t arrive as soon as some had forecast. https://www.wired.com/story/ford-taps-brakes-arrival-self-driving-cars/

April 8, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Why a New Crop of Electric SUV Batteries Are Coming Up Short First the Jaguar I-Pace, now the Audi E-tron: The vehicles’ EPA range ratings are falling short of expectations. https://www.wired.com/story/audi-e-tron-epa-range-anxiety-batteries/

April 7, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla’s Disappointing Numbers and More Car News This Week Tesla’s deliveries fell 31 percent in the first quarter compared with the previous quarter. New York moves toward congestion pricing. And trucking futures. https://www.wired.com/story/teslas-disappointing-numbers-more-car-news-this-week/

April 4, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla Is Better at Making Cars. Delivering Them? Not So Much. The always-exciting electric car maker suffers its biggest drop in deliveries yet in the first quarter. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-better-making-cars-delivering-them-not-so-much/

April 4, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Audi’s New Electric-Car Factory Goes Green Electric vehicles consume more energy than gasoline-powered rides during manufacturing. Audi’s new E-tron plant tries to change that. https://www.wired.com/story/audi-e-tron-green-factory/

April 2, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall What Will Be the Right Price to Cut Congestion in New York? New York will become the first US city to impose fees on driving in busy parts of town to raise money for its ailing subway system. But setting the right price won’t be easy. https://www.wired.com/story/what-will-be-right-price-cut-congestion-new-york/

April 1, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams UPS Drones Are Now Moving Blood Samples Over North Carolina The FAA’s first sanctioned, revenue-generating drone delivery service involves speeding up the movement of blood and tissue samples. https://www.wired.com/story/ups-matternet-drone-delivery-north-carolina/

March 31, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Inside a Ferrari Hypercar, Lyft’s IPO, and More Car News Plus, we ride the Jeep Gladiator and ponder the future of electric vehicles, courtesy of battery-swapping rickshaws. https://www.wired.com/story/ferrari-p80c-hypercar-lyft-ipo-roundup/

March 31, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Futures Aren’t Just for Juice. They’re for Truck Routes Too Many futures are for physical products, while others border on metaphysical. You can buy and sell on snowfall, box office returns, energy prices—and now trucking. https://www.wired.com/story/futures-arent-just-juice-truck-routes/

March 30, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Bobble-Heading Through the Mud in the Jeep Gladiator Pickup The $33,545 Gladiator is made for the toughest off-road conditions you can find—with a few creature comforts thrown in. https://www.wired.com/story/jeep-gladiator-pickup-off-road-review-photos-specs/

March 29, 2019 | Author: Aarian Marshall, Scott ThurmAarian Marshall and Scott Thurm Here Come the Gig-Economy IPOs: Lyft Rises on Its First Day Lyft got a jump on rival Uber with its IPO. Investors liked the offering despite the ride-hailing company’s growing losses. https://www.wired.com/story/lyft-ipo-filing-ridership-revenue-losses-costs-charts/

March 29, 2019 | Author: Megha BahreeMegha Bahree India Goes Electric With Battery-Swapping Rickshaws Because even an electric autorickshaw can be out of reach for many, SUN Mobility is trying a different tack to clean up India’s air. https://www.wired.com/story/india-sun-mobility-electric-rickshaw-bus-battery-swap/

March 28, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Complex Quest to Write a Robocar Driving Test Self-driving cars are patrolling our roads, and it’s about time someone made a proper engineering standard that they can be held to. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-car-standards-certification-underwriters-laboratory/

March 26, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Ferrari Built the Track-Slaying P80/C for a Single Customer The unnamed buyer spent dio knows how much on a hypercar that oozes with Ferrari heritage but blazes around corners. https://www.wired.com/story/ferrari-p80c-hypercar/

March 26, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The War to Remotely Control Self-Driving Cars Heats Up Designated Driver is just the latest competitor to enter the market for the teleoperation tech that will make robo-cars work. https://www.wired.com/story/designated-driver-teleoperations-self-driving-cars/

March 25, 2019 | Author: Laura MalloneeLaura Mallonee The Engine Propelling the Fastest Woman on Four Wheels A turbojet engine used on F-4 Phantom jets during the Vietnam War finds a new purpose. https://www.wired.com/story/the-engine-propelling-the-fastest-woman-on-four-wheels/

March 24, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall How Self-Driving Has Changed Since Uber’s Crash and More Car News Plus: Tesla sues Zoox over trade secrets, riding with Peloton’s truck train, and more. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-crash-anniversary-tesla-zoox-lawsuit-roundup/

March 23, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Safety-Obsessed Volvo Goes After Distracted, Speedy Drivers To go with smarter safety tech, Volvo is upping its driver-monitoring efforts and putting speed limits on all its cars. https://www.wired.com/story/volvo-safety-distracted-driving-speed-limit/

March 21, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla Sues Zoox Over Manufacturing and Logistics Secrets The automaker says four former employees took proprietary information to their new jobs at Zoox. Oh, and Tesla sued an employee of another rival too. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-sues-zoox-over-manufacturing-logistics-secrets/

March 21, 2019 | Author: Joe LindseyJoe Lindsey A New Wave of Brainy Bikes Do Everything but Ride Themselves Automated gear changes, app-controlled suspensions, overtaking vehicle alerts, and more smart tech are here for the human-powered two-wheeler. https://www.wired.com/story/cycling-smart-connected-tech-sram/

March 20, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A Cab’s-Eye View of How Peloton’s Trucks ‘Talk’ to Each Other It’s a technology called platooning, and it could be safer and more efficient than regular truck driving, and easier to implement than full-on robo trucks. https://www.wired.com/story/cabs-eye-view-how-pelotons-trucks-talk/

March 19, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams A Tap-to-Fly Helicopter Shows How Flying Cars Might Take Off Sikorsky’s Matrix Technology program has made giving flight a whirl a matter of tapping on a tablet. https://www.wired.com/story/sikorsky-sara-helicopter-autonomous-flying-car-air-taxi-tech/

March 18, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall SEC: Elon Musk Fully Ignored a Key Term of Settlement In a new court filing, the US agency argues a federal judge should hold the Tesla CEO in contempt for his tweets. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-tesla-sec-lawsuit-twitter-court-filing/

March 18, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall 1 Year After Uber’s Fatal Crash, Robocars Carry On Quietly In the autonomy industry, companies are now more circumspect about when their life-saving technology will hit the road. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-crash-elaine-herzberg-anniversary-safety-self-driving/

March 17, 2019 | Author: Alex Davies, Aarian MarshallAlex Davies and Aarian Marshall Boeing’s 737 Crash, Tesla’s Model Y, and More News This Week This week’s transportation news focused on two major stories: the investigation into the fatal crash of Ethiopian Flight 302 and Elon Musk’s reveal of Tesla’s new baby SUV. https://www.wired.com/story/boeing-737-crash-tesla-model-y-roundup/

March 15, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Stacking Tesla’s Model Y Against Its Electric SUV Competition Elon Musk’s latest creation is entering a crowded market. Here’s how its specs match those of Audi, Jaguar, Mercedes, and more. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-model-y-suv-specs-competitors-compared/

March 15, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies How Investigators Pull Data off a Boeing 737’s Black Boxes The recovery process can be slow, and may involve baking them in an oven, but the information investigators recover can be crucial to preventing future crashes. https://www.wired.com/story/boeing-737-max-8-ethiopia-crash-black-box-data-lion-air/

March 15, 2019 | Author: Aarian Marshall, Alex DaviesAarian Marshall and Alex Davies Elon Musk’s Model Y SUV Brings More Tesla to More Masses It starts at $39,000, has up to 300 miles of range, and is due out in fall 2020. Oh, and it has a panoramic glass roof. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-model-y-specs-photos-reveal/

March 15, 2019 | Author: Alex Davies, Aarian MarshallAlex Davies and Aarian Marshall Liveblog: Tesla Debuts the Model Y, Its Baby SUV Follow along with us as Elon Musk takes the stage to show off Tesla’s latest creation. https://www.wired.com/story/live-tesla-debuts-the-model-y-its-baby-suv/

March 14, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies How to Watch Tesla’s Model Y Reveal Elon Musk will soon show off his automaker’s new baby SUV, so here’s what we know and how to stay up to speed. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-watch-live-video-elon-musk-model-y/

March 13, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Boeing’s Grounded 737s Won’t Cause Massive Flight Delays The aviation industry is used to disruptions, and it knows how to keep customers—especially fancy ones—moving. https://www.wired.com/story/boeing-737-crash-grounded-flight-delays-cancellations/

March 13, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Boeing Plans to Fix the 737 MAX Jet With a Software Update But a plan that seemed straightforward has been complicated by the Ethiopian Airlines crash. https://www.wired.com/story/boeing-737-max-8-ethiopia-crash-faa-software-fix-lion-air/

March 13, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall FAA Grounds Boeing’s 737 MAX Jet Days After Ethiopia Crash The agency has banned the 737 MAX jet from flying in US airspace, effective immediately. https://www.wired.com/story/boeing-737-max-8-ethiopia-crash-faa-ground-safety/

March 12, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Cracking the Devilish Aerodynamics of Newfangled Flying Cars As outfits like Beta, Joby, and Kitty Hawk explore new kinds of aircraft with pivoting rotors, wings, and more, they must crack the complex problem of keeping heavier-than-air machines aloft. https://www.wired.com/story/beta-ava-flying-car-aerodynamics/

March 12, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Elon Musk Says Tweeting Is Free Speech in His SEC Battle The Tesla CEO’s lawyers argue the SEC has overreached in its attempt to see Musk held in contempt of court over a recent tweet. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-tesla-twitter-sec-settlement/

March 10, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Crashed Ethiopian Air Jet Is Same Model as Lion Air Accident An Ethiopian Airlines Boeing 737 MAX 8 crashed shortly after takeoff Sunday, evoking comparisons to an Indonesian incident in October. https://www.wired.com/story/crashed-ethiopian-air-jet-same-model-lion-air-accident/

March 10, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Electric Minivans at the Geneva Motor Show, and More Car News Plus: Lightweight leather, dune buggies, and a volume knob made from a meteorite. https://www.wired.com/story/electric-minivans-geneva-motor-show-car-news/

March 9, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Knobs Made of Meteorite and More Geneva Motor Show Insanity The annual gathering is where high-end automakers show their stuff, and this year’s show included a Rolls-Royce offering that’s, well, (from) out of this world. https://www.wired.com/story/geneva-motor-show-ferrari-mclaren-rolls-royce/

March 7, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Scooter Startups Are Ditching Gig Workers for Real Employees Spin is experimenting with a move away from gig workers in favor of proper employees—and it’s not alone. https://www.wired.com/story/spin-scooter-share-gig-economy-employees/

March 6, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Waymo’s Move to Sell Lidar Units Is a Bet on a Bigger Market The shift to sell its technology to robotics and security companies is an indication that Waymo isn’t placing all its bets on self-driving cars. https://www.wired.com/story/waymo-selling-lidar-fought-uber-protect/

March 5, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Mercedes Remakes the Minivan as an All-Electric Luxury Ride The German automaker’s MPV has room for eight, 249 miles of range, and makes the kiddie karter look good. https://www.wired.com/story/mercedes-electric-minivan-mpv/

March 4, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies How Amazon Taught the Echo Auto to Hear You in a Noisy Car Start with a sort of crash test dummy that has creepily realistic human ears, then add a bunch of road noise. Repeat. https://www.wired.com/story/amazon-echo-auto-engineering/

March 3, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla’s $35,000 Model 3 Arrives and More Cars News This Week Elon Musk hits a milestone and gets in trouble with the SEC, Lyft files for its IPO, cities investigate congestion pricing, and more. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-model-3-35000-lyft-ipo-roundup/

March 2, 2019 | Author: Aaron GordonAaron Gordon How Arrivo Got Colorado to Back a Wild-Eyed Highway Scheme Brogan BamBrogan’s company promised Colorado a hyperloop-inspired transportation, then shut down. https://www.wired.com/story/arrivo-colorado-brogan-bambrogan-hyperloop-concept/

February 28, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Age of Congestion Pricing May Finally Be Upon Us Some US cities might start charging extra to drive on crowded, busy roads. https://www.wired.com/story/age-of-congestion-pricing-nyc/

February 28, 2019 | Author: Aarian Marshall, Alex DaviesAarian Marshall and Alex Davies Tesla Is (Finally!) Selling the Model 3 for $35,000 Elon Musk’s automaker is also introducing a slightly more capable version of the car, moving its sales process online, and shuttering many of its stores. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-model-3-35000-price-autopilot-self-driving-stores-closing/

February 27, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Polestar Tempts the Masses by Taking on the Tesla Model 3 The electric car is plenty fast, fairly cheap, and carving out a not-quite-luxurious niche in a booming category. https://www.wired.com/story/polestar-2-electric-volvo/

February 25, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Elon Musk’s Latest Tweets Land Him in Yet More Trouble The SEC has asked a judge to hold the Tesla CEO in contempt of court, but even that didn’t stop Musk’s tweeting. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-tweet-tesla-contempt-court-sec/

February 25, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Inside the Creation of Zero’s All-New Electric Motorcycle With bigger players moving into the e-bike market, Zero thinks the SR/F puts it back at the front of the pack. https://www.wired.com/story/zero-srf-electric-motorcycle-photos-specs-design/

February 24, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Trouble Brews Anew at Tesla, Plus More Car News This Week The Tesla Model 3 loses its Consumer Reports recommended status, we drive Hyundai’s hydrogen-powered SUV, and more. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-self-driving-model-3-news-roundup/

February 22, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies New Hydrogen-Powered Hyundai: a Gas to Drive, a Pain to Fuel The Nexo is an excellent electric SUV, but that may not be enough to overcome the difficulties of driving on hydrogen. https://www.wired.com/story/hyundai-nexo-review-hydrogen-fuel-cell-electric/

February 19, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Elon Musk Promises a Really Truly Self-Driving Tesla in 2020 The CEO says his Autopilot system will be “feature-complete” this year, and ready to ferry snoozing passengers by the end of next year. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-tesla-full-self-driving-2019-2020-promise/

February 19, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Audi Cars Tell You How Fast to Go to Catch All Green Lights The automaker’s new feature taps into light timing data to let drivers ride the “green wave” and breeze through town. https://www.wired.com/story/audi-glosa-green-light-connected/

February 18, 2019 | Author: Jonathon KeatsJonathon Keats Jargon Watch: What ‘Roadmanship’ Means to a Self-Driving Car More than a century later, the quaint term is back as a basis for long-overdue safety standards in autonomous vehicles. https://www.wired.com/story/jargon-watch-roadmanship-self-driving-cars/

February 18, 2019 | Author: Rebecca HeilweilRebecca Heilweil How a DIY Tesla Mechanic Resurrects Damaged Electric Cars Rich Benoit stumps for the right-to-repair movement, pushing uncooperative manufacturers to make it easier for owners to fix stuff themselves. https://www.wired.com/story/diy-tesla-mechanic-resurrects-damaged-electric-cars/

February 17, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Digging Into Self-Driving Data and More Car News This Week Plus: We bid adieu to the Airbus A380, Amazon makes a move, and we take a tour of the gear that keeps Nascar racers on the oval. https://www.wired.com/story/amazon-rivian-self-driving-disengagement-reports/

February 15, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber Sues NYC to Kill Its Ride-Hail Car Cap New York’s mayor says the rule, which halts the granting of new licenses, is vital for reining in congestion. Uber says the city is overreaching. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-nyc-lawsuit-car-cap/

February 15, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall See All the Tools and Tricks That Make Nascar Go If perfectly arranged drawers and heart-stopping car racing is your thing, you’ll be glad to meet the crews who make it happen. https://www.wired.com/story/nascar-pit-stop-race-crew-tour/

February 14, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Bid Adieu to the A380, the World’s Jumbo-est Passenger Jet It was so huge that it required a whole special bespoke transportation logistics setup, but no one wanted to buy it. https://www.wired.com/story/airbus-a380-cancelled/

February 13, 2019 | Author: Alex Davies, Aarian MarshallAlex Davies and Aarian Marshall A New Robo-Car Report Card Isn’t Quite What It Seems The numbers are a little jumbly, but reports published by the state’s DMV show progress toward the day when humans are unshackled from the steering wheel. https://www.wired.com/story/new-robo-car-report-card-not-what-it-seems/

February 13, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Americans Are Abandoning Public Transit—but Don’t Blame Uber In a world of cheap gas, easy-come auto loans, ride-hail, and now a new breed of bike- and scooter-share, transit riders aren’t riding like they used to. https://www.wired.com/story/transit-center-census-americans-public-transportation/

February 13, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Forget People, Elroy’s Self-Flying Drone Hauls Heavy Cargo The hybrid-powered aircraft will carry up to 500 pounds with a range of 300 miles and could enter service next year. https://www.wired.com/story/elroy-cargo-drone-chaparral/

February 11, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Softbank Invests $1B in Robo-Delivery Startup Nuro So get ready to see a lot more of the company’s toaster-inspired, human-free robots roaming the street, delivering groceries. https://www.wired.com/story/softbank-nuro-self-driving-investment/

February 10, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Amazon’s Self-Driving Bet and More Car News This Week The logistics giant invests in autonomous vehicle startup Aurora, the micromobility world ponders its future, we review the new Porsche 911, and more. https://www.wired.com/story/amazon-aurora-self-driving-roundup/

February 8, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Green New Deal’s Trains and EVs Won’t Work for Everyone Access to cars is the best short-term solution for connecting lower-income people to jobs, but the autos they can afford are the worst for the planet. https://www.wired.com/story/green-new-deal-electric-cars/

February 8, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Ride With the Guy Who Builds Roller Coasters in His Yard With the help of a 300-pound test dummy named Todd, Will Pemble has turned his home into an amusement park. https://www.wired.com/story/homebuilt-roller-coaster-video/

February 7, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Amazon Dives Into Self-Driving Cars With a Bet on Aurora The tech titan just announced its investing in autonomous technology developer Aurora. https://www.wired.com/story/amazon-aurora-self-driving-investment-funding-series-b/

February 6, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams With Its New 911, Porsche Improves the Unimprovable—Again The evolution of the 911 has always relied on key incremental advances, and the eighth generation continues the tradition of striving for perfection. https://www.wired.com/story/porsche-911-carrera-2020/

February 4, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Micromobility: the Prose and Poetry of the Scooter-Faithful The shared, electric scooter and bike-based industry has earned its own conference—even as the hype starts to cool. https://www.wired.com/story/micromobility-conference-scooters-bikes/

February 3, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla Profits, a Polar Vortex, and More This Week in Car News Plus: Lyft tries to stop a driver minimum wage law and carbon fiber production is going to be problematic for flying taxis. https://www.wired.com/story/future-of-cars-tesla-earnings/

January 31, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Why’d the Polar Vortex Cancel So Many Flights? Blame Humans Freezing temperatures may not bother airplanes, but they are no good for the people on the ground who make them fly. https://www.wired.com/story/polar-vortex-chicago-flights-cancelled-cold-why/

January 31, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall NYC Now Knows More Than Ever About Your Uber and Lyft Trips The city has an unusual amount of insight into what ride-hail companies do on its streets, and it uses the info to plan for the future. https://www.wired.com/story/nyc-uber-lyft-ride-hail-data/

January 30, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Tesla Moves to Build the Model Y After a Gangbusters 2018 Elon Musk’s car company just announced its second profitable quarter in a row, but keeping the momentum going requires more focus on costs and a move overseas. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-q4-2018-profits-elon-musk-model-y/

January 30, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Lyft Sues New York City Over Driver Minimum Wage Rules Ride-hail companies Lyft and Juno say the new rules, set to roll out Friday, would benefit the market leader: Uber. https://www.wired.com/story/lyft-sues-new-york-city-driver-minimum-wage/

January 30, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies A Windshield-Mounted Cure for the Common Pothole CarVi would use its camera-carrying gadgets to identify the scourges, then share the info with local governments. https://www.wired.com/story/carvi-pothole-detection/

January 30, 2019 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Why Electric Cars Struggle in the Cold—and How to Help Them Cold weather is no fun for battery-powered cars, but experienced owners have a few tips for getting by when the mercury drops. https://www.wired.com/story/electric-cars-cold-weather-tips/

January 29, 2019 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Mercedes’ EQC SUV Makes Everyday Electric Elite With some clever tricks and flair-free styling, Mercedes sets off down the battery-powered path. https://www.wired.com/story/mercedes-eqc-electric-suv/

January 29, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The Need for Carbon Fiber Could Ground the Flying-Car Future The many companies racing to launch air taxis face the gnarliness of building aircraft from the lightweight but finicky material. https://www.wired.com/story/air-taxi-flying-cars-carbon-fiber-production-icon-a5/

January 28, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Los Angeles Is Now Offering Car Rides to Metro Stations The city and ride-share company Via are testing a new service meant to get more people onto public transit. https://www.wired.com/story/los-angeles-metro-via-rideshare-pilot/

January 27, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber Wants Self-Driving Scooters and More Car News This Week Plus: Making public transit work better for women, the government shutdown messes with air traffic control, and more. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-self-driving-scooters-more-car-news/

January 26, 2019 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart A ‘Multicultural Toilet’ and Other Innovations to Fix Flying This year’s Crystal Cabin nominees offer new ways to make the most of precious space. https://www.wired.com/story/crystal-cabin-awards-multicultural-toilet/

January 25, 2019 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton Ending the Government Shutdown Won’t Fix Flight Delays The shutdown will have longterm effects, likely pushing aging air traffic controllers to retire and slowing the training of their replacements. https://www.wired.com/story/government-shutdown-air-traffic-controller-shortage/

January 25, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall America Needs Way, Way More Electric-Car Charging Stations The number of EVs on US roads is likely to triple in the next few years. Some places have more prep work to do than others. https://www.wired.com/story/us-charging-network-electric-vehicle-needs/

January 24, 2019 | Author: Alex Davies, Aarian MarshallAlex Davies and Aarian Marshall So Uber Wants Self-Driving Bikes and Scooters. Why? And How? They’d be difficult to engineer, and expensive to boot. But they’re part of the company’s master plan. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-self-driving-scooters/

January 23, 2019 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Boeing’s Flying Taxi Prototype Takes to the Air (Briefly) The company is one of the partners in Uber’s bid to fly the skies. https://www.wired.com/story/boeing-air-taxi-uber/

January 23, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Want to Boost Transit Ridership? Try Making Women Feel Safer Way more men than women are taking LA’s Expo line, and new research helps explain why. https://www.wired.com/story/boost-transit-ridership-women-safer/

January 21, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Do You Need a Digital License Plate? One Startup Thinks So It can pay your tolls, display Amber alerts, and track your location. But at several hundred bucks a pop, maybe your E-Z Pass will do for now. https://www.wired.com/story/digital-license-plates/

January 20, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Tesla’s Cost-Cutting Layoffs and More This Week in Car News Elon Musk prepares for lean times, news from CES and the Detroit Auto Show, and more in the future of cars. https://www.wired.com/story/future-of-cars-tesla-layoffs/

January 18, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Why Azealia Banks and Grimes Matter to a Tesla Investor Suit Shareholders are suing Elon Musk over that “taking Tesla private” tweet, and just got the right to subpoena Banks and Grimes. emphasized text https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-lawsuit-elon-musk-grimes-azealia-banks/

January 18, 2019 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla Cuts 3,000 Jobs, Bracing for an Uncertain Future Elon Musk’s automaker is laying off 7 percent of its full-time staff as it leans into the tough job of building mass-market cars. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-layoffs-cost-cutting/

January 17, 2019 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Detroit Auto Show Proves Americans Sure Love SUVs The people want their cars big and gas-powered. The automakers are happy to provide. https://www.wired.com/story/detroit-auto-show-2019-suvs-concepts/

January 16, 2019 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Bold Robocar Roaming Las Vegas Without a Human Backup Yandex, the “Google of Russia,” showed up at CES with a bold demonstration of what a Moscow-trained robot car can do. https://www.wired.com/story/robocar-roaming-las-vegas-without-human-backup/

January 15, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Bracing for a Hazy Robo-Future, Ford and VW Join Forces By joining forces, the major automakers have each diversified their self-driving portfolios. https://www.wired.com/story/ford-vw-alliance-self-driving-cars/

January 15, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies 10 Years Later, Retrace the ‘Miracle on the Hudson’ Flight On the anniversary of the remarkable crash landing, remember just how quickly it all happened. https://www.wired.com/story/miracle-hudson-flight-anniversary-flight-path-sully/

January 15, 2019 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart With a Cadillac SUV, GM Shows a New Way to an Electric World The concept teased at the Detroit Auto Show is the first step in a new way of winning drivers over to batteries and motors. https://www.wired.com/story/cadillac-electric-suv-gm-plan/

January 15, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall As Tech Invades Cycling, Are Bike Activists Selling Out? Now in the cycling business, Uber, Lyft, and others are co-opting the experience of longtime safe streets advocates. https://www.wired.com/story/cycling-advocacy-uber-lyft-bird-scooters/

January 14, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Ford’s Shelby GT500 Is the Most Powerful Mustang Ever The latest take on the muscled-up Mustang has more than 700 horsepower and might corner as well as it sprints. https://www.wired.com/story/ford-shelby-mustang-gt500-2020-specs-photos/

January 14, 2019 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart As Self-Driving Cars Stall, Players Revive an Old Approach With true autonomy proving harder than we hoped, some companies are refocusing on systems that split the work between human and machine. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-cars-ces-semi-autonomous-veoneer/

January 13, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Butt Sensors, Flying Taxis, and More This Week in Car News A Hyundai with legs, a Tesla Model S robot death stunt, and all the happenings out of CES that you missed. https://www.wired.com/story/ces-flying-cars-bell-beta-veoneer-self-driving-cars/

January 12, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Why Seattle Built—Then Buried—a Key Part of Its New Tunnel As the city gets ready to open the long-awaited SR 99 tunnel, it exhumes a crucial ramp it intentionally buried in 2013. https://www.wired.com/story/seattle-sr-99-tunnel-opening-on-ramp-excavation/

January 11, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies A New Camera Turns Its Gaze to the Driver—and Everyone Else Expect to see more systems like Guardian’s Optical Cabin Control as cars start to drive themselves—and need to watch their masters. https://www.wired.com/story/guardian-optical-cabin-control-driver-monitoring/

January 10, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Ford Axes Its Chariot Shuttles, Proves Mobility Is Hard Despite a change in strategy, the app-based commuter service couldn’t make its business work. https://www.wired.com/story/ford-axes-chariot-mobility-is-hard/

January 10, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Snow Can’t Stop the Edward Scissorhands of Flying Cars The Ava may look strange, but it’s a clever machine built for the coming age of air taxis. https://www.wired.com/story/beta-ava-flying-car-aviation/

January 9, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies VW’s EV Chargers Make Paying for Power Easier Than Ever VW’s Electrify America program is adding a capability that identifies the driver by their car and bills them automatically. https://www.wired.com/story/volkswagen-electric-car-charging-electrify-america-plug-charge/

January 8, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A Tesla-Robot ‘Crash’ Stunt Shows We Need Robocar Schooling The seemingly hoax-y death of “Promobot” is a handy justification for the newly launched Partnership for Automated Vehicle Education. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-promobot-pave-self-driving-education/

January 8, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Cabbies Unite! An App Challenges the Uber and Lyft Overlords SoMo is a new app from mapping company HERE that pushes back against ride-hail dominance by giving other drivers a common platform. https://www.wired.com/story/here-mobility-app-uber-lyft-challenge/

January 8, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A Third of Americans Use Ride-Hail. Uber and Lyft Need More That number has doubled since 2015, but Uber and Lyft have made little progress on their bigger goal: attracting regular riders. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-lyft-ride-hail-stats-pew-research/

January 7, 2019 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Hyundai’s Walking Car Concept With Legs Reinvents the Wheel The automaker’s ‘Elevate’ concept uses wheels as well as legs to move through any territory. https://www.wired.com/story/hyundai-walking-car-elevate-concept-ces/

January 7, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Bell Reveals a Surprisingly Down-to-Earth Air Taxi The company behind the V-22 Osprey and V-280 Valor brings its experience to the pie-in-the-sky flying car industry. https://www.wired.com/story/bell-nexus-air-taxi-flying-car/

January 7, 2019 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart You Can Now Buy Harley-Davidson’s Electric Motorcycle Unveiled today at CES, the LiveWire will hit 60 mph in 3.5 seconds and cover 110 miles between charging stops. https://www.wired.com/story/harley-davidson-electric-motorcycle-livewire/

January 6, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla’s Price Cut and More Car News From This Week Plus, New York cancels a much-hyped subway shutdown, self-driving cars have an interesting 2018, and we ride an odd, three-wheeled electric vehicle. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-price-cut-car-news-this-week/

January 4, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Simple Engineering That Will Keep NYC’s L Train Rolling Turns out there’s an easy way to fix the Canarsie Tunnel without shutting down the line for several years. And it’s already being used in other cities. https://www.wired.com/story/engineering-l-train-shutdown-canarsie-tunnel/

January 4, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall New York Has Averted a Subway Line Shutdown. Now What? Organizers and transit companies wonder how the canceled L-train shutdown will affect its silver lining: the plans to rethink its transportation system. https://www.wired.com/story/new-york-subway-l-train-bikes-pedestrian/

January 3, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall VW’s Mobile Chargers Could Help EVs Conquer the World These behemoths hold enough juice for 15 electric cars, and are meant to supplement areas with sub-par charging networks. https://www.wired.com/story/volkswagen-electric-car-charging-station-mobile/

January 2, 2019 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla’s $7,500 Tax Credit Goes Poof, but Buyers May Benefit To offset the phase-out of a federal tax credit, Tesla cut the price of its cars by $2,000—which might be better for some buyers. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-tax-credit-price-cut/

January 2, 2019 | Author: Rebecca HeilweilRebecca Heilweil The Tricky Business of Making Ride-Hail Work for Kids The outfits vying to be the “Uber for kids” must build viable businesses that assuage all sorts of concerns about kids in cars. https://www.wired.com/story/ride-hail-sharing-kids-hopskipdrive-zum-kango/

December 30, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall 2018 Was the Year of the Scooter. What Happens Now? After the mania comes the grind. https://www.wired.com/story/2018-year-of-the-scooter-what-happens-2019/

December 29, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The Heir to the V-22 Osprey Flies Through a Year of Testing Bell’s V-280 Valor tiltrotor, bidding to replace the Army’s Black Hawk helicopter, has spent the past 12 months bagging a series of milestones. https://www.wired.com/story/bell-valor-v280-testing-flight/

December 28, 2018 | Author: Andrea ValdezAndrea Valdez The Most-Read WIRED Transportation Stories of 2018 This year, our readers remained obsessed with self-driving and electric cars—and one of the most famous men making them. https://www.wired.com/gallery/most-read-transportation-stories-2018/

December 27, 2018 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton Rotating Detonation Engines Could Propel Hypersonic Flight It runs on an endless shockwave, but, sadly, it’s still in the prototype stage. https://www.wired.com/story/rotating-detonation-engine/

December 26, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Farewell, Chevy Volt: An Oral History of the Plug-In Hybrid The dealers didn’t get it, neither did most of the public. But people who loved them, really loved them. https://www.wired.com/story/chevy-volt-obituary-oral-history/

December 25, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Don’t Ask When Self-Driving Cars Will Arrive—Ask Where Autonomous vehicles are already on the road. Whether they’re “here” depends on where you are. https://www.wired.com/story/when-self-driving-cars-will-arrive-where/

December 24, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Forget Elon Musk’s Troubles—Tesla Had a Blockbuster 2018 Look past the CEO’s antics, and it’s clear the automaker spent the year clearing major, long-standing hurdles. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-elon-musk-very-good-year-model-3/

December 23, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Robocars, Elon, and More This Year in the Future of Cars 2018’s biggest transportation stories include mathematicians willing to chat airplane peeing, clock-watching RAF pilots, and, of course, Mr. Musk. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-scooters-ride-hail-roundup-2018/

December 23, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Smash Barriers to Bike-Sharing With Closca’s Telescoping Helmet The helmet that collapses to half its size is easy to stash in a backpack—and have ready for any way and time you ride. https://www.wired.com/story/closca-collapsible-helmet/

December 22, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Super-Fast Airport Scanners Are Coming—Eventually They’ll use AI and millimeter wave technology to speed you through the lines and even monitor crowds from afar. https://www.wired.com/story/super-fast-airport-scanners/

December 21, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies City Driving Is Silly Fun in Arcimoto’s Electric 3-Wheeler The battery-powered FUV may not revolutionize how we get around, but it could make life on the road a lot more enjoyable. https://www.wired.com/story/arcimoto-fuv-three-wheeler-electric/

December 20, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Startup Is Challenging Google Maps—and It Needs You The mapping company StreetCred wants to pay a volunteer mapping army in cryptocurrency to carry out its data missions. https://www.wired.com/story/streetcred-mapping-cryptocurrency-needs-you/

December 20, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall After a Deadly Crash, Uber Returns Robocars to the Road Nine months after an Uber self-driving car killed a woman in Arizona, the company resumes testing in Pittsburgh. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-returns-self-driving-after-deadly-crash/

December 19, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams With the E-tron, Audi Shows What an Electric SUV Can Be The new battery-powered luxury ride is capable, comfy, and clever. https://www.wired.com/story/audi-etron-review/

December 19, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Elon Musk Unveils the Boring Company’s Car-Flinging Tunnel The Tesla and SpaceX CEO showed off the details of his latest scheme to slay traffic. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-boring-company-car-flinging-tunnel/

December 18, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Self-Driving’s Outcast Returns With a Robotruck Scheme Anthony Levandowski launches Pronto AI and sends his robot on a cross-country trip to prove its skills. https://www.wired.com/story/anthony-levandowsk-pronto-self-driving-truck/

December 18, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Lamborghini’s Urus Makes the Supercar SUV Look Good Oh, and it can whoop the Lamborghini Gallardo on the track. https://www.wired.com/story/lamborghini-urus-suv/

December 18, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies VW’s Robo-Cars Get a Boost From Luminar’s Lidar VW’s self-driving division Audi AID picked Luminar’s system from a crowded field, impressed by its range and resolution. https://www.wired.com/story/vw-audi-aid-luminar-lidar-self-driving/

December 17, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Toyota Hits the Water With an Investment in Robo-Ships The automaker’s AI and robotics-focused investment arm is funding Sea Machines Robotics, which could make life on the water safer and more efficient. https://www.wired.com/story/toyota-sea-machines-autonomous-boats/

December 16, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Inside Elon Musk’s Production Hell and More This Week in Cars We go deep into the Tesla CEO’s very difficult past few years, hop aboard a self-driving truck, ogle Aston Martin’s hypercar, and more. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-tesla-aston-martin-valkyrie/

December 15, 2018 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton Why Forgetting a Donor Heart on a Southwest Flight Was NBD Transplant organs require precise logistics to get from one body to another, but this was an unusual case. https://www.wired.com/story/southwest-flight-donor-heart/

December 15, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Maddening Struggle to Make Robo-Cars Safe—and Prove It Startup Zoox is just one of many self-driving developers looking for the best way to address the complex issue of safety. https://www.wired.com/story/zoox-self-driving-cars-safety/

December 13, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart As Virgin Galactic Reaches Space, Pilots Become Astronauts Richard Branson’s extra-planetary effort takes a giant leap toward realizing its dream of making space tourism a reality. https://www.wired.com/story/virgin-galactic-space-vss-unity-flight/

December 13, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Aston Martin’s $3M Valkyrie Gets an Engine Born of F1 Tech The forthcoming hypercar will draw more than 1,000 horsepower from a V12 made with help from Formula 1 engineers. https://www.wired.com/story/aston-martin-valkyrie-engine-v12-f1-cosworth/

December 13, 2018 | Author: Charles DuhiggCharles Duhigg Dr. Elon & Mr. Musk: Life Inside Tesla’s Production Hell Unfettered genius. Unpredictable rages. Here’s what it was like to work at Tesla as Model 3 manufacturing ramped up and the company’s leader melted down. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-tesla-life-inside-gigafactory/

December 13, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The WIRED Guide to Self-Driving Cars How a chaotic skunkworks race in the desert launched what’s poised to be a runaway global industry. https://www.wired.com/story/guide-self-driving-cars/

December 12, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall How Robocars Handle the Frustratingly Human Act of Merging For tech that can struggle to understand how humans drive, the communication-heavy, high-speed highway merge is no easy thing. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-cars-merging-highways/

December 11, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Burger King’s 1-Cent Whopper Offers a Taste of the Robocar Future With the spread of self-driving technology, gimmicks like the Whopper Detour will become much more pervasive—and a little bit creepy. https://www.wired.com/story/burger-king-whopper-detour-mcdonalds-self-driving-car-advertising/

December 11, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Cake’s Electric Motorcycle Makes Dirt Biking a Silent Joy Want to get a rookie into off-roading? Let them ride the $13,000, all-electric Kalk motorcycle. https://www.wired.com/story/cake-kalk-electric-motorcycle/

December 10, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Even Elon Musk Abuses Tesla’s Autopilot Musk’s ‘60 Minutes’ interview risks making the public even more confused about how to safely use the semi-autonomous system. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-tesla-autopilot-60-minutes-interview/

December 10, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies This Robotruck’s Cameras See Twice as Far as Any Lidar TuSimple’s computer-vision-wielding truck drives like a champion—until a system freeze cuts a test-drive short. https://www.wired.com/story/tusimple-self-driving-truck-cameras-computer-vision/

December 9, 2018 | None Waymo’s Self-Driving Launch, and More This Week in Cars But the announcement came with serious caveats. Plus: Tesla’s Autopilot, May Mobility, and scooters. https://www.wired.com/story/waymo-self-driving-this-week-cars/

December 8, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall 32 Hours in Chandler, Arizona, the Self-Driving Capital of the World As Waymo launches its robocar service, we hit the ground to see how the Phoenix suburb is handling the new tech. https://www.wired.com/story/32-hours-chandler-arizona-self-driving-capital/

December 7, 2018 | Author: Levi Tillemann , Lassor FeasleyLevi Tillemann and Lassor Feasley Let’s Count the Ways E-Scooters Could Save the City The vehicles made by Bird, Lime, and the like can slash emissions, reinvigorate mass transit, and address America’s dependency on cars. https://www.wired.com/story/e-scooter-micromobility-infographics-cost-emissions/

December 6, 2018 | Author: DL ByronDL Byron UPS Tries Delivery Tricycles As Seattle’s Traffic Doom Looms More than a century after it started delivering telegrams by bike, UPS is going back to pedal power in its hometown. https://www.wired.com/story/ups-delivery-tricycle-seattle/

December 5, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Congress Races to Pass a Self-Driving Car Law By Year’s End With robo-cars on the road and a new Congress coming in, legislators are trying to finally finish up the AV Start Act. https://www.wired.com/story/av-start-act-senate-congress-new-language-self-driving/

December 5, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Waymo’s So-Called Robo-Taxi Launch Reveals a Brutal Truth The outfit that started as Google’s self-driving car team still relies on human safety operators—indicating just how hard this problem really is. https://www.wired.com/story/waymo-self-driving-taxi-service-launch-chandler-arizona/

December 4, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A Not-So-Sexy Plan to Win at Self-Driving Cars May Mobility’s path to success hinges on using robo-cars in simple scenarios, where they can work well and bring in revenue. https://www.wired.com/story/may-mobility-win-self-driving-cars/

December 3, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies A Sleeping Tesla Driver Highlights Autopilot’s Biggest Flaw California Highway Patrol officers used a clever trick to stop a Tesla going 70 mph with a sleeping man at the wheel. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-sleeping-driver-dui-arrest-autopilot/

December 3, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Porsche Wants You to Use Maps for Exploration—Not Navigation The automaker is teaming up with Mapbox to make in-car maps more than tools for getting from one place to another as efficiently as possible. https://www.wired.com/story/porsche-mapbox-navigation-exploration-collaboration/

December 2, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Jeep Revives the Pickup and More This Week in the Future of Cars Americans love their trucks, and the auto industry answered this week with the Jeep Gladiator, Range Rover Evoque, Rivian’s electric pickup, and more. https://www.wired.com/story/jeep-gladiator-rivian-pickup-porsche-911-roundup/

November 30, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies GM’s President Is Leaving Detroit to Run Its Robo-Car Biz Dan Ammann is leaving his role in Detroit to become the CEO of Cruise, which is preparing to launch a commercial robo-car service next year. https://www.wired.com/story/gm-dan-ammann-cruise-self-driving-cars-ceo/

November 30, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Putting Airbags Outside the Car Could Make Crashes Way Safer Auto supplier ZF’s “external side airbag” would deploy moments before impact, in a bid to better protect the car’s passengers. https://www.wired.com/story/zf-external-side-airbag-crash/

November 29, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Lyft Bets Big on Bikes in NYC, and Uber Is None Too Happy Now the owner of the continent’s largest bike-share company, Lyft is growing its footprint in NYC’s outer boroughs—upsetting Uber and Lime. https://www.wired.com/story/lyft-bets-bikes-nyc/

November 28, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Locals Kill One of Elon Musk’s Plans for a Tunnel Under LA Musk’s Boring Company has dropped plans to dig under the city’s west side after neighborhood groups sued to stop the project. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-boring-company-sepulveda-tunnel/

November 28, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Audi’s E-tron GT Brings Battery Power to a Speedy, Svelte Sedan The automaker’s electric charge builds on the E-tron SUV with the E-tron GT, a four-door that will do 0 to 60 mph in 3.5 seconds. https://www.wired.com/story/audi-etron-gt-sedan-specs-photos/

November 28, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Porsche’s New 911 Listens to the Road to Weather the Wet The new 992 continues the evolution of the famed model with refined design, pepped up performance, and a neat trick for detecting slippery conditions. https://www.wired.com/story/porsche-911-992-specs-price/

November 28, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The All-New Gladiator Is Jeep’s Old-School Nod to Pickups Americans love pickup trucks, and Jeep is happy to cater to their wishes. https://www.wired.com/story/jeep-gladiator-pickup-truck/

November 27, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall GM’s Job Cuts Are Another Sign of a Future With Fewer Cars Preparing for a new sort of future, the automaker is cutting 14,000 jobs, closing three plants, and killing a bunch of car models. https://www.wired.com/story/gm-job-cuts-plant-closings-future-cars/

November 27, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Range Rover’s New Evoque Is Made to Conquer the Parking Lot With an “invisible” hood, the new generation of the cute ute can handle an off-road paradise—or the parking lot they paved over it. https://www.wired.com/story/range-rover-evoque-suv-2020/

November 26, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall If You Hate Traffic, Curb Your Love for Online Shopping The ecommerce boom is nice for convenience but not for efficiency. Fortunately, there are ways to fix that. https://www.wired.com/story/online-shopping-traffic-delivery-efficiency/

November 26, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Bentley’s Tweedy New Convertible Has a Secret Spinning Door The new Continental GT Convertible has a roof that’ll go great with your hunting jacket, along with excessive engineering and swank interiors. https://www.wired.com/story/bentley-continental-gt-convertible-tweed-roof/

November 26, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Rivian Wants to Do for Pickups What Tesla Did for Cars RJ Scaringe’s Rivian Automotive just unveiled its electric pickup truck, and it’s looking good. https://www.wired.com/story/rivian-wants-to-do-for-pickups-what-tesla-did-for-cars/

November 24, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Drop the Batteries—Diamonds and Lasers Could Power Your Drone Rather than have drones waste energy carrying their own power, LakeDiamond wants to charge them by firing lasers through diamonds at their solar cells. https://www.wired.com/story/drones-batteries-lasers-diamonds-lakediamond/

November 21, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Airport Wi-Fi Is Safe, Plus Travel Scoops You May Have Missed On this greatest of travel days, we’re reviewing our favorite here-to-there stories, from airport face scans to holiday traffic jams. https://www.wired.com/story/travel-stories-advice-thanksgiving-roundup/

November 21, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Creepy or Not, Face Scans Are Speeding up Airport Security Who cares if you hate it? This time- and effort-saving tech is spreading, and fast. https://www.wired.com/story/airport-security-biometrics-face-scanning/

November 20, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Daring Art of a Helicopter Wildfire Rescue Two chopper pilots pulled off a daring rescue from the Woolsey Fire, plucking three people and two dogs off a ridge in hideous flying conditions. https://www.wired.com/story/woolsey-fire-helicopter-rescue-video/

November 20, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Stop Worrying About Buying Carbon Offsets for Your Flights Many airlines must offset increased emissions to meet a UN agreement, so they’re done relying on individuals, which is likely more effective anyway. https://www.wired.com/story/airline-emissions-carbon-offsets-travel/

November 20, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Airports Cracked Uber and Lyft—Time for Cities to Take Note Airports serve as handy case studies for what happens when the cars show up, and how to beat them back again. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-lyft-ride-hail-airport-traffic-cities/

November 18, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart This Week in the Future of Cars: Women Pay More for Transit Tesla, GM, and Nissan want to restore the fading tax credit for EVs; Waymo is almost ready to go; the Mustang gets electrified; and more car news. https://www.wired.com/story/future-of-cars-pink-tax/

November 15, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The ‘Baby Boom’ Charts a Return to Supersonic Flight Before Colorado-based plane maker Boom Supersonic can launch its airliner, it has to see its 1/3-scale starter plane take off. https://www.wired.com/story/boom-aerospace-baby-boom-demonstrator-supersonic/

November 14, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Uber Rewards Loyalty Program Gives Perks to Power Users Rack up enough points and a real life human will answer your customer support call. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-rewards-loyalty-program/

November 14, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla, GM, and Nissan Unite to Save Their EV Tax Credits The EV Drive Coalition will push Congress to extend the $7,500 federal tax credit for electric cars, but advocates say it could do much more. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-gm-nissan-ev-drive-coalition-federal-tax-credit/

November 13, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart A Startup Is Setting Drones Free by Tying Them to the Ground A tether connecting a drone to the ground liberates the aircraft from reliance on short-lived batteries, allowing it to stay aloft for weeks at a time. https://www.wired.com/story/startup-setting-drones-free-tying-them-to-the-ground/

November 12, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies How to Land a ‘Completely Uncontrollable’ Passenger Jet When the pilots of Air Astana Flight 1388 lost control of their Embraer 190, they spent a scary two hours in the air over Portugal before making it down safely. https://www.wired.com/story/air-astana-flight-1388-portugal-loss-control/

November 12, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Pink Transit Tax: Women Spend More Than Men to Get Around NYC The burden falls especially heavily on people who take care of children—nearly all of whom are women. https://www.wired.com/story/nyc-public-transportation-pink-tax-gender-gap/

November 11, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla’s Booming Model 3 Sales and More This Week in the Future of Cars Elon Musk puts Tesla in the black, cities rein in scooters, and a car engineer spends a lot of time throwing up. https://www.wired.com/story/car-news-roundup-tesla-model-3-sales/

November 10, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Land Rover Bets a Vomit-y Teacups Ride Could Cure Car Sickness Jaguar Land Rover is investigating how to detect and curtain motion sickness, and that meant emptying an engineer’s stomach a few times. https://www.wired.com/story/jaguar-land-rover-car-sickness-study/

November 9, 2018 | Author: WIRED StaffWIRED Staff How a Real Life Iron Man Built His Own Jetpack Flying Suit Richard Browning endured more than a few crashes—and broke some concrete—on the way to designing the jetpack suit he’s now using to launch a racing league. https://www.wired.com/story/richard-browning-iron-man-jetpack-suit-flying-video/

November 8, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Virgin Hyperloop One’s New CEO Could Make a Wooshy Future Real The former head of New York, London, and Hong Kong transit signs on with the hyperloop company. https://www.wired.com/story/new-virgin-hyperloop-one-ceo-jay-walder/

November 8, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies How Do Self-Driving Cars See? (And How Do They See Me)? From Lidar to cameras to radar, self-driving cars use several technologies to create their maps of the world, and (hopefully) not run over humans. https://www.wired.com/story/the-know-it-alls-how-do-self-driving-cars-see/

November 8, 2018 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton The Clever Tech Keeping America’s (Many) Disabled Farmers on the Job One in five American farmers has some sort of disability, and they rely on a cornucopia of tools to keep putting food on everyone’s table. https://www.wired.com/story/farmer-disabilities-tools-agrability-breaking-new-ground/

November 7, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Boeing Issues Safety Warning After a Fatal 737 MAX Nosedive The plane builder wants pilots to brush up on what to do if a faulty sensor sends a 737 MAX into a dive. https://www.wired.com/story/boeing-safety-warning-737-max-nosedive/

November 7, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Booming Model 3 Sales Are Moving Tesla Beyond its Niche Tesla is not just playing on the same field as the established automakers and their gas-powered cars and trucks. It’s beating many of them. https://www.wired.com/story/booming-model-3-sales-moving-tesla-beyond-niche/

November 6, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall How to Derail a Runaway Train (and Save Australia) After a 268-car, four-locomotive Australian train traveled 57 miles with no one at the controls, it’s good to review. https://www.wired.com/story/australia-runaway-train-derailment/

November 6, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Audi’s A8 Sedan Rolls With the Punches to Make T-Bone Crashes Safer The $84,000 luxury sedan can sense an impending crash and adjust its suspension to protect its occupants in under a second. https://www.wired.com/story/audi-a8-active-safety-features/

November 6, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Milking Scooters for Cash Helps Cities Build for the Future Cities are experimenting with fees for scooter companies desperate to leave their electric mobiles on their sidewalks. And that money could help them keep up with the evolving world of mobility. https://www.wired.com/story/scooters-cities-fees-mobility/

November 5, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Want to Make an All-Star Electric Truck? Drop the Driver Einride, the startup now running a small robo-trucking service in Sweden, says that self-driving tech is a key enabler for electric propulsion. https://www.wired.com/story/einride-self-driving-electric-truck-sweden/

November 5, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Luxuriate in This Mechanic’s Teardown of a 1974 Harley Davidson The premier episode of WIRED’s [De]Constructed takes a gleaming looking into the guts of a vintage Harley Davidson Shovelhead. https://www.wired.com/story/harley-davidson-motorcycle-deconstructed-video/

November 4, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Waymo Drops the Driver, Plus More This Week in the Future of Cars California lets self-driving cars go fully robo, Tesla upgrades Autopilot, Chevy makes an electric Camaro, and more. https://www.wired.com/story/waymo-self-driving-california-tesla-autopilot-roundup/

November 4, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla’s Autopilot Now Changes Lanes—And You’re Gonna Help It Out The newly released “Navigate on Autopilot” makes choices about when to change lanes, but depends on the human’s help—help that will make the system better in the long run. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-navigate-on-autopilot/

November 3, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Intricate Maps Reveal What US Public Transit Gets Wrong—and Right One obsessive planner, a bunch of data, and a lot of mapping flair makes for a stirring guide to US transport. https://www.wired.com/story/intricate-maps-us-public-transit-gets-wrong-right/

November 2, 2018 | Author: Ashley NunesAshley Nunes Robotaxis Are Coming. So Why Are We Still So Unprepared? Opinion: We worry about glitchy driverless tech, but we should be worried about the remote human minders. https://www.wired.com/story/robotaxis-are-coming/

November 1, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Learn to Fly Sikorsky’s New Helicopter in Just 45 Minutes The tablet- and joystick-controlled chopper is part of an effort minimize—and maybe someday eliminate—the role of the human pilot. https://www.wired.com/story/sikorsky-helicopter-darpa-alias/

November 1, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Uber Just Made It Easier to Chow Down on Your Company’s Dime Integrating Uber Eats into Uber for Business locks ever more customers into the ride-hailing company’s ecosystem in advance of an IPO. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-eats-for-business/

October 30, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies A Florida Man Is Suing Tesla for a Scary Autopilot Crash The latest lawsuit over Elon Musk’s semi-autonomous driving feature claims Tesla sales reps oversold the system’s capabilities. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-autopilot-crash-lawsuit-florida-shawn-hudson/

October 30, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Waymo Can Finally Bring Truly Driverless Cars to California The company born as Google’s self-driving car project is the first with the right to test human-free cars on public roads in the Golden State. https://www.wired.com/story/waymo-self-driving-cars-california/

October 30, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Chevy’s Making an Electric Camaro to Dominate the Drag Strip Buy into the heresy of the eCOPO Camaro and you get more than 700 horsepower, 600 pound-feet of torque, and a quarter-mile time in the 9-second range. https://www.wired.com/story/chevys-electric-camaro-to-dominate-the-drag-strip/

October 30, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall (Pseudo) Scientific Strategies for Trick-or-Treating Like a Beast You want all the Halloween candy. A bit of data crunching will help you get it. https://www.wired.com/story/halloween-trick-treating-candy-optimization-strategies/

October 29, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall We’ve Been Talking About Self-Driving Car Safety All Wrong Forget miles driven and disengagements. It’s time for a new framework. We just need to figure out what that looks like. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-cars-safety-metrics-miles-disengagements/

October 28, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Unintended Consequences Tesla gets profitable, an ode to the dinky EV, the high cost of fixing an extra-safe car, and more. https://www.wired.com/story/car-news-roundup-tesla-profitable-dinky-evs-ode/

October 27, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart You Will Now Spend Hours Watching Mesmerizing Engine Rebuild Time-Lapses Hagerty’s Redline Rebuilds series is a testament to the intricacies of the internal combustion engine in an age where simpler electrics are en route to dominance. https://www.wired.com/story/hagerty-engine-rebuild-videos/

October 26, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Step Inside the Air Force’s Sound-Swallowing Anechoic Chamber The 30-foot cube is at the center of the Air Force Research Laboratory’s effort to help soldiers, sailors, and air crews focus on what matters, when it matters. https://www.wired.com/story/air-force-anechoic-chamber-acoustic-study/

October 26, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart ‘Invisible’ Car Pillars Nix the Trade-off Between Safety and Visibility Thick pillars are good in crashes but bad for a driver’s line of sight. Continental wants to make them disappear. https://www.wired.com/story/continental-invisible-a-pillar/

October 25, 2018 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton To Fix the Ills of Tourism, Think Like a Traffic Engineer Exploding global tourism is becoming a mess, and the way to fix it involves thinking about people like cars. https://www.wired.com/story/tourism-crowds-solutions-traffic-engineering/

October 25, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Cars With Active Safety Features Can Be Crazy Expensive to Fix A new report from AAA finds that when cars with active safety features do crash, they can cost thousands of dollars to fix. https://www.wired.com/story/active-safety-features-repair-fix-costs-aaa-report/

October 24, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla Finally Turns a Profit, and Promises to Keep Doing It Elon Musk’s electric car company is pulling out of Model 3 production hell, and starting to make money. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-finally-made-profit-promises-to-keep-doing/

October 24, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall What Can the Trolley Problem Teach Self-Driving Car Engineers? New research finds Nicaraguans and Hondurans are less likely to choose to crash into fit people, and those from Japan or Indonesia would rather spare the lawful. But developers say the moral quandary just isn’t very helpful. https://www.wired.com/story/trolley-problem-teach-self-driving-car-engineers/

October 23, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies What It’s Like to Fly the WWII-Era Plane That Just Crashed on LA’s 101 Freeway Wondering why someone was flying the decades-old T-6 Texan that crash landed in Agoura Hills? Simply put, it’s a blast. https://www.wired.com/story/wwii-plane-crash-la-freeway-101-agoura-hills/

October 23, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart It’s Time You Fell in Love With a Small, Cheap, Electric Car You don’t have to spend six figures—or even buy a shiny new car—to have a lot of fun with a battery. https://www.wired.com/story/ode-to-the-dinky-electric-car/

October 22, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies A Turkish Airlines Jet Flew 800 Miles Out of Its Way—and Landed on Time Turkish Airlines Flight 800 went over Greenland on its way from Panama City to Istanbul, a testament to the power of the jet stream. https://www.wired.com/story/turkish-airlines-flight-800-panama-city-istanbul/

October 21, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies This Week in the Future of Cars: Let’s Start All Over Again Tesla makes yet another non-$35K Model 3, battery swapping somehow comes back, yet more evidence ‘semi-autonomous’ driving is confusing people, and more car news. https://www.wired.com/story/cars-roundup-new-model-3-lime-new-scooter/

October 20, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Skip Scooters Get a Latch So They Don’t Junk up the Sidewalks It’s an engineering fix designed to make the vehicles more attractive to officials and regulators. https://www.wired.com/story/skip-scooters-latch-dont-junk-up-sidewalk/

October 19, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla’s New ‘Mid-Range’ Model 3 Is the iPhone XR of Cars Elon Musk’s unexpected version of the Model 3 will offer 260 miles of range for around $45,000, and carves out a new niche in an expanding product line. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-mid-range-model-3-apple-iphone-xr/

October 19, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Drive.ai Brings Its Self-Driving Cars to Dallas Cowboy Fans The startup is launching a service that will cart the public around Arlington, Texas, including to and from AT&T Stadium. https://www.wired.com/story/driveai-self-driving-cars-arlington-texas-cowboys-dallas/

October 19, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Lime’s New Scooter Is Hardier, Heavier, and Built for Life on the Streets More range, more robust, more stable, more waterproof. Lime thinks its “Gen 3” scooter is ready to take on the worst the world can do to it. https://www.wired.com/story/lime-scooter-gen3-design/

October 18, 2018 | Author: Levi Tillemann , Colin McCormickLevi Tillemann and Colin McCormick The Faster, Cheaper, Better Way to Charge Electric Vehicles Opinion: Forget fast-charging. Battery swapping is back—and it’s the tech of the future. https://www.wired.com/story/the-faster-cheaper-better-way-to-charge-electric-vehicles/

October 18, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Drivers Wildly Overestimate What ‘Semiautonomous’ Cars Can Do Seventy percent of people believe you can buy an autonomous car today. And that’s a problem. https://www.wired.com/story/semi-autonomous-systems-safety-research-euro-ncap-thatcham/

October 18, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Why People Keep Rear-Ending Self-Driving Cars Human drivers (and one cyclist) have rear-ended self-driving cars 28 times this year in California—accounting for nearly two-thirds of robocar crashes. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-car-crashes-rear-endings-why-charts-statistics/

October 16, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Audi Brings Drift-Happy Driving Dynamics to All-Electric SUV German automaker takes advantage of its all-electric powertrain to make the E-tron a delightfully drifty luxury vehicle. https://www.wired.com/story/audi-etron-electric-suv-driving-review/

October 16, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber and Lyft Made Traffic Worse in San Francisco. But It’s Complicated A new report concludes that Uber and Lyft were responsible for 51 percent of the daily vehicle delay hours in the city between 2010 and 2016, but there are a few big caveats. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-lyft-san-francisco-traffic-report/

October 15, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Don’t Worry! The Future Is Going to Be Fine Kitty Hawk CEO Sebastian Thrun and Y Combinator president Sam Altman are bullish on nuclear fusion, flying cars, and AI. https://www.wired.com/story/wired25-sebastian-thrun-sam-altman/

October 15, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Rolls-Royce Wants to Fill the Seas With Self-Sailing Ships The vision starts with helping humans stay safe at sea, but could put fully robo-boats into action as ferries in just a few years. https://www.wired.com/story/rolls-royce-autonomous-ship/

October 14, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Happy Birthday to Us We look at the latest happenings in the auto-world, and look back at WIRED’s greatest hits from a quarter century of chronicling the ever-molting world of transportation. https://www.wired.com/story/future-cars-wired-25-transportation-stories/

October 11, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Hurricane Michael Hit the Parts of Florida Least Prepared to Flee Its Wrath What’s really scary is that as climate change brings fiercer storms, more places must learn to prepare for disaster. https://www.wired.com/story/hurricane-michael-florida-evacuation-plans/

October 11, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies A Drone-Flinging Cannon Proves UAVs Can Mangle Planes Researchers armed with a very fun kind of cannon have shown that drones have potential to do serious damage to aircraft. https://www.wired.com/story/drone-plane-collision-damage-study/

October 11, 2018 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton So, Self-Driving Cars Could Make Humans Unhealthier Than Ever A widespread shift to autonomous vehicles could weaken America’s already slipping stance in a two-front war against pollution and sedentary behavior, which are tightly linked to cancer and heart disease. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-cars-obesity-pollution-public-health/

October 10, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Hankook’s New Tire Uses Tree Resin to Keep Electric Cars Rolling The Kinergy AS EV tire uses a substance called “Aqua Pine” to improve performance, and is designed to limit noise and improve efficiency. https://www.wired.com/story/hankook-ev-electric-car-kinergy-tire/

October 7, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Go Your Own Way Elon Musk doesn’t back down, Honda and GM hook up for self-driving cars, a truck company comes out of stealth, and more car news from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/this-week-future-cars-go-your-own-way/

October 6, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Cars of the Paris Auto Show Reveal a Quirky, Urban, Electric Future From Toyota’s “self-charging hybrids” to Citroën’s new runabout, Paris offers a glimpse of the automotive future in that parallel universe we call “Europe.” https://www.wired.com/story/quirky-electric-city-cars-ruled-the-paris-auto-show/

October 6, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart What Are Shorts and Why Does Elon Hate Them? Because their actions drive down the value of Tesla’s stock. https://www.wired.com/story/what-are-short-sellers-and-why-does-elon-hate-them/

October 6, 2018 | Author: Jim ResnickJim Resnick Want to Drive Like a Pro Racer? Hope You Like Numbers We hit the track to find out how much information goes into today’s race cars—and whether it could improve our skills through the turns. https://www.wired.com/story/auto-racing-data-logging/

October 6, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber Writes an Equation to Help Cities Measure—and Manage—the Curb In the age of ride-hailing and scooters, this strip of urban space is a hot commodity. Now cities have a way to measure just how hot. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-city-equation-curb/

October 4, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla’s Autopilot Report Makes Big Safety Claims With Little Context Tesla’s report finds drivers using Autopilot crash nearly seven times less often than the general population, but safety experts aren’t convinced. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-autopilot-safety-report-statistics/

October 4, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The DOT Says ‘Drivers’ Don’t Have to Be Human And that’s really great news for the humans developing self-driving trucks. https://www.wired.com/story/dot-says-drivers-dont-have-to-be-human/

October 4, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall California Says ‘Nope’ to the EPA’s Car Emissions Rules The state’s Air Resources Board passes new measures that double down on its stringent vehicle emissions rules—and maintain its collision course with the Trump administration. https://www.wired.com/story/california-nope-epa-car-emissions/

October 4, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart A Helicopter Engine Cuts This Hybrid Plane’s Fuel Use in Half Zunum Aero is using a modified helicopter engine to generate power, supplementing the batteries packed in its fuselage. https://www.wired.com/story/zunum-aero-hybrid-plane-safran-engine/

October 3, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Honda’s Helping GM on Its Quest to Deliver Self-Driving Cars The Japanese automaker will help develop a new design for a self-driving vehicle, and pitch in $2.75 billion. https://www.wired.com/story/honda-gm-cruise-self-driving-cars/

October 2, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla Made a Lot of Cars in Q3. But It Needs to Make More Tesla built a record 53,239 Model 3 electric sedans—but the coming months will really test the automaker as it aims for stability and expansion into China. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-q3-production-numbers/

October 2, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A Self-Driving Truck Startup Keeps It Simple, Stupid Ike, just out of stealth, is licensing its software stack from the automated delivery robot company Nuro. https://www.wired.com/story/ike-self-driving-truck-startup-nuro-software-deal/

October 2, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Now 5 Years Old, the Hyperloop Industry Keeps on Whooshing On The oldest hyperloop company is five years old, and we still don’t have hyperloop—but these loop dreamers aren’t giving up. https://www.wired.com/story/hyperloop-transportation-technologies-capsule-quintero-one/

October 1, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Ex-Apple Engineers Build a Speed-Spotting Lidar for Self-Driving Cars The young startup Aeva has $45 million in funding and a sensor it says can give self-driving cars a whole new view of the world. https://www.wired.com/story/aeva-lidar-self-driving-sensor-apple/

September 30, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Elon Musk, Modern-Day Houdini? Elon settles with the SEC. Plus, a secret cabal of flying car advocates, and more car news from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/this-week-future-cars-elon-musk-modern-day-houdini/

September 29, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Elon Musk’s SEC Settlement Could Have Gone So Much Worse Musk loses some control over the electric carmaker—and his Twitter account. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musks-sec-settlement-could-have-gone-so-much-worse/

September 29, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Channel Your Inner Fred Flintstone in This Pedal-Powered Car Yes, someone created a car with bike pedals where the normal pedals should be. https://www.wired.com/story/channel-fred-flintstone-peddle-powered-car/

September 28, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Elon Musk Has Finally Picked a Fight He Can’t Win The Tesla CEO’s decision to refuse an SEC settlement sets him up for battle against the government, and shareholders aren’t happy. https://www.wired.com/story/investors-mad-at-elon-musk/

September 27, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The SEC Is Suing Elon Musk (It’s the Tweets) The Tesla CEO is being charged with “making false and misleading statements.” https://www.wired.com/story/sec-is-suing-elon-musk/

September 27, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Inside the Secret Conference Plotting to Launch Flying Cars Over two days in Bentonville, Arkansas, the new aerial mobility nobility gathered away from the public eye to craft strategies for launching the next age of aviation. https://www.wired.com/story/inside-secret-conference-plotting-flying-cars/

September 27, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Lyft Will Pay You to Ditch Your Car. Will It Work? The company’s new challenge is a PR stunt. It’s also a useful way to learn about the quirks of user behavior. https://www.wired.com/story/lyft-will-pay-ditch-your-car-will-it-work/

September 27, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart A Better Motor Is the First Step Towards Electric Planes Magnix is testing a new motor designed specifically for aviation, which is lighter weight, and higher power. https://www.wired.com/story/magnix-electric-plane-motor/

September 26, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies How to Build a Floating Bridge in 12 Minutes When war and natural disasters like Hurricane Florence call for a quick crossing, military engineers hop to with one of their favorite tools—the improved ribbon bridge. https://www.wired.com/story/improved-ribbon-floating-bridge-calfire-florence-flooding/

September 23, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Electric Start Meet the all-electric Audi E-tron SUV; the Porsche Taycan’s speedy charging setup; a pair of Ferrari Monzas; and more car news from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/this-week-future-cars-electric-start/

September 22, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Stubborn Bike Commuter Gap Between American Cities Fewer Americans are biking to work, new data show, but some cities are seeing much more progress than others. https://www.wired.com/story/cycling-census-commuter-data-gap/

September 21, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Model 3 Crash Testing Hammers Home Tesla’s Safety Excellence Apart from a few hiccups and questions about Autopilot, Elon Musk’s automaker knows how to make very safe cars. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-model-3-crash-testing-safety-rating/

September 21, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Germany’s Self-Driving Streetcar Puts Autonomous Tech on Track Siemens is developing autonomous tech with transit vehicles on tracks, making the self-driving challenge simpler but still worth solving. https://www.wired.com/story/siemens-potsdam-self-driving-street-car-tram/

September 20, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Porsche’s Sleek Chargers Will Power up EVs in Just 15 Minutes The German automaker’s “electric pit stops” promise to put 250 miles of range on the Taycan’s batteries nearly three times faster than a Tesla Supercharger. https://www.wired.com/story/porsche-taycan-fast-chargers-electric-pit-stops/

September 19, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Ferrari’s Monza Cars Mix Its Most Powerful Engine With 1950s Cool The first cars in the “Icona” line offer 800 horsepower and looks borrowed from Ferrari’s post-war racers. https://www.wired.com/story/ferrari-monza-sp1-sp2-inona-cars/

September 18, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A DOJ Probe Into Elon’s Tweets Could Spell Yet More Trouble for Tesla The reported criminal probe is likely in its early stages, but darkens an already gloomy sky gathering over Elon Musk’s automaker. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-elon-musk-doj-investigation/

September 18, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart How Audi’s New E-tron Stacks Up to Its Electric Competitors, Spec by Spec From kilowatt-hours to horsepower to acceleration times, see how the E-ron SUV compares to similar offerings from Tesla, Mercedes-Benz, Jaguar, and others. https://www.wired.com/story/audi-etron-specs-comparison-electric-cars/

September 18, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Still Smarting From Uber, Cities Wise up About Scooter Data Most cities felt powerless to extract concessions from Uber and Lyft. Now that scooters are here, they’ve learned their lesson—and toughened up. https://www.wired.com/story/cities-scooter-data-remix-uber-lyft/

September 18, 2018 | Author: Anthony LydgateAnthony Lydgate How Zipline Helps Remote Regions Get Blood From a Drone The sky delivery service scales up. https://www.wired.com/story/wired25-anne-wojcicki-keller-rinaudo-zipline-medical-drones/

September 18, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Audi at Last Unveils the E-tron, Its First All-Electric SUV Starting at $74,800 and offering 248(ish) miles of range, the E-tron is here to do battle with Tesla and every other automaker crowding into the luxury electric market. https://www.wired.com/story/audi-etron-electric-suv/

September 17, 2018 | Author: Joe LindseyJoe Lindsey The Exquisite, Intricate Insanity of Riding a Bike at 184 MPH Guts, legs of unobtanium, a friend with a drag racer, and a keen sense of aerodynamics are all key to Denise Mueller-Korenek’s mission of setting the bike land speed record. https://www.wired.com/story/denise-mueller-korenek-bike-speed-record-168-mph/

September 17, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall 5 Great Routes for Self-Driving Trucks—Whenever They’re Ready Traffic analytics company Inrix looked at freight and safety data to consider where robo-trucks could make the biggest impact. https://www.wired.com/story/inrix-self-driving-truck-routes/

September 16, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: The Coming Storm Florence forces logistically complex evacuations, Tesla fixes a security flaw, flying cars get hooked up, and more. https://www.wired.com/story/week-future-cars-coming-storm/

September 15, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies BMW’s Tech-Stuffed Concept SUV Heralds a Fancy, Electric Future The Vision iNEXT concept has everything from touch-control seats to a Little Mermaid–inspired interior—and BMW insists it’s for real. https://www.wired.com/story/bmw-vision-inext-suv-concept-new-electric-course/

September 15, 2018 | Author: Peter NortonPeter Norton Self-Driving Car Developers Should Put Pedestrians First Opinion: Contrary to the hype, walkers and bikers are much smarter than autonomous vehicles https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-car-developers-should-put-pedestrians-first/

September 14, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall When It’s Time to Evacuate, Cities Struggle to Help Those Who Can’t Drive As storms like Hurricane Florence get more serious and the US population ages, a tricky logistical problem will only become more important. https://www.wired.com/story/hurricane-evacuate-cities-cant-drive/

September 14, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams To Solve Flying Cars’ Biggest Problem, Tie Them to Power Lines To get around concerns of battery capacity and weight, Karman Electric wants flying cars to draw juice from the ground, like an inverted streetcar system. https://www.wired.com/story/karman-electric-flying-car-air-taxi-power-lines/

September 13, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Lyft’s Bid to Rule the Streets Now Includes Public Transit Starting in Santa Monica, users can now check transit routes and times in the Lyft app—part of the ride-sharing company’s strategy to move beyond cars. https://www.wired.com/story/lyft-public-transit-app-zimmer-santa-monica/

September 13, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart As Hurricane Florence Looms, Drone Pilots Prepare for Recovery Forecasts are calling for a brutal storm, so pilots are getting ready to take to the skies—and give the recovery effort a head start. https://www.wired.com/story/hurricane-florence-drone-recovery/

September 12, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Waze Lights the Beacons to Guide Drivers Through Chicago’s Tangled Streets To guide drivers through a multi-layered labyrinth where GPS doesn’t work, Waze hooked up 500 coordinate-beaming beacons. https://www.wired.com/story/chicago-waze-beacons-spothero-gps/

September 11, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall How to Move a Million People Out of a Hurricane’s Way After years of planning, officials monitoring Hurricane Florence have just a few days to get their citizens to safety. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/move-2-million-people-hurricane-matthews-way/

September 11, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart LA’s Teaming up With Other Cities to Get Cheaper EVs It’s leading a group of 18 cities that will work together to get better deals on electric cars. https://www.wired.com/story/los-angeles-electric-car-portal/

September 11, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies A Shape-Shifting Van Concept Prepares Mercedes for the Future It’s a cargo van! It’s a passenger van! It’s the Vision Urbanetic, and it’s part of Mercedes’ bid for the future of transportation. https://www.wired.com/story/mercedes-vision-urbanetic-concept-van/

September 9, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: We’ll Be Blunt About This Elon Musk is smoking something, doppler lidar helps cars see better, and the Diplomatic Security Service braves Ebola https://www.wired.com/story/future-of-cars-lets-be-blunt/

September 8, 2018 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton The 19th Century Argument for a 21st Century Space Force In an orbital world, nations must protect their satellites the way they once guarded sea lanes. https://www.wired.com/story/space-force-mahan-argument/

September 7, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Elon Musk’s Blunt-Toking Goodwill Tour Won’t Fix Tesla’s Real Problems As more high-level executives leave, investors aren’t calmed by Musk’s attempt to return to his far-out thinking self on Joe Rogan’s podcast. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-weed-toke-tesla/

September 7, 2018 | Author: Aarian Marshall, Jack StewartAarian Marshall and Jack Stewart It’ll Take Way More Than All This to Oust Elon Musk From Tesla Wild tweets, an inquisitive SEC, fights with reporters—none of it’s anywhere close to ending Musk’s control of the electric automaker. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-tesla-ceo-joe-rogan-podcast/

September 6, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall 3 Dire Visions of the Bay Area in 2070—and 1 That’s Pretty Great A new report outlines how social and economic policies could shape the future of the wealthy and unequal region. https://www.wired.com/story/spur-bay-area-2070-report-predictions/

September 6, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Chevy’s Beefy ZR2 Bison Is the Pickup Truck You Bring to Armageddon The latest performance variant of the Colorado pickup truck is clad in Boron steel, rides 31-inch tires, and will take you down any road. Or lack thereof. https://www.wired.com/story/chevy-zr2-bison-colorado-pickup-truck/

September 5, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies A New Doppler Lidar Solves Self-Driving Cars’ Need for Speed Blackmore’s lidar laser scanner detects not just where things are, but how fast they’re moving—a potentially key feature for globe-trotting robo-cars. https://www.wired.com/story/blackmore-doppler-lidar-self-driving-cars/

September 5, 2018 | Author: Aarian Marshall, Jack StewartAarian Marshall and Jack Stewart Bump-Canceling Bunk Beds Promise Supersmooth Bus Rides To make long-distance, overnight bus rides more palatable, Cabin developed an active suspension for the beds in its vehicles. https://www.wired.com/story/cabin-bus-sleep-suspension-system/

September 4, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Mercedes Challenges Tesla With an All-Electric SUV With 200 miles of range and 564 pound-feet of torque, the battery-powered EQC makes yet more competition for Elon Musk’s luxury market dominance. https://www.wired.com/story/mercedes-benz-eqc-electric-suv/

September 4, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies How Self-Driving Supergroup Aurora Plans to Make Robocars Real One of the most respected—and quietest—teams in the race for autonomy reveals its approach to a problem that’s much harder than everybody hoped. https://www.wired.com/story/aurora-self-driving-cars-plan/

September 2, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Picking Up the Pieces A Lego Bugatti Chiron, Uber’s new self-driving partner, Elon Musk’s tweets, and more car news from this week https://www.wired.com/story/this-week-future-cars-pieces/

September 1, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Riding With the Diplomatic Couriers Who Deliver America’s Secret Mail The little-known Diplomatic Courier Service works like your interoffice mail system, but on a planetary scale, with complex protocols to ensure the safe transport of classified material by land, air, and sea. https://www.wired.com/story/diplomatic-courier-service/

August 31, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams A New Ejection Seat Makes Rocketing out of a B-2 Bomber Surprisingly Safe The ACES 5 system also accommodates both lighter and heavier passengers, so the Air Force can expand its pool of potential pilots. https://www.wired.com/story/utc-aces5-ejection-seat-b2-bomber/

August 30, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Coolest Bugatti Ever Goes 18 MPH (and Is Made of Lego) Where the “real” Chiron produces 1,500 horsepower from a quad-turbocharged W16 engine and can hit 261 mph, the Lego look-alike makes 5.3 horses from 2,304 tiny motors. https://www.wired.com/story/lego-bugatti-chiron/

August 30, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall SF Is Bringing Back Banned Electric Scooters—With Limits The city granted operating permits to just Skip and Scoot, two companies that emphasized good relationships with public officials. https://www.wired.com/story/san-francisco-santa-monica-e-scooter-permits/

August 30, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Jaguar’s New Electric SUV Demands a New Kind of Car Review The I-Pace posts glorious power numbers and a jolting 0 to 60 mph time—but that’s not what separates it from its rivals. https://www.wired.com/story/jaguar-ipace-electric-suv-review/

August 29, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies A Brief History of Elon Musk’s Market-Moving Tweets Tesla stock is down following the CEO’s revival of his “pedo guy” claim—not the first time Musk’s taste for Twitter has changed how investors regard his company. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-twitter-stock-tweets-libel-suit/

August 29, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Toyota Joins Uber on Its Tortuous Journey to Self-Driving Cars With a $500 million investment, the automaker has committed to helping the ride-hailing giant deliver on robo-cars. But it’s not quite clear what that means. https://www.wired.com/story/toyota-uber-tortuous-journey-self-driving-cars/

August 28, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Want a Flying Car Future? Try Starting with Smarter Helicopters Silicon Valley startup SkyRyse thinks personal air transport will take off so hard that it isn’t waiting for advanced tech. https://www.wired.com/story/skyryse-flying-cars-helicopters/

August 28, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Keeping Tesla Public Won’t Save Elon Musk From the SEC—or Angry Investors The decision not to take his automaker private doesn’t do much to shield the CEO from a reported SEC investigation, and shareholders who say his unexpected tweet cost them money. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-tesla-private-public-sec/

August 27, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Why Tesla’s Autopilot Can’t See a Stopped Firetruck Semiautonomous driving systems are designed to ignore unmoving obstacles because otherwise, they couldn’t work at all. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-autopilot-why-crash-radar/

August 27, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Elegant Schematics Show Subway Stations Are Places, Too New York City architect Candy Chan wants city residents to think more deeply about their fascinating, complex mass transit system. https://www.wired.com/story/3d-schematics-nyc-subway-stations/

August 26, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Make It Work! Tesla’s legal hiccups, a new Bugatti supercar, a reworked Porsche 911, and more car news from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/this-week-future-cars-make-it-work/

August 25, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Audi’s Electric Concept Puts the Driver in the Center—And Everywhere Else In the PB 18 e-tron, the driver’s seat slides left and right, so when you’re not burdened with a passenger, you can sit in the middle, just like the pros. https://www.wired.com/story/audi-etron-pb-18-pebble-beach-electric-concept/

August 24, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Mercedes’ Silver Arrow Concept Packs Swanky Tech Into an Old Timey Racer Inspired by the racing cars of the 1930s, this single seater uses a big battery and augmented reality to mix modern luxury with an old-school aesthetic. https://www.wired.com/story/mercedes-benz-eq-silver-arrow-concept-pebble-beach-photos/

August 24, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Bugatti One-Ups Itself With Its New Divo Supercar The Divo is lighter, stiffer, and faster than the (already extreme) Bugatti Chiron. https://www.wired.com/story/bugatti-new-divo-supercar/

August 23, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Infiniti Prepares for a Fancy, Electric Future With a Sleek New Concept The newly unveiled Prototype 10 has just one seat, needs no fuel, and is a sign of where the cars of the future are headed. https://www.wired.com/story/infiniti-prototype-10-concept-photos/

August 22, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Singer’s Latest Creation Brings Formula 1 Know-How to the Porsche 911 The famed Porsche restoration house has produced what it calls the most advanced air-cooled 911 on the planet. https://www.wired.com/story/singer-porsche-911-williams/

August 22, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall GM’s 3-D-Printed Seat Bracket Heralds a Future of Cheaper, Better Cars Additive manufacturing is finally reaching the auto industry in earnest, and it could change how cars are built. https://www.wired.com/story/general-motors-auto-industry-3d-printing-additive-manufacturing/

August 21, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Missed Connections of San Francisco’s Gleaming New Transit Station The newly opened, $2.26 billion Salesforce Transit Center is shiny and bright, but could do much more to guide residents and tourists into the city. https://www.wired.com/story/san-francisco-transbay-terminal-transit-center/

August 21, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Wildest Lawsuits Facing Tesla Right Now The beleaguered electric auto maker is finally cranking out Model 3s, but it has a few other issues to handle, too. https://www.wired.com/story/wildest-lawsuits-tesla-right-now/

August 20, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Self-Driving Startup Teaching Cars to Talk Silicon Valley-based Drive.ai relies on machine learning to make its robots drive—and smart design to make them communicate. https://www.wired.com/story/driveai-self-driving-design-frisco-texas/

August 20, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Self-Driving Cars Should Look Down, Not Just Ahead A Boston-based startup wants to equip AVs with ground penetrating radar, which they can use to identify exactly where they are. https://www.wired.com/story/ground-penetrating-radar-self-driving-cars/

August 20, 2018 | Author: Steven LevySteven Levy 385 Feet of Crazy: The Most Audacious Flying Machine Ever Alt-aviation wizard Burt Rutan set out to design a plane that could haul rockets to the edge of space. Then he persuaded Microsoft cofounder Paul Allen to build a dual-fuselage beast with a wingspan longer than a football field. https://www.wired.com/story/stratolaunch-airplane-burt-rutan-paul-allen/

August 19, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart This Week in the Future of Cars: Honey We Broke the Future As Elon Musk draws the wrath of investors and maybe the SEC, whither Tesla? Plus, the Boring Company heads to LA, and Alphabet’s Sidewalk Labs tries to rethink the future of cities. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-tesla-sec-news-roundup/

August 18, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Elon Musk Is Broken, and We Have Broken Him The CEO’s increasingly erratic behavior is putting Tesla at risk. And there’s blame to go around. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-tesla-tweets-struggles/

August 17, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Sidewalk Labs’ Bid to Reinvent Toronto Starts With Shape-Shifting Streets Google’s sister company intends to rethink how cities work, and that means adding some flexibility to how their public spaces are designed. https://www.wired.com/story/google-sidewalk-labs-toronto-quayside-flexible-streets/

August 15, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Elon Musk’s Boring Company Plans to Dig a Tunnel to Dodger Stadium The proposed 3.6-mile route would take fans from the metro to the parking lot, saving them from hellish LA traffic. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-boring-company-tunnel-los-angeles-dodger-stadium/

August 15, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Elon Musk and His Fight With the SEC The Tesla CEO might have trouble winning a showdown with the federal agency, according to experts. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-private-elon-musk-sec-investigation/

August 14, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Why Saudi Arabia Would Want to Invest in Elon Musk and Tesla Spending on electric cars is a great way to diversify an economy built on the back of Big Oil. https://www.wired.com/story/saudi-arabia-investment-elon-musk-tesla/

August 12, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Show Me the Money Elon Musk’s tweets, Tesla’s mysterious privatization scheme, Uber’s New York loss, and more car news. https://www.wired.com/story/this-week-future-cars-tesla-private/

August 11, 2018 | Author: Aarian Marshall, Jack StewartAarian Marshall and Jack Stewart Stealing a Plane Is Not Easy, So How Did It Happen in Seattle? Investigators are asking how a man managed to steal, fly, and crash a plane without authorization. https://www.wired.com/story/seattle-stolen-plane-investigation/

August 11, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Details on Tesla Going Private Are a Little Clearer, But Not Much Elon Musk still has to prove he has the funding in place, and investors want to know where it’s coming from. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-going-private/

August 8, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall New York City Goes After Uber and Lyft The Big Apple deals the ride-hail companies with their first set of serious American regulations. Which city will impose regulations next? https://www.wired.com/story/new-york-city-cap-uber-lyft/

August 8, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Semiautonomous Cars Have Flaws. That’s Why They Need Tests The Insurance Institute for Highway Safety tested features in cars from Tesla, BMW, Mercedes, and Volvo and found they all had issues. Here’s where safety rankings would come in handy. https://www.wired.com/story/semi-autonomous-cars-safety-tests/

August 7, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Can Elon Musk Really Take Tesla Private? The Tesla CEO tweeted he had secured funding for a buyout of the electric carmaker, and market madness ensued. https://www.wired.com/story/can-elon-musk-really-take-tesla-private/

August 7, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart As Uber Gives up on Self-Driving Trucks, Another Startup Jumps In Kodiak, founded by an ex-Uber engineer, wants to become the go-to source for the tech to make trucks drive themselves. https://www.wired.com/story/kodiak-self-driving-semi-trucks/

August 7, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Startup Would Like Self-Driving Car Companies to Share Data If data-labeling companies like Scale API have to re-do the same kind of work for multiple autonomous driving companies, the really important stuff—the weird edge cases—might get missed. https://www.wired.com/story/scale-ai-label-share-self-driving-data/

August 6, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Meet the UK’s New, Very British Fighter Jet With both allies and adversaries in doubt, an aircraft concept that looks out for numero uno. https://www.wired.com/story/uk-very-british-tempest-fighter-jet/

August 6, 2018 | Author: Michael CaloreMichael Calore What It’s Like to Drive Ford’s New Mustang Bullitt To commemorate the 50th anniversary of Hollywood’s greatest-ever car chase, Ford has trotted out an updated version of the iconic green fastback from the film Bullitt. https://www.wired.com/story/2019-ford-mustang-bullitt-test-drive/

August 5, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Can’t We All Just Get Along? Tesla’s earnings call, Elon Musk’s chip announcement, Sacramento’s self-driving ambitions, and more car news. https://www.wired.com/story/this-week-future-cars-tesla-apology-nvidia/

August 4, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla Says Its New Self-Driving Chip Is Finally Baked The car company says it developed its own computer chip, taking it one more step toward vertically integrating its autonomous driving technology. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-self-driving-car-computer-chip-nvidia/

August 1, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla Loses More Money Than Ever, but Says Profits Are Coming Today’s investor call was low on Muskian braggadocio, delivered a little hater schadenfreude, and offered some reasonable promises. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-q2-2018-earnings-call/

August 1, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Sacramento Eases Into the Self-Driving Scene A $100,000 partnership with the company Phantom Auto shows the city wants to be tech-forward, but is cautious. https://www.wired.com/story/sacramento-phantom-auto-self-driving-car-partnership/

July 31, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Can Waymo Self-Driving Cars Help Fix Phoenix’s Public Transit? The Silicon Valley self-driving company just announced a partnership with Phoenix’s Valley Metro, which prompts the age-old question: Can a private tech company provide solutions for the masses? https://www.wired.com/story/waymo-phoenix-partnership/

July 29, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: In Good Times and Bad Flying cars sound fun! But flying car regulations do not. The baby Airstream is so tiny and adorable! But that baby Airstream’s price tag is not. Plus: more ups and downs in the week’s car news. https://www.wired.com/story/future-of-cars-flying-cars/

July 27, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Happy Weekend, Here’s DJ Khaled on a Lyft E-Scooter The first look at the ride-hail company’s newest line of business, courtesy of the ‘gram. https://www.wired.com/story/dj-khaled-lyft-scooter/

July 27, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Airstream’s $40,000 Baby Trailer Gets an Off-Roading Upgrade The new X-Package upgrade gives the Basecamp a 3-inch lift kit that increases ground clearance, plus all-terrain tires from Goodyear. https://www.wired.com/story/airstream-basecamp-x-package/

July 26, 2018 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton Much of the US Electric Grid Could Go the Way of the Landline Phone As renewable energy picks up and electricity demand drops, it’s getting way more expensive for a large part of the grid to produce electricity, and that’s a problem for everyone. https://www.wired.com/story/electric-grid-rising-costs-renewables/

July 26, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Baraja’s New Lidar Uses Rainbow Physics to Help Self-Driving Cars See Instead of relying on a single spinning laser, the prism-based technology for self-driving cars takes advantage of how wavelengths of light arrange themselves. https://www.wired.com/story/baraja-lidar-prism-self-driving-cars/

July 25, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart We Trained Like Tom Cruise for the Wild Mission: Impossible Helicopter Stunt To see how Cruise pulled off the gut-twisting corkscrew dive, we went to Airbus’ helicopter flight school for our own training time. https://www.wired.com/story/mission-impossible-fallout-helicopter-stunt-tom-cruise/

July 25, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Congress May Love Flying Cars, But the Skies Still Need Traffic Cops The House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology loved what they heard from Uber, but experts wonder if flying taxis are really ready for takeoff. https://www.wired.com/story/congress-flying-cars-regulation/

July 24, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall After the Fatal Crash, Uber Revamps Its Robo-Car Testing The new program will put two safety drivers in each car, and the company will deploy a system that watches to see if they’re actually paying attention. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-crash-uber-revamps-testing/

July 24, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Not Just Tech Bros: E-Scooter Fans Are Surprisingly Diverse A new report shows shared electric scooters are a valued way of getting around for a diverse swath of city folk, including women and low-income populations. https://www.wired.com/story/electric-scooter-share-demographics-report-study-populus/

July 22, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Sweating the Small Stuff BMW goes after Uber, Tesla charms its customers, Zoox takes on the crazy streets of San Francisco, and more news from the swift-shifting world of cars. https://www.wired.com/story/car-news-roundup-tesla-zoox-bmw-reachnow-uber/

July 21, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Solar May Never Power Your EV, but You Can Still Drive on Sunshine Solar panels may never be good enough to keep electric cars from being plugged in, but advances in the tech make driving on power generated from the sun a near-term possibility. https://www.wired.com/story/solar-power-electric-cars/

July 20, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Beyond Elon Musk’s Drama, Tesla’s Cars Are Thrilling Drivers Look beyond the Twitter antics and the up-and-down stock price, and you’ll find a growing mass of happy customers. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-range-record-munro-profitability-model-3/

July 20, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Zoox Flashes Serious Self-Driving Skills in Chaotic San Francisco The secretive startup has released a video showing its car facing down some of San Francisco’s gnarliest thoroughfares and San Franciscans’ most befuddling behaviors. https://www.wired.com/story/zoox-self-driving-car-video-san-francisco/

July 19, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The Head-Spinning Challenge of Teaching Helicopters to Fly Themselves Aviation companies around the world are working on self-flying helicopters, a technical ordeal that makes robo-planes look easy. https://www.wired.com/story/sikorsky-self-flying-helicopter-sara/

July 19, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Loon’s Internet-Slinging Balloons Are Headed to Work Over Kenya The former Google X project, now its own Alphabet company, signs its first commercial agreement. https://www.wired.com/story/loon-internet-balloons-kenya-google-alphabet-x/

July 18, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Internet of Balloons How Loon, Google’s newest sister company, uses stratospheric balloons to make the web truly worldwide. https://www.wired.com/amp-stories/loon-internet-of-balloons/

July 17, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall BMW’s Launching an Uber Competitor in Seattle The automaker’s ReachNow car-sharing service now lets users book rides with pro drivers, putting it in competition with and Uber Black and Lyft Lux. https://www.wired.com/story/bmw-reachnow-ride-hailing-seattle/

July 17, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Self-Driving Cars Finally Get an Easy-to-Read Rule Book The ‘Road Rules’ platform lets cities compile details about things like stop signs and school zones in a computer-friendly format that any self-driving developer can fold into its software. https://www.wired.com/story/inrix-road-rules-self-driving-cars/

July 15, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: The Inside Look Our look at Alphabet’s moonshot factory, Uber’s HR chief resigns, Elon Musk’s plan for a high-tech cave rescue, and more. https://www.wired.com/story/this-week-in-future-cars-inside-look/

July 15, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Complex Engineering of the Simple Hook That Could Make Drone Deliveries Real Engineers at the Google sister company Wing spent more than a few hours searching for just the right mechanism that would let their drones safely deliver packages. https://www.wired.com/story/wing-alphabet-x-drone-engineering/

July 14, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Pininfarina’s Back With a $2 Million Electric Hypercar The famed Italian design house hopes to win over customers with a battery-powered ride that hits 60 mph in under two seconds and offers 310 miles of range. https://www.wired.com/story/pininfarina-electric-supercar-pf0-specs/

July 13, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Home From the Honeymoon, the Self-Driving Car Industry Faces Reality In the post-Uber crash era, self-driving car developers are struggling with how to present their technology to an increasingly wary public. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-car-faces-reality/

July 12, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Terrible Timing of Tesla’s Expiring $7,500 Tax Credit Now that Elon Musk’s car company is finally putting out the more affordable Model 3, it could be a problem. https://www.wired.com/story/terrible-timing-teslas-expiring-tax-credit/

July 12, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Sweden’s Electric Robo-Truck Is Made for Life in the Forest Einride’s T-log ditches the engine for batteries, the human for software, and the container for a big pile of logs. https://www.wired.com/story/einride-t-log-electric-autonomous-self-driving-truck/

July 11, 2018 | Author: Wendy DentWendy Dent The Engineering Behind Elon Musk’s Bid to Save Thailand’s Cave Boys The SpaceX and Tesla CEO’s work to help the rescue operation captivated the internet and reinforced the most flattering image of Musk, as a brilliant engineer with a nose for unexpected solutions to pressing problems. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-thailand-cave-boys-rescue-engineering/

July 11, 2018 | Author: Jessi HempelJessi Hempel Uber and Lyft’s Never-Ending Quest to Crush Price Comparison Apps Apps like Bellhop and RideGuru allow riders to find the best deal—highlighting the uncomfortable truth that price is the bottom line for ride-sharing companies. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-and-lyfts-never-ending-quest-to-crush-price-comparison-apps/

July 11, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Good and Bad of Ride-Sharing When It Comes to Race Research conducted in LA shows that Lyft reaches almost every neighborhood, regardless of race or income, but black riders still wait longer to be picked up. https://www.wired.com/story/race-good-and-bad-ride-share/

July 11, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Inside X, the Moonshot Factory Racing to Build the Next Google Seven years after its secretive launch, X is starting to spawn mind-blowing companies—and show us what an ever expanding Google means for the world. https://www.wired.com/story/alphabet-google-x-innovation-loon-wing-graduation/

July 10, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Mercedes Will Launch Self-Driving Taxis in California Next Year Mercedes parent company Daimler has struck the partnerships it thinks it needs to keep up in the race for autonomy. https://www.wired.com/story/mercedes-will-launch-self-driving-taxis-in-california-next-year/

July 10, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Bulgaria’s First New Plane in Decades Is a Freakishly Strong Drone Brothers Svilen and Konstantin Rangelov are working on a drone they say will someday haul 800 pounds up to 1,550 miles. https://www.wired.com/story/dronamics-bulgaria-cargo-drone/

July 7, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Lofty Goals, Raw Ambition Tesla meets Model 3 production goals, Lyft buys into bikes, GM’s self-driving cars get into a scrape, and more. https://www.wired.com/story/car-news-roundup-tesla-production-polaris-sllingshot/

July 7, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart NASA Tests a Plane That Is Very, Very Quiet Messy air around the plane is what creates all that noise, but engineers experimented with a variety of techniques that smoothed things out and hushed things down. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-cuts-airplane-noise/

July 7, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart A Racing Robocar Takes On England’s Swankiest Track Roborace’s Robocar is headed to the Goodwood Festival of Speed to tackle the event’s famed hill climb. https://www.wired.com/story/roborace-robocar-goodwood-festival-speed-hill-climb/

July 5, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Funky Boat Circling the Planet on Renewable Energy and Hydrogen Gas The French-built Energy Observer is on a years-long, 50-country tour of the planet, spreading the gospel of fossil-fuel-free ocean travel. https://www.wired.com/story/energy-observer-renewable-energy-voyage/

July 5, 2018 | Author: Jordan GolsonJordan Golson The Sooty, Swirling Logistics of Fighting 2018’s First Major Wildfire As the 2018 fire season gets going, a report from Durango, Colorado, lays out how firefighters tackle major blazes. https://www.wired.com/story/durango-wildfire-416-fighting/

July 4, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Delightfully Nonsensical Slingshot Might Just Be the Future of Driving The three-wheeler from Polaris is all about having fun on the road—and once the robots free us from the drudgery of daily driving, that’s all we’ll have left. https://www.wired.com/story/polaris-slingshot-future-driving/

July 3, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Audi’s Electric E-Tron Ditches Side-View Mirrors for Sleek, Silent Cameras The much-anticipated SUV uses cameras and interior displays to improve aerodynamics and cut noise—too bad the setup’s illegal in the US. https://www.wired.com/story/audi-etron-mirrors-cameras-interior-photos/

July 3, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A Cruise-on-Cruise Crash Reveals the Hardest Thing About Self-Driving Tech Humans are wild beasts, and they’re not getting off the road anytime soon. https://www.wired.com/story/cruise-on-cruise-crash-hardest-thing-self-driving/

July 3, 2018 | Author: Jay WalljasperJay Walljasper The Bitter Battle to Turn an Old Factory Into a 21st Century ‘Eco-Village’ A bold plan to redevelop Ford’s Twin Cities Assembly Plant has become the focus of a fight over density, traffic, and the future of cities. https://www.wired.com/story/ford-st-paul-development-housing-cities-yimby-nimby/

July 2, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Lyft’s Big Bike-Share Buy Is About Ruling the Streets The ride-hailing company’s acquisition of the country’s largest bike-share operator moves Lyft beyond the car—and raises a few questions. https://www.wired.com/story/lyft-motivate-bike-share-aquisition/

July 2, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla Finally Hits Its Model 3 Goal—And Immediately Ups the Ante After months of production hell, Elon Musk’s automaker finally made 5,000 Model 3 cars in one week. And it’s already shooting for 6,000. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-model-3-production-goals/

July 1, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Unconventional Wisdom Uber gets new life in London, VW climbs a mountain, robo-cars deliver groceries, and more from the molting world of transportation. https://www.wired.com/story/car-news-roundup-mclaren-senna-uber-london/

June 30, 2018 | Author: Basem WasefBasem Wasef McLaren’s $958,966 Senna Hypercar Ain’t Pretty, but It Can Whip a Track The automaker’s latest ride, named for an F1 legend, won’t win your heart with its looks. Who cares? https://www.wired.com/story/mclaren-senna-review/

June 29, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Crash-Happy RC Cars Make Self-Driving Tech Smarter Short on time, money, and space, Georgia Tech researchers created a 1:5 scale platform that lets them test autonomous tech without fear of crashing. https://www.wired.com/story/crash-happy-rc-cars-make-self-driving-tech-smarter/

June 28, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Get Yer Bread and Milk From Kroger’s Cute New Delivery Robot Built by Nuro, the little autonomous R1 can carry 12 bags of groceries to your door—but the other logistics are still up in the air. https://www.wired.com/story/nuro-grocery-delivery-robot/

June 28, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Boeing’s Proposed Hypersonic Plane Is Really, Really Fast Supersonic planes are always almost here, but maybe the way to fly is to go faster. Much, much faster. https://www.wired.com/story/boeing-hypersonic-mach-5-jet-concept/

June 27, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Distracted Driving Is Out of Control, and There’s No Single Cure What with phones and in-car infotainment systems, it’s harder than ever to watch the road—and it’s becoming a problem. https://www.wired.com/story/distracted-driving-studies-statistics/

June 26, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams VR Pilot Training Now Comes With a Sense of Touch Finger-mounted actuators give pilots training with virtual reality the sensation of touching the switches and controls, so they’re better prepared when the move into the real cockpit. https://www.wired.com/story/pilot-training-simulator-vr-haptic-touch/

June 26, 2018 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton Traffic Doesn’t Hurt the Economy—But We Should Still Fix It A new study questions the idea that gridlock stalls commerce, and points to a new way of talking about the problem. https://www.wired.com/story/traffic-economy-fixes/

June 25, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Neat Engineering VW Used to Smash the Pikes Peak Record The team simulated energy usage in its all-electric race car, but Sunday’s sprint was the first time it was able to test it in action. https://www.wired.com/story/engineering-of-the-vw-pikes-peak-battery/

June 25, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Uber Tells London’s Regulators ‘We’ve Changed’ The ride-sharing company needs the world to believe that it has reformed if it’s going to get self-driving cars on the road. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-case-starts-in-london/

June 25, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Cities Are Watching You—Urban Sciences Graduates Watch Back American Wi-Fi networks, smart traffic lights, security cameras, cell phones, and vehicles are throwing off truckloads of data. A new program at MIT (and others like it) teaches students to handle it in ways that make residents’ lives better. https://www.wired.com/story/mit-urban-sciences-program/

June 24, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Getting Down and Dirty Ford’s foray into train stations, VW’s electric mountain climber, and more car news from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/week-in-future-of-cars-down-and-dirty/

June 22, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies How Tesla Is Building Cars in Its Parking Lot We dug through the permits Elon Musk’s automaker filed for the right to start building Model 3 sedans in a semi-permanent tent outside its Fremont factory. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-fremont-factory-model-3-production-tent-parking-lot-structure/

June 22, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Unavoidable Folly of Making Humans Train Self-Driving Cars Humans are terrible at paying attention when they’re doing all the driving. So why expect anything different when the robot is in charge? https://www.wired.com/story/uber-crash-arizona-human-train-self-driving-cars/

June 22, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart VW’s Electrifying Bid to Dominate a Mountain Race To conquer the Pikes Peak International Hill Climb, Volkswagen ditched the engine for a pair of batteries and a clever new charging setup. https://www.wired.com/story/vw-volkswagen-pikes-peak-hill-climb-id-r-race/

June 21, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Massachusetts Welcomes Self-Driving Cars—With a Couple Caveats The state’s DOT and cities in the Boston area are pioneering a new regulatory regime to encourage testing of this new tech, without letting developers do whatever they like. https://www.wired.com/story/massachusetts-boston-self-driving-car-rules-regulations/

June 21, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Colorado Joins California in the Fight for Cleaner Cars While the EPA moves to roll back vehicle emissions standards, Colorado’s using a legal loophole to follow California’s much stricter rules. https://www.wired.com/story/colorado-epa-california-emissions/

June 19, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Why Ford Is Buying Detroit’s Derelict Train Station It’s a savvy PR move, but it also sends a big message. The carmaker wants to show it can compete with Uber and Waymo and all the Silicon Valley tech giants. https://www.wired.com/story/why-ford-buying-detroit-derelict-train-station/

June 18, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Engineers Turning an Old Volvo Concept Into a $155,000 Hybrid Five years after showing off the Concept Coupe, Volvo has resurrected the much-loved design as the first offering from its newly electric-focused brand, Polestar. https://www.wired.com/story/volvo-polestar-1-design-engineering/

June 17, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: The Big Dig Elon Musk’s Boring Company gets work in Chicago, Volvo gets some lidar, Byton’s new concept, and more. https://www.wired.com/story/car-news-roundup-boring-chicago-byton-concept/

June 15, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Four Reasons We Don’t Have Flying Cars—Yet The technological hurdles facing the development of aircraft for urban mobility systems like UberAIR are massive, but not insurmountable. https://www.wired.com/story/four-reasons-we-dont-have-flying-cars-yet/

June 14, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Elon Musk’s Boring Company Wins a Big Boring Contract in Chicago Pods in the tunnel will speed people to O’Hare Airport in less than 15 minutes. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-boring-company-contract-chicago/

June 14, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Boeing’s $2 Million Challenge to Make the Sky Fun Again—With ‘Flying Motorbikes’ In a Boeing-sponsored competition, teams designed personal flying machines that look more like jetpacks and flying motorbikes than the boring planes we use today. https://www.wired.com/story/boeing-gofly-competition-personal-flying-machine-winners/

June 14, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Volvo Finds the Lidar It Needs to Build Self-Driving Cars The automaker plans to use Luminar’s laser sensors to help its autonomous vehicles see and understand the world. https://www.wired.com/story/volvo-self-driving-lidar-luminar/

June 14, 2018 | Author: Mark HarrisMark Harris The Bike Share War Is Shaking Up Seattle Like Nowhere Else Residents are divided over whether the city’s dockless bike share program is revolutionizing transit—or creating an unwieldy, dangerous mess. https://www.wired.com/story/the-bike-share-war-is-shaking-up-seattle-like-nowhere-else/

June 13, 2018 | Author: Tim NewcombTim Newcomb The Brilliant Vigilance of Seattle’s Gargantuan New Tunnel How do you keep a tunnel safe? Hundreds of cameras, 17 jet fans, and a sprinkler system that can out-hose Splash Mountain. https://www.wired.com/story/seattle-sr-99-tunnel-tech-bertha/

June 13, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Self-Driving Cars Likely Won’t Steal Your Job (Until 2040) A new report finds that while some jobs, like trucking, will eventually fade, autonomous tech will benefit the economy overall. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-car-job-impact-economy-savings-safe-report/

June 12, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Byton’s K-Byte Electric Concept Makes Self-Driving Look Good While Tesla struggles, Chinese automakers like Byton are aiming to gobble up its market share with electric, someday self-driving cars. https://www.wired.com/story/byton-k-byte-concept-electric-self-driving/

June 12, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber Strips Down Its App to Ramp Up in Developing Countries Uber Lite should make the ride-hailing service easier to use in markets where service is spotty and data is limited, starting with India. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-lite-india-app/

June 11, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Finally, a Real World Grading System for Autopilot Tech The UK’s Thatcham Research will soon start evaluating systems like Tesla’s Autopilot not just on how they drive, but on how easy they are to understand. https://www.wired.com/story/thatcham-autopilot-grading-semi-autonomous/

June 11, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart A Single Drone Helped Mexican Police Drop Crime 10 Percent Over four months, police in Ensenada, south of Tijuana, used a DJI drone to help make 500 arrests and cut robberies by 30 percent. https://www.wired.com/story/ensenada-mexico-police-drone/

June 10, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: It’s Business Time Larry Page’s flying car starts to look real, Uber and Lyft get into bike-sharing, and Elon Musk works to get Tesla on track. https://www.wired.com/story/future-cars-roundup-tesla-shareholders-kitty-hawk-flyer/

June 9, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Land Rover Wants to Take Self-Driving Cars Off-Roading Land Rover always delivers capability and convenience, and that means teaching its cars to drive themselves where the roads don’t go. https://www.wired.com/story/land-rover-self-driving-cortex/

June 8, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Airbus Rattles Its Whale of a Jet in the Name of Safety Before it can make its maiden flight this summer, the enormous, glorious Airbus Beluga XL must survive the static ground vibration test. https://www.wired.com/story/airbus-beluga-xl-testing/

June 8, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Larry Page’s Flying Car Project Suddenly Seems Rather Real The Google founder’s Kitty Hawk has shown a new version of its Flyer vehicle, boasting a sleek design and solid specs. https://www.wired.com/story/kitty-hawk-larry-page-flying-car-prototype/

June 7, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Lyft Redesigns Its App—and Strategy—for the Age of Sharing Believing sharing is key to its longterm success, the Uber rival is doing everything it can to get more people into fewer cars. https://www.wired.com/story/lyft-app-redesign-sharing/

June 6, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Dawn of Mobile Convenience Stores—and (Maybe) Free Rides Startups like Cargo, which allow you to buy convenience-store items from ride-hailing drivers, point to a future where your commute doesn’t cost a cent—because you, friend, are the product. https://www.wired.com/story/cargo-and-the-dawn-of-the-free-ride/

June 5, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Elon Musk Calms Down, and More News From Tesla’s Big Shareholder Meeting At the automaker’s annual shareholder meeting, the CEO struck a conciliatory note while providing updates on Model 3 production, Autopilot, Tesla’s Supercharger network, veganism, and more. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-tesla-shareholders-meeting/

June 5, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall To Bring On the Robocars, Scientists Must Understand How Humans Ride Researchers at the University of Michigan are just the latest to use pokey driverless shuttles to study how people use, and feel about using, this new technology. https://www.wired.com/story/michigan-mcity-self-driving-shuttle-research/

June 4, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Save the Scooters, Redesign the Streets, and Save San Francisco Instead of limiting scooters, officials should rebuild infrastructure with their riders in mind. Because a city made for scooters is a city made for freedom. https://www.wired.com/story/san-francisco-scooter-ban/

June 3, 2018 | Author: Alex Davies, Aarian MarshallAlex Davies and Aarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Money Money Money Moneyyy! Softbank puts $2 billion into GM’s self-driving venture, Avis looks to the future, automakers play with subscriptions, and more from a very dynamic automotive world. https://www.wired.com/story/gm-softbank-investment-tesla-braking-news-roundup/

June 1, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Lyft Wants to Dominate Transportation, and That Means Bike Share The ride-hailing company is reportedly buying Motivate, the largest bike-share company in the US, for $250 million. https://www.wired.com/story/lyft-bike-share-motivate-acquisition/

June 1, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies As Rental Cars Fade Away, Avis Will Try Anything to Survive The 72-year-old company is ready to try just about anything, from bikes to robots, to stick around. https://www.wired.com/story/avis-ohad-zeira-self-driving-future/

May 31, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Softbank Pours $2.25 Billion Into GM’s Bid for Self-Driving Dominance It’s the biggest deal yet in a nascent but booming industry, and confirms the automaker’s status as one of the leading players. https://www.wired.com/story/general-motors-softbank-cruise-self-driving-investment/

May 31, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Airbus’ H160 Helicopter Helps Save Pilots from Their Own Mistakes If pilots ever lose their bearings, a double-tap on the yoke automatically returns the helicopter to a stable, controlled position. https://www.wired.com/story/airbus-h160-helicopter/

May 30, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla’s Quick Fix for Its Braking System Came From the Ether Shortly after Consumer Reports panned the Model 3 for its long stopping distance, Elon pushed a change through to adjust the antilock algorithm. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-model3-braking-software-update-consumer-reports/

May 30, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Mapbox Uses Your Phone’s Camera to Chart a Changing World The mapping company’s new software development kit will let its customers tap into data from their users’ phone cameras to keep tabs on the streets in real time. https://www.wired.com/story/mapbox-phone-camera-data-software-development-kit/

May 29, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall False Positives: Self-Driving Cars and the Agony of Knowing What Matters New details from Uber’s self-driving crash highlight the difficulty—and importance—of ignoring what doesn’t matter, while recognizing what does. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-cars-uber-crash-false-positive-negative/

May 28, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Forget Robo-Cars and Hit the Water on an Autonomous Boat Rather than worrying about robo-taxis, researchers at places like MIT are making ships self-piloting to save fuel and prevent accidents. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-ships-boats/

May 27, 2018 | Author: Caitlin HarringtonCaitlin Harrington Automakers Are Making Car Ownership Optional Monthly car subscriptions through startups like Carma Car, Fair, and Flexdrive offer all the utility of ownership with none of the hassle. https://www.wired.com/story/automakers-subscription-car-ownership-optional/

May 26, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Israel’s Self-Flying ‘Cormorant’ Whisks Wounded Soldiers to Safety Tactical Robotics’ autonomous aircraft may not look too cool, but it might make battlefields safer and eventually help civilians fly around town. https://www.wired.com/story/tactical-robotics-cormorant-autonomous/

May 25, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies This Week in the Future of Cars: Burn, Baby, Burn Elon Musk’s Twitter rage, new details on Uber’s self-driving crash, and more car news from a wild week. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-crash-elon-twitter-media-rage-roundup/

May 24, 2018 | Author: Aarian Marshall, Alex DaviesAarian Marshall and Alex Davies Uber’s Self-Driving Car Saw the Woman It Killed, Report Says The National Transportation Safety Board says the vehicle had trouble identifying Elaine Herzberg as a human, and then wasn’t able to brake to avoid hitting her. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-self-driving-crash-arizona-ntsb-report/

May 24, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall California’s Heavy-Handed Plan to Regulate the Self-Driving Car Biz Self-driving industry reps are not happy with the Public Utilities Commission’s proposed plan for how driverless taxis should operate—especially the requirements that they offer services for free and ban pooled rides. https://www.wired.com/story/californias-plan-regulate-self-driving-car-biz/

May 24, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Students Turn the Chevy Camaro Into a Eco-Happy Future Machine College teams from around the country competed by making hybrid and electric versions of the muscle car. https://www.wired.com/story/chevy-camaro-hybrid-student-competition-ecocar3/

May 23, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Porsche’s New Cayenne Hybrid Checks Your Route to Pick its Power The luxury SUV looks down the road to see where battery power would be best, and where you’ll need old-fashioned internal combustion. https://www.wired.com/story/porsche-cayenne-e-hybrid/

May 22, 2018 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton Math Says Urinals in Planes Could Make Lavatory Lines Shorter for Everyone As long as you’ve got the exact right number of urinals. https://www.wired.com/story/airplane-urinals-lines-math/

May 22, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Engineers Don’t Totally Dig Elon Musk’s Tunneling Promises The Boring Company CEO makes a lot of promises about advancing tunneling and clearing congestion, but not everyone buys in. https://www.wired.com/story/engineers-dont-totally-dig-musk-tunneling/

May 21, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla Expands Its Model 3 Offerings—At a Steep Price Elon Musk’s automaker is now offering more variants of its most important car, and making steady progress toward profitability. But that $35,000 price point remains just a promise. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-expands-model-3-offerings-consumer-reports-review/

May 21, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Seakeeper’s Super Spinning System Keeps Ships Stable at Sea Seakeeper’s gyroscopic system counteracts a boat’s natural motion to keep you and your seasick friends from rocking with the waves. https://www.wired.com/story/seakeeper-stable-ship-system/

May 21, 2018 | Author: Aarian Marshall, Alex DaviesAarian Marshall and Alex Davies Lots of Lobbies and Zero Zombies: How Self-Driving Cars Will Reshape Cities Urban planners can ditch those outdated layouts and transform the city into a joyful mess of throughways and byways optimized not for cars but for people. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-cars-cities/

May 18, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Who’s In Charge Here, Anyway? Uber’s flying car plan encounters the FAA, Tesla’s Autopilot fight continues, Audi keeps its self-driving tech out of the US, and more car news this week. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-flying-cars-tesla-autopilot-roundup/

May 18, 2018 | Author: Jack Stewart, Aarian MarshallJack Stewart and Aarian Marshall Elon Musk Presents His Tunnel Vision to the People of LA The Boring Company CEO presented his idea for slaying traffic to a packed crowd in Los Angeles, sharing specs and engineering details and promising to beat his pet snail in a race. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-boring-company-tunnels-los-angeles-plan/

May 17, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Is Tesla’s Autopilot Safe? Finding Out Demands Better Data Elon Musk has made bold claims about his sort of self-driving feature saving lives, but the truth is far trickier, and harder to reach. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-autopilot-crash-safety/

May 16, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Nissan’s Following Tesla Into Solar Power and Home Batteries The maker of the Leaf is now offering UK homeowners rooftop solar panels and big batteries for a clean ride from generation to acceleration. https://www.wired.com/story/nissan-solar-panels-home-batteries/

May 16, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart It Takes a Single Autonomous Car to Prevent Phantom Traffic Jams New research shows that the presence of just one connected, automated car can smooth traffic for everyone. https://www.wired.com/story/one-autonomous-car-prevent-traffic-jams/

May 15, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Americans Can’t Have Audi’s Super Capable Self-Driving System And the automaker’s reasons point to the American struggle to adapt to a new kind of driving. https://www.wired.com/story/audi-self-driving-traffic-jam-pilot-a8-2019-availablility/

May 14, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Acura Has Finally Made an Easy-to-Use Infotainment System The 2019 RDX SUV comes with a ‘True Touchpad’ interface that takes the best parts of touchscreens and touchpads, to make life on the road easier than ever. https://www.wired.com/story/acura-rdx-true-touch-infotainment-interface/

May 13, 2018 | Author: Clive ThompsonClive Thompson The Vehicle of the Future Has Two Wheels, Handlebars, and Is a Bike The future of transportation looks to be merging with sci-fi. But the bike-tech revolution reminds us that innovation isn’t always about the totally new. https://www.wired.com/story/vehicle-future-bike/

May 13, 2018 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton California Rules May Make Weed Shippers Report Themselves to the Feds To truck marijuana around the Golden State, you might have to register your vehicle with a federal government that’s not too keen on your new small business. https://www.wired.com/story/california-cannabis-shipping-regulations/

May 12, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Uber’s Flying-Car Plan Meets the Regulator It Can’t Ignore The FAA is down with drones, but it has a whole lot of questions before it lets Uber fill them with people. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-flying-cars-faa-regulation/

May 11, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Touch and Go Uber updates its totally serious flying car plan, Elon Musk battles investors, Texas gets self-driving cars, and more. https://www.wired.com/story/future-cars-roundup-tesla-uber-flying-cars/

May 11, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Save Lives With Smarter, Slower Streets—Not Self-Driving Cars Autonomous vehicles could save lots of lives someday. Right now, we need better street design. https://www.wired.com/story/pedestrian-deaths-street-design/

May 10, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Rolls-Royce Reveals the $325,000 Cullinan, Its Rowdy, Regal SUV The luxury carmaker’s new behemoth combines a massive engine and clever suspension to take the fancy folk absolutely anywhere they care to go. https://www.wired.com/story/rolls-royce-cullinan-suv-photos-specs/

May 9, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Struggling Tesla Faces an Investor Insurrection Amid a pile of crises and slow Model 3 production, one investor is calling for a shakeup of Tesla’s board of directors—and for more oversight over CEO Elon Musk. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-elon-musk-investors-board-vote/

May 9, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart FAA Relaxes Drone Restrictions With 10 New Programs Selected local authorities can use drones for defibrillator deliveries, runway inspections, and mosquito control. https://www.wired.com/story/faa-relaxes-drone-restrictions-with-10-new-programs/

May 9, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Unfold the Complex Engineering of Aston Martin’s Super Swanky Convertible Engineers spent four years designing and abusing a folding roof for the DB11 Volante. https://www.wired.com/story/aston-martin-db-11-volante-convertible-roof-engineering/

May 9, 2018 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton Why Traffic-Choked Nashville Said ‘No Thanks’ to Public Transit After the city’s voters shot down an ambitious plan to fund light rail and bus lines, transit advocates wonder where they went wrong. https://www.wired.com/story/nashville-transit-referendum-vote-plan/

May 8, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Uber Unveils the Flying Taxi It Wants to Rule the Skies The catamaran-like electric concept is the sort of vehicle Uber wants to integrate into a flying taxi network—it just needs other people to build the thing. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-unveils-flying-taxi/

May 7, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Texas Gets Its First Self-Driving Car Service Silicon Valley’s Drive.ai is starting a pilot program to ferry office workers around a small area of Frisco, with vehicles that can “chat” with passers-by. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-cars-texas-frisco-driveai/

May 5, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Lockheed’s Drone-Sploding Baby Missile Weighs Just 5 Pounds To defend against nimble threats like drones and mortar, the Miniature Hit-to-Kill missile’s tracking system borrows from medical imaging technology like X-rays, ultrasound, and endoscopy. https://www.wired.com/story/lockheed-martin-miniature-hit-kill-missile/

May 4, 2018 | Author: Aarian Marshall, Alex DaviesAarian Marshall and Alex Davies Waymo’s Self-Driving Car Crash in Arizona Revives Tough Questions Whether or not the autonomous Pacifica minivan was at fault, it’s bad news for a young industry trying to prove it can makes roads safer for everyone. https://www.wired.com/story/waymo-crash-self-driving-google-arizona/

May 4, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: All About Elon A blitz of Tesla news, plus: electric scooters, more trouble for Uber, and more arrests in Volkswagen’s diesel emissions scheme. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-musk-model-3-uber-vw-roundup/

May 4, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla’s Favorite Autopilot Safety Stat Just Doesn’t Hold Up Elon Musk’s automaker says the semiautonomous feature cuts crashes by 40 percent, but a closer look at the math reveals some major caveats. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-autopilot-safety-statistics/

May 3, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Elon Musk’s Attack on Tesla Investors Could Make Him a Liability After the CEO derided analysts for asking hard questions about Tesla’s finances, investors might be wary of Musk’s role in the company’s future. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-tesla-model-3-earnings-call/

May 3, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Americans Are Falling in Love With Bike Share But they’re not yet sold on dockless bikes, according to a new report. https://www.wired.com/story/americans-falling-in-love-bike-share/

May 3, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Airbus Combines Satellites, Planes, and Drones for a New View of the World ‘Airbus Aerial’ is using a variety of vehicles to provide vital data to climate modelers, farmers, city planners, infrastructure engineers, and first responders. https://www.wired.com/story/airbus-aerial-drones/

May 2, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Tesla Ramps Up Model 3 Production and Predicts Profits This Fall Elon Musk’s automaker is now building more than 2,000 Model 3 sedans a week and may be profitable sometime soon, thanks in part to the demise of Flufferbot. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-model-3-production-profitability/

May 2, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Buying a Tesla? Don’t Count on That $7,500 Tax Credit Tesla’s about to max out its use of the federal tax credit, setting up yet another hurdle for the struggling automaker as challenges mount from GM, Ford, Volvo, VW, and others. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-federal-tax-credit-model-3/

May 1, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Love of the People Isn’t Enough to Keep Shared Electric Scooters Rolling One company has seen a 61 percent day-over-day increase in ridership, but more serious problems could make it hard to stay in business. https://www.wired.com/story/shared-electric-scooters-rolling/

April 30, 2018 | Author: Nicolas StecherNicolas Stecher Mercedes-Benz’s Plan for Surviving the Auto Revolution The company that invented the automobile is getting ready for a world where batteries, sharing, and robots rule. https://www.wired.com/story/daimler-mercedes-case-wilko-stark-interview/

April 29, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Wildest Rides From Beijing’s Bling-Flinging Auto Show Automakers hankering for a piece of the booming Chinese market brought some of the swankiest wares to the capital city’s auto show this week. https://www.wired.com/gallery/beijing-auto-show-mercedes-bmw-concepts/

April 28, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A Dodger Stadium Gondola Is Just LA’s Latest Wild Bid to Bust Traffic Flying people to baseball games is exactly the kind of thing LA’s Office of Extraordinary Innovation was meant to consider. https://www.wired.com/story/dodger-gondola-bust-traffic/

April 27, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Let’s Get That Win Why self-driving car developers should be aiming lower; plus: an electric Maybach, Tesla’s (latest) Autopilot shakeup, and more. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-cars-win-tesla-autopilot-roundup/

April 27, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The Crazy, Complicated Engineering Inside Honda’s New Clarity Hybrid The latest Honda hybrid uses two motors, an engine, and a bevy of buttons, paddles, and pedals—and can leave drivers feeling like symphony conductors. https://www.wired.com/story/honda-clarity-hybrid-powertrain/

April 26, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Surprisingly Simple iPad Apps Pilots Use to Make Your Flight Better No Words With Friends here, it’s all about fuel calculations, safety notices, and maps. https://www.wired.com/story/pilot-ipad-apps/

April 26, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies BMW’s Self-Driving Cars Get Their Lasers The German automaker struck a deal to purchase lidar laser sensors from Israel’s Innoviz. https://www.wired.com/story/bmw-magna-innoviz-lidar-self-driving/

April 25, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart BMW’s New Electric SUV Looks Shockingly Normal After the ultra-funky i3 and i8, the German automaker is bringing its batteries into the mainstream. https://www.wired.com/story/bmw-electric-suv-ix3/

April 24, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall NYC Is Redesigning Its Ancient, Ponderous, and Unpopular Bus System In a city where buses average under 7 mph, rethinking routes could make a major difference. https://www.wired.com/story/nyc-redesigning-ponderous-bus/

April 24, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Mercedes’ Electric Maybach SUV Comes With a Built-In Tea Kettle A tea kettle surrounded by rose gold, white leather, and lots of swanky features. https://www.wired.com/story/mercedes-maybach-suv-concept-photos/

April 22, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart For a Much-Needed Win, Self-Driving Cars Should Aim Lower Stop talking about saving the world, and focus instead on making tangible improvements to people’s lives. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-self-driving-crash-strategy/

April 21, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Heat-Seeking Cameras Could Help Keep Self-Driving Cars Safe Thermal imaging cameras could provide one more way for robo-cars to see the world—and stay out of danger. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-cars-thermal-image-cameras/

April 20, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Taming the Jungle An electric scooter invasion, Uber’s peace process, Tesla’s tantrum, and more from a wild week. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-peace-tesla-scooters-roundup/

April 20, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The 11 Hypiest Hyperloop Projects We’ve Been Promised So Far Now it’s just a matter of seeing who can actually deliver on the futuristic, tube-based transportation system. https://www.wired.com/gallery/hyperloop-projects-TK-TK/

April 19, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Airlines Check Their Engines for the Flaw That Hit Southwest Flight 1380 Investigators says the 737’s engine showed signs of “metal fatigue”—and now airlines are hoping to find similar problems before they cause another disaster. https://www.wired.com/story/southwest-1380-engine-metal-fatigue/

April 19, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Bunkbeds in the Cargo Hold Trumpet a New Golden Age of Flying Coming attractions for economy fliers on Airbus planes could include actual lie-flat beds—in the cargo hold. https://www.wired.com/story/airbus-beds-cargo-hold/

April 19, 2018 | Author: Jessi HempelJessi Hempel Can This Man Help Uber Recover From the Travis Kalanick Era? CEO Dara Khosrowshahi is a champion of everything Uber once rejected: caution, discipline, and tact. Can he reform Silicon Valley’s most audacious company? https://www.wired.com/story/uber-move-slow-test-things/

April 18, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart How Southwest Flight 1380’s Pilots Landed With a Blown Engine One woman died on the flight from New York to Dallas after an engine failed and blew a hole in the cabin at 32,500 feet. https://www.wired.com/story/southwest-flight-1380-engine-failure-landing-pilots/

April 17, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Discombobulated Cities Wrestle With an Electric Scooter Influx San Francisco just passed a bill to take more control of how these scooter systems work, and it’s not the only city struggling to divide precious space. https://www.wired.com/story/discombobulated-cities-electric-scooters/

April 16, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber Makes Peace With Cities by Spilling Its Secrets The ride-hailing company is working with DC to share data—and the much coveted curb. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-nacto-data-sharing/

April 13, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Sharing Spaces Uber goes beyond cars, Airstream unveils a cozy trailer, Tesla fights the feds, and more. https://www.wired.com/story/roundup-tesla-ntsb-crash-uber-bikes/

April 12, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla’s Wild Fight With the Feds Investigating Its Autopilot Death Elon Musk’s automaker has quit the investigation led by the National Transportation Safety Board, and the sniping is getting serious. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-autopilot-investigation-ntsb-crash/

April 12, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Airstream’s New Baby Trailer is Less Pretty, More Practical The compact, lightweight Nest breaks with the aluminum tradition in favor of fiberglass. https://www.wired.com/story/the-new-airstream-nest/

April 12, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Luminar’s New Lidar Could Bring Vision to Every Robocar in the World The company run by a 23-year-old photonics genius is ramping up production as self-driving cars get closer to reality. https://www.wired.com/story/luminar-lidar-self-driving-cars/

April 11, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber’s New Bid for Dominance: Controlling Every Way You Move Uber’s going beyond ride-hailing with new plans to get its users into rental cars, bikes, and even public transit. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-bid-dominance-mobility/

April 11, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Raytheon’s New Radar Could Help Bring Flying Cars to Our Cities As drones and flying cars move into reality, we need radar systems better equipped for keeping an eye on everyone. https://www.wired.com/story/raytheon-radar-drones/

April 9, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Porsche’s Rule-Obliterating 919 Hybrid Evo Outraces F1’s Fastest Cars Ignoring the regulations that govern motorsports, the 919 Hybrid Evo beat F1 champ Lewis Hamilton’s record time at Belgium’s famed Spa Francorchamps track. https://www.wired.com/story/porsche-919-hybrid-evo/

April 9, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber Acquires the Bike-Share Company Jump The acquisition signals that Uber wants to be more than just taxi substitute. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-acquires-jump-bike/

April 9, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Fancy New Suspension Could Make Car Rides a Lot Smoother It works sort of like noise-cancelling headphones, eliminating bumps with movement in the opposite direction. https://www.wired.com/story/proactive-car-suspension/

April 8, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Inside the Safety Issues Surrounding the NY Helicopter Crash I was a passenger onboard a companion flight on March 11. Locked to the downed craft, the victims didn’t stand a chance. https://www.wired.com/story/helicopter-crash-harnesses-escape-training/

April 8, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Never-Ending Self-Driving Car Project When will autonomous vehicles be finished? Definitely do not hold your breath. Really—stop it. https://www.wired.com/story/when-will-self-driving-cars-ready/

April 7, 2018 | Author: Miranda KatzMiranda Katz The Dreamers of the L Train Shutdown How a disastrous 15-month shutdown on one of New York’s busier subway lines un-bottled the city’s creativity. https://www.wired.com/story/dreamers-l-train-shutdown/

April 6, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Working Through the Chaos A Tesla wreck, an EPA rollback, and a city simulator https://www.wired.com/story/week-future-cars-chaos/

April 4, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall As Shared Scooters Invade, Cities Must Decide Whose Vehicles Belong Where San Francisco is just the latest city dealing with a horde of new vehicles—from dockless bikes to electric scooters—and struggling to figure out how to best allocate limited space. https://www.wired.com/story/san-francisco-electric-scooters-bird-limebike/

April 3, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart NASA’s Newest X-Plane Could Revive Supersonic Flight for the Masses Lockheed Martin’s Low Boom Demonstrator joins the ranks of NASA’s famed X-planes—and could bring back the age of supersonic civilian aviation. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-x-plane-supersonic-lockheed-low-boom-x-58/

April 3, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla Finally Starts to Climb Out of Model 3 Production Hell The latest numbers from Elon Musk’s automaker show slow but encouraging progress in its fight to deliver history’s most anticipated car. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-model-3-production-elon-musk/

April 3, 2018 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton Truckers Take on Trump Over Electronic Surveillance Rules Drivers unhappy about electronic devices that track how much time they spend on the road are taking their grievances to Washington. https://www.wired.com/story/trump-truckers-hours-service-electronic-logging-device/

April 3, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The World’s Fastest Drones Want to Save Lives in America, Too Zipline is already making life-saving deliveries in Africa and Europe. Now it wants to start flying in its home country. https://www.wired.com/story/zipline-drone-delivery-reno-faa/

March 31, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Uber Crash Won’t Be the Last Shocking Self-Driving Death These systems will fail, and when the do, the result will look nothing like human-powered crashes. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-self-driving-crash-explanation-lidar-sensors/

March 30, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies China and the Children Will Save the Electric Car From Scott Pruitt’s EPA The EPA may be able to roll back regulations in the US, but other forces will push automakers to keep making electric cars. https://www.wired.com/story/trump-pruitt-epa-car-emissions-regulations-electric-cars-china/

March 30, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla’s Autopilot Was Involved in Another Deadly Car Crash The automaker says its semi-autonomous system was engaged when a Model X SUV hit a freeway barrier last week in California, killing the driver. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-autopilot-self-driving-crash-california/

March 30, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Worst Thing About Tesla’s 123,000-Car Recall? Crummy Timing Automakers recall cars all the time, but Tesla just doesn’t need any more problems right now. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-model-s-steering-bolt-recall/

March 30, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Back to Normal? A ban for Uber, a challenge to Tesla, and Jaguars for Waymo. https://www.wired.com/story/back-to-normal-cars-roundup-news/

March 29, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Jaguar’s New F-Pace SUV Is Fast, Sporty, and Expensive It goes from 0 to 60 in 4.1 seconds, and it has fatter tires and updated aerodynamics to match. https://www.wired.com/story/jaguar-fpace-suv/

March 28, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies SF Motors Brings the Latest Electric SUV to Challenge Tesla The Chinese-backed automaker is the most recent addition to a growing armada of automakers making electric cars. https://www.wired.com/story/sf-motors-electric-suv-tesla/

March 28, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart You’ll See Right Through the New Genesis Essentia Concept Car The new electric concept from Hyundai’s upscale line, just unveiled at the New York Auto Show, has a transparent hood, but no engine to show off. https://www.wired.com/story/new-genesis-essentia-concept-car/

March 27, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Waymo Expands Its Robo-Fleet with Electric Jaguar SUVs The company will buy 20,000 electric I-Paces and use them to create a massive platoon of self-driving ridesharing cars. https://www.wired.com/story/waymo-buys-jaguar-suvs/

March 27, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Arizona Won’t Be the Last Place to Micromanage Robocars As self-driving tech changes life on the street, expect lots of cities and states to write their own rules. They’ve done it before. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-self-driving-crash-arizona-suspend-testing-ducey-governor/

March 25, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Forget Self Driving. The Future is in Self Parking Companies are already testing systems like collaborative parking, remote-control summoning, and special picker-upper robots. https://www.wired.com/story/self-parking-cars/

March 23, 2018 | Author: Aarian Marshall, Alex DaviesAarian Marshall and Alex Davies This Week in the Future of Cars: A Fatal Uber Crash, and a Tempest of Questions Plus, we get our hands on the Model 3, Elon Musk gets a nice compensation package from Tesla, and all the other car news you missed this week. https://www.wired.com/story/this-week-fatal-uber-crash/

March 23, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Lose-Lose Ethics of Testing Self-Driving Cars in Public The true ethical dilemma with driverless cars isn’t the trolley problem—it’s whether we should be testing them on public streets at all. https://www.wired.com/story/lose-lose-ethics-self-driving-public/

March 22, 2018 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton As Pedestrian Deaths Spike, Scientists Scramble for Answers Researchers do have a culprit in mind—that thing in your hand. https://www.wired.com/story/pedestrian-death-rates-climb/

March 22, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla’s Model 3 Is the Best Electric Car You Can’t Buy—Yet Elon Musk’s car for the masses lives up to the hype. Now he just has to build the thing. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-model-3-review/

March 21, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber Video Shows the Kind of Crash Self-Driving Cars Are Made to Avoid And that the human safety driver was looking away from the road in the seconds leading up to the fatal impact. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-self-driving-crash-video-arizona/

March 19, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber’s Self-Driving Car Just Killed Somebody. Now What? The first deadly crash raises questions about how fast autonomous driving tech is progressing—and who’s in charge of keeping us safe. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-self-driving-car-crash-arizona-pedestrian/

March 16, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams New FAA Rules Take Aim at Dangerous Helicopter Flights The crash on Sunday that drowned five people could have been averted with rules that prevent open door flights with non-quick-release harnesses. https://www.wired.com/story/new-faa-rules-for-open-door-helicopter-flights/

March 16, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Ordinary Engineering Behind the Horrifying Florida Bridge Collapse The “quick build” process used to put up the span that fell and killed six people is actually quite common—and has been around for decades. https://www.wired.com/story/ordinary-engineering-florida-bridge-collapse/

March 16, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: The Time of Questioning Donald Trump and Elon Musk ponder tariffs, NYC thinks about traffic, and more. https://www.wired.com/story/trump-musk-nyc-congestion-charge-roundup/

March 16, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart My Day With the Zombies Who Help Airports Practice Plane Crashes To see how airports prep for disaster, I joined the volunteer zombie corps and boarded a plane bound for (faux) doom. https://www.wired.com/story/my-day-with-the-zombies-who-help-airports-practice-plane-crashes/

March 15, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall How Much Does It Cost to Unclog NYC’s Streets? In a city where some vehicles average 4.7 mph, a congestion charge may be the only way. That is, if it can fix the Uber problem. https://www.wired.com/story/cost-unclog-nyc-streets/

March 15, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Even More Evidence That Electric Cars Could Save the Planet The latest data says that in the US, electric cars are indeed cleaner than gas-powered ones—and the gap is widening. https://www.wired.com/story/even-more-evidence-that-electric-cars-could-save-the-planet/

March 14, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Lyft Strikes a Self-Driving Deal to Make Itself Everybody’s Best Bud The ride-hailing company is now working with auto industry supplier Magna to build a self-driving system any automaker can use. https://www.wired.com/story/lyft-magna-self-driving-system/

March 13, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Waymo Takes the Final Step Before Launching Its Self-Driving Car Service The company that started off as Google’s self-driving car project is now putting passengers in truly driverless cars in Phoenix—and will soon launch a commercial service. https://www.wired.com/story/waymo-self-driving-car-service-phoenix/

March 12, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Elon Musk’s and Donald Trump’s Twitter Tariff Tiff Real talk: Imposing tariffs and fees on the import and export of cars is unlikely to make things better. https://www.wired.com/story/musk-trump-twitter-tariff-tiff/

March 11, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart 7 Future-Revealing Details From the 2018 Geneva Motor Show Bugatti brings carbon fiber to the windshield, Mercedes ups its headlight game, and more. https://www.wired.com/gallery/geneva-motor-show-best-features-cars/

March 9, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Elon Musk’s Boring Company Is Now All About Public Transit, and It’s Confusing The Tesla and SpaceX CEO says his futuristic tunnel-based system will now prioritize people who don’t travel by car. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-boring-company-public-transit/

March 9, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Of Course Waymo Is Testing Self-Driving Trucks Google’s sister company just announced its plans to run its robo-rigs in Georgia. https://www.wired.com/2017/06/course-googles-waymo-building-self-driving-trucks/

March 9, 2018 | Author: Aarian Marshall, Alex DaviesAarian Marshall and Alex Davies This Week in the Future of Cars: The Robots Shoulder the Load Self-driving trucks make news in Arizona and Florida, plus highlights from the supercar-happy Geneva Motor Show. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-starsky-robotics-trucks-mclaren/

March 9, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Self-Driving Cars Meet Their New Nemesis: Local Politicians The mayor of San Francisco won’t be the last to try to exert control over this sweeping technological change. https://www.wired.com/story/san-francisco-self-driving-cars-rules-farrell/

March 8, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Dying to Know Uber’s Secrets, Data-Hungry Cities Get Creative Researchers want to know how ride-hailing companies are affecting their streets, but don’t have much information to help them. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-lyft-data-research-driver-pay/

March 8, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Starsky Robotics Unleashes Its Truly Driverless Truck in Florida The robo-trucking startup moves closer to starting commercial deliveries, no humans needed. https://www.wired.com/story/starsky-robotics-truck-self-driving-florida-test/

March 6, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Range Rover’s $295K Coupe SUV Proves No Niche Is Too Small The all-new Ranger Rover SV Coupe has two doors, costs a ton of money, and makes a surprising amount of sense. https://www.wired.com/story/range-rover-suv-sv-coupe-geneva/

March 6, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Volvo’s Polestar and Volkswagen Unveil New Rivals for Tesla At the ultra-flashy Geneva Motor Show, the revived Polestar, VW, and other automakers showed off cars they hope will let them dominate the growing electric car market. https://www.wired.com/story/volvos-polestar-and-volkswagen-unveil-new-rivals-for-tesla/

March 6, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Uber’s Self-Driving-Truck Scheme Hinges on Logistics, Not Tech And the ride-hailing giant is hard to beat when it comes to piling up data about where and when things go. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-self-driving-truck-scheme-logistics-testing/

March 6, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Is Supersonic Passenger Flight Set For a Comeback? The return of faster-than-sound flight could soon be a reality. https://www.wired.com/amp-stories/supersonic-flight/

March 4, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Inside the Million-Dollar Senna, McLaren’s Fiercest Road Car Ever The British automaker’s latest supercar is all about function—and fun—over form. https://www.wired.com/story/mclaren-senna-supercar-geneva/

March 3, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Drones Help Bring Back Electricity in Puerto Rico As the island struggles to come back online after Hurricane Maria, commercial quadcopters do the job quickly and safely. https://www.wired.com/story/drones-electricity-puerto-rico/

March 2, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Exhilarating Art of Landing Planes in Crazy Crosswinds What looks terrifying from the cabin is more like a bit of fun for pilots who know how to crab and slip. https://www.wired.com/story/plane-landing-crosswinds/

March 2, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Building the Bones Jaguar’s electric I-Pace, Porsche’s supercharging network, Ford’s self-driving tests in Miami, and more news from an auto industry trying to rebuild. https://www.wired.com/story/this-week-in-the-future-of-cars-building-the-bones/

March 1, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Jaguar’s New Electric SUV Aims to End Tesla’s Luxury EV Monopoly The I-Pace, set to enter production later this year, brings fresh design to a segment long dominated by Elon Musk. https://www.wired.com/story/jaguars-new-electric-suv-aims-to-end-teslas-ev-monopoly/

March 1, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies GM One-Ups Ford With a Carbon-Fiber-Loaded Sierra Pickup Truck The 2019 GMC Sierra Denali comes with a host of fancy features, including a bed made of carbon fiber. https://www.wired.com/story/gmc-sierra-denali-carbon-fiber-pickup-truck-bed/

February 28, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Porsche’s Tesla-Fighting Electric Sports Car Gets Its Own Supercharger Network The Mission E sports car will be able to charge its battery using a network of 800-volt fast chargers Porsche is installing around the country. https://www.wired.com/story/porsche-mission-e-sports-car-charging-network/

February 28, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Volvo Launches a VC Fund to Invest Its Way Into the Future Eager for fresh ideas in a rapidly changing industry, Volvo joins the many automakers writing big checks for little startups. https://www.wired.com/story/volvo-vc-fund-cars-tech-startups/

February 28, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Ride-Hailing Business Is Now Way Bigger Than Uber and Lyft The ride-hailing game isn’t just big, it’s important—which is why companies like Sony and Bosch are joining the fray. https://www.wired.com/story/ride-hailing-business-uber-lyft-sony-bosch/

February 27, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Ford’s Miami Self-Driving Cars Will Tackle the Tricky Bits The Detroit carmaker is set to start testing driverless cars in Florida, with a new maintenance depot to help it figure out how to actually operate robotaxi fleets. https://www.wired.com/story/ford-miami-self-driving-cars/

February 27, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Hyundai’s Self-Driving Car Masters the Oh-So-Human Roundabout Traffic circles are a nasty problem for robotic drivers, and Hyundai thinks it has found a solution. https://www.wired.com/story/hyundai-nexo-hydrogen-fuel-cell-self-driving/

February 26, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Fully Self-Driving Cars Are Really Truly Coming to California Cars without people inside could hit public streets by April 2. https://www.wired.com/story/california-self-driving-car-laws/

February 24, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Engineering Challenge of Giving Formula 1 Cars Halos These potentially life-saving bands of titanium come with a handful of fresh potential problems. https://www.wired.com/story/formula-1-f1-cars-halo/

February 23, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Doomsday L Train Shutdown Just Might Save NYC A comprehensive plan to give L train riders new ways to move could offer long lasting benefits to a growing city. https://www.wired.com/story/nyc-l-train-shutdown-plan/

February 23, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: There’s Gold in Them Thar Data Uber’s new Express Pool service, General Motors’ sweet Super Cruise feature, and more car news you missed this week. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-express-pool-cadillac-super-cruise-week-car-news/

February 23, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Inside the Command Center Keeping the Winter Olympics Safe In a windowless room in Seoul, dozens of security experts practiced—and now watch—for the worst. https://www.wired.com/story/winter-olympics-security-command-center-korea/

February 22, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Airlines Won’t Dare Use the Fastest Way to Board Planes United’s latest experiment with the boarding procedure could make things better—but it’s no revolution. https://www.wired.com/story/united-airlines-boarding-process-fastest/

February 22, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Electric Bikes Want to Take On Everyone—Even Uber If Uber doesn’t take them over first. https://www.wired.com/story/shared-electric-bikes-take-on-everyone/

February 21, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber Launches Express Pool to Conquer the Commute The company’s bid to see more of its occasional users could threaten public transit. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-express-pool-cities-launch/

February 20, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Laser Maps Behind Cadillac’s Superb Self-Driving Skills Super Cruise—Cadillac’s answer to Tesla Autopilot—uses a massive mapping database to rein in badly behaving drivers. https://www.wired.com/story/cadillac-super-cruise-ct6-lidar-laser-maps/

February 19, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Looking for a Smart City? Grab Your Skis Why the Winter Olympics should inspire more than your next vacation. https://www.wired.com/story/smart-city-ski-resorts/

February 17, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Airport Traffic Controllers Trade the Tower for a Screen-Stuffed Cave At the newly expanded Fort Lauderdale airport in Florida, ground traffic controllers watch their planes through radar and video, not line-of-sight. https://www.wired.com/story/airport-traffic-controllers-trade-the-tower-for-a-screen-stuffed-cave/

February 16, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: The Titans Start Talking Trump’s infrastructure plan, Tesla Model 3 struggles, and more car news you missed this week. https://www.wired.com/story/trump-infrastructure-tesla-model-3-gm-maven/

February 15, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Before They Can Take Off, Flying Cars Must Defeat Bureaucracy For aircraft like Airbus’ Vahana, the FAA’s outdated rules pose a more serious threat than gravity. https://www.wired.com/story/airbus-vahana-first-flight-faa-certification-flying-cars/

February 15, 2018 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton Amtrak Survived Richard Nixon—Can It Overcome Donald Trump? The latest budget proposal halves the federal government’s Amtrak commitment—including funding for a safer braking system. https://www.wired.com/story/trump-budget-amtrak-nixon/

February 14, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Trump’s Infrastructure Plan Threatens to Leave Little Cities Behind The White House’s proposal might work for wealthier urban areas, but offers little help for cash-poor locales. https://www.wired.com/story/trump-infrastructure-plan-leave-little-cities/

February 14, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart As Electric Cars Surge, the Gas Engine Keeps Getting Better After more than a century of improvements, engineers say the internal combustion engine is far from ready for retirement. https://www.wired.com/story/internal-combustion-engine-technology-argonne/

February 13, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Car-Sharing Company That Could Save GM Expands to Canada Maven isn’t just a way to rent Chevy Malibus by the hour. It’s a way to gain crucial logistics and fleet experience as the world shifts away from private car ownership. https://www.wired.com/story/gm-maven-toronto/

February 11, 2018 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton To Save Our Infrastructure, Make Every Road a Toll Road The gas tax is bad, and there’s a better way forward. https://www.wired.com/story/gas-tax-vmt-toll-road/

February 9, 2018 | Author: Aarian Marshall, Alex DaviesAarian Marshall and Alex Davies The End of Waymo v. Uber Marks a New Era for Self-Driving Cars: Reality The lawsuit encapsulated the way this industry used to work, and its end signals a shift into the future. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-waymo-trial-settlement-self-driving-cars/

February 9, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber and Waymo Abruptly Settle For $245 Million After a heated few days in court, Uber and Waymo have agreed to a truce—one that gives Google an added stake in its autonomous vehicle rival. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-waymo-lawsuit-settlement/

February 9, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies This Week in the Future of Cars: The Struggle Is Real Waymo v. Uber, Tesla’s Model 3 struggles, a robocar gets slapped, and more from the raging riot that is the car world. https://www.wired.com/story/waymo-uber-tesla-news-roundup/

February 8, 2018 | Author: Marc Scribner Marc Scribner Outdated Auto Safety Regulations Threaten the Self-Driving Revolution Opinion: Modernizing car safety rules will foster innovation and possibly save tens of thousands of lives every year. Congress just needs to make it happen. https://www.wired.com/story/outdated-auto-safety-regulations-threaten-the-self-driving-revolution/

February 7, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall With Deleted Messages, Waymo v Uber Is Looking a Little More Spy vs. Spy A calm Travis Kalanick waves away suspicious communications, and Waymo hasn’t quite connected the dots. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-waymo-self-driving-trial-day-3-kalanick/

February 7, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla Burns More Money Than Ever as Model 3 Production Crawls Along But CEO Elon Musk is as optimistic as ever that the problems are only temporary. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-model-3-production-problems-elon-musk-feb-2018/

February 7, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Get Rich So You Can Fly in a V-22 Osprey-Inspired Private Plane Leonardo’s AW609 is a VTOL aircraft meant for the civilian market. https://www.wired.com/story/leonardo-aw609-tilt-rotor/

February 7, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers A Bid to Solve California’s Housing Crisis Could Redraw How Cities Grow California State Senator Scott Wiener is pushing a bill that would rejigger zoning laws—and fight climate change, reduce traffic, and build a new urban future https://www.wired.com/story/scott-weiner-california-housing-bill-cities/

February 6, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Waymo v. Uber’s Big Question: What on Earth Is a Trade Secret, Anyway? Plus, a well-hydrated former Uber CEO Travis Kalanick takes the stand. https://www.wired.com/story/waymo-uber-trial-kalanick-testimony/

February 6, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies What Is Lidar, Why Do Self-Driving Cars Need It, and Can It See Nerf Bullets? Laser-shooting sensors are a key component of self-driving cars. But we can also use them to defeat our enemies. https://www.wired.com/story/lidar-self-driving-cars-luminar-video/

February 6, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Self-Driving Cars Use Crazy Amounts of Power, and It’s Becoming a Problem All those computers and sensors can hurt fuel economy and range, practical problems for commercial systems. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-cars-power-consumption-nvidia-chip/

February 5, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Waymo v. Uber Kicks Off With Travis Kalanick in the Crosshairs As the blockbuster legal fight goes to trial, Waymo makes clear who it wants to paint as the big baddie. https://www.wired.com/story/waymo-uber-trial-kalanick-day-one/

February 5, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Byton and Aurora Are Building a Self-Driving Electric SUV The Chinese automaker and the star-studded self-driving startup have joined forces. https://www.wired.com/story/aurora-byton-self-driving-electric-suv/

February 5, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies DMV Data Says Waymo and GM Are Leading the Self-Driving Car Race The numbers we have are a little jumbly, but they’re the best we’ve got—and they do tell an interesting story. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-cars-disengagement-reports/

February 3, 2018 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton Electric Cars Could Destroy the Electric Grid—or Fix It Forever A major uptick in driving on batteries will stress today’s aging grid, but also offer an opportunity to make it way better. https://www.wired.com/story/electric-cars-impact-electric-grid/

February 2, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Shortcuts The video game-style secrets to self-driving cars, Waymo and Uber face off, and more car news from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/roundup-shortcuts/

February 2, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart How NASA Tests Shapeshifting Plane Wings Shape memory alloys could make plane wings that flap, to reduce drag, or increase stability in supersonic flight. https://www.wired.com/story/how-nasa-tests-shapeshifting-plane-wings/

February 1, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Alphabet’s Sidewalk Labs Launches a Platform for Making the City of Tomorrow Meet Coord, (yet another) “operating system” for the age of urban mobility. https://www.wired.com/story/alphabet-sidewalk-labs-coord-city-of-tomorrow/

February 1, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The WIRED Guide to Hyperloop Everything you ever wanted to know about Elon Musk’s fever-dream train-in-a-tube. https://www.wired.com/story/guide-hyperloop/

February 1, 2018 | Author: David PierceDavid Pierce The WIRED Guide to Drones These tiny flyers are going to fill the skies, transforming entire industries for the better—and worse. https://www.wired.com/story/guide-drones/

February 1, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart 10 Commandments for Making Future Cities More Livable A collection of 15 mobility tech companies, like Uber and Zipcar, have signed up to a plan to make cities nicer places to live, with fewer private cars. https://www.wired.com/story/10-commandments-for-making-future-cities-more-livable/

February 1, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Greed, Ambition, and Trade Secrets: Welcome to Waymo v. Uber Why you should pay attention to this tech showdown, no matter who you are. https://www.wired.com/story/waymo-uber-self-driving-car-trial-preview/

February 1, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Self-Driving Cars Have a Secret Weapon: Remote Control Autonomous vehicles will drive themselves. Until the world around them gets weird and they freeze up. Then friendly, overlord humans will step in. https://www.wired.com/story/phantom-teleops/

January 31, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Turns Out Uber and Lyft Might Not Be Ruining the American City New research suggests the relationship between ride-hailing services, public transit, and traffic is more complicated than you might think. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-lyft-not-ruining-cities/

January 30, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The Security Savants Protecting the Winter Olympics You may not know the Diplomatic Security Service, but you’ll be glad its agents started preparing for these Games years ago. https://www.wired.com/story/winter-olympics-security/

January 30, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Nuro’s Self-Driving R-1 Doesn’t Drive You—It Drives Your Stuff The autonomous vehicle startup has impressive founders and a clever business model. https://www.wired.com/story/nura-ai-startup-self-driving/

January 30, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Waymo Launches Its Self-Driving Armada The Alphabet spinoff is in a rush, so it’s buying thousands more “driverless” cars from Fiat-Chrysler. https://www.wired.com/story/waymo-launches-self-driving-minivans-fiat-chrysler/

January 27, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Beguiling Science of Making Planet-Saving Pavement Turns out it’s not so easy to improve the way we produce the stuff beneath our feet. https://www.wired.com/story/pavement-environment-science/

January 26, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Ford Paves a Path From Big Automaker to Big Operating System With a reorganization and two acquisitions, a hazy vision of Ford as a transportation operating system starts to take shape. https://www.wired.com/story/ford-future-operating-system/

January 26, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week In the Future of Cars: Is This What a Hangover Feels Like? Tesla Autopilot crashes, Elon Musk’s $0 salary, details form Uber’s secretive Strategic Services Group, and more slightly catastrophic news from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-crashes-musk-money-more/

January 25, 2018 | Author: Mark HarrisMark Harris The Tricks and Travails of Uber’s Self-Driving Car Spies The embattled company’s Strategic Services Group spills its secrets in court. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-waymo-self-driving-car-ssg/

January 24, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart People Keep Confusing Their Teslas for Self-Driving Cars Another Tesla crash and a DUI remind us that Autopilot and similar systems can be very confusing—and that it’s becoming a problem. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-autopilot-crash-dui/

January 24, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Elon Musk’s $0 Salary Encapsulates the Legend of Tesla In a rapidly changing world, Musk’s combination of prescience, persuasion, and a taste for challenges makes him feel like a good bet. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-salary/

January 23, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Riding a Wild Wind, Transatlantic Jets Fly Faster Than Ever A 200-mph jet stream has sent several passenger jets to nearly 800 mph and helped break a (subsonic) speed record. https://www.wired.com/story/norwegian-air-transatlantic-speed-record/

January 23, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Elon Musk Wants to Dig Another Tunnel Under LA At a city council meeting, Musk’s Boring Company made its case for what could be the future of transportation. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-boring-company-culver-city/

January 21, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart As Cars Go Robo, Their Makers Find New Partners When Aptiv teams up with BMW, it’s like “Intel Inside” but for self-driving cars. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-cars-ces-2018/

January 20, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Potential Pitfalls of Electric Cars, in 5 Charts EVs could save the planet, but only if we understand their full impact—from mines in the DRC to fossil fuels in Kansas. https://www.wired.com/story/the-potential-pitfalls-of-electric-cars-in-5-charts/

January 19, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: TFW the Future Isn’t Here Yet News from CES and the Detroit Auto Show, plus Texas Instruments’ latest headlight experiments. https://www.wired.com/story/ces-detroit-auto-show-news-cars/

January 19, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Thank the Planet’s Shifty Magnetic Poles for Runway Renaming Magnetic north changes by as much as 40 miles per year, and that means signage updates. https://www.wired.com/story/airports-rename-runways-magnetic-shift/

January 18, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart What We’ve Already Learned About the Future of Cars in 2018 Both CES and the Detroit Auto Show happen early in the year, and give plenty of hints for what lies ahead. https://www.wired.com/story/what-weve-already-learned-about-the-future-of-cars-in-2018/

January 18, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The World’s Biggest Jet Engine Is About to Get a Blast of Ice When temperatures drop below -6 degrees F, engineers in Manitoba will bring the freeze to the GE9X. https://www.wired.com/story/testing-boeings-new-engine/

January 17, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Nissan Wants to Help You Drive by Reading Your Mind Just put on this goofy helmet, and the car could know what you’ll do before you do it. https://www.wired.com/story/nissan-brain-wave-project/

January 17, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Ford Finally Makes Its Move Into Electric Cars The Detroit automaker will invest $11 billion to rival General Motors—and protect its place in the global market. https://www.wired.com/story/ford-electric-cars-plan-mach-1-suv/

January 15, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Brilliant New Headlights Use a Million Pixels to Talk to the World Too bad federal regulations won’t allow Texas Instruments’ cool tech on American roads. https://www.wired.com/story/texas-instruments-headlights/

January 14, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Boeing’s Experimental Cargo Drone Is a Heavy Lifter Eventually, it should be able to fly as far as 20 miles, carrying 500 pounds (or 400 large Domino’s pizzas). https://www.wired.com/story/boeing-delivery-drone/

January 13, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Deep in the Desert, the Hyperloop Comes to Life Virgin Hyperloop One wants to launch a commercial hyperloop in 2021, and it’s got work to do. https://www.wired.com/story/virgin-hyperloop-one-engineering/

January 12, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Everything Happens At Once Like, all of it. Fresh from CES, news from Chinese electric vehicle-maker Byton, Toyota, Uber, and Bell Helicopters. https://www.wired.com/story/gm-driverless-toyota-e-palette-byton-ev/

January 12, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies GM Will Launch Robocars Without Steering Wheels Next Year Now the automaker must prepare for the age of the truly driverless car. https://www.wired.com/story/gm-cruise-self-driving-car-launch-2019/

January 10, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Inside the 4-Day Disaster that Nearly Broke JFK Airport The bad weather was bad enough to trigger cascade of effects through a system that’s in delicate equilibrium at the best of times. https://www.wired.com/story/jfk-bomb-cyclone-mess/

January 10, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Climb Inside Bell’s (Theoretical) Flying Taxi of the Future At CES2018, Bell Helicopter showed off its idea of how a flying taxi system might work—so we climbed aboard. https://www.wired.com/story/bell-flying-car-concept-ces-video/

January 9, 2018 | Author: Patrick FarrellPatrick Farrell Why One Dude Has Spent Years Building a Boeing 777 Out of Paper It might not fly, but this designer’s ultimate paper plane does have retractable landing gear and more than 300 tiny seats. https://www.wired.com/story/why-one-dude-has-spent-years-building-a-boeing-777-out-of-paper/

January 8, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Toyota Joins With Uber and Amazon to Find Its Self-Driving Future The journey starts with a shape-shifting electric vehicle called the e-Palette. https://www.wired.com/story/toyota-self-driving-epalette-uber-amazon-pizza-hut/

January 8, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla’s Latest Chinese Competitor Takes Screens to an Extreme The new electric car concept is heavy on flash, but has substance under the skin. https://www.wired.com/story/byton-tesla-latest-chinese-competitor-takes-screens-to-an-extreme/

January 7, 2018 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Wanna Master the Crafty Aerodynamics of a Humongous Telescope? Call Boeing. To design what will be the world’s largest optical telescope, some ambitious astronomers turned to Boeing for help. https://www.wired.com/story/how-boeing-helped-design-giant-magellan-telescope/

January 6, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Mazda’s Idea to Make Driving Fun Again Could Keep Us Safe A new approach to distracted driving is the sort of thinking we’ll need more of as driving gets more and more complicated. https://www.wired.com/story/mazda-distracted-driving-patent/

January 5, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: On Your Mark, Get Set… 2018 opens with big news from Tesla, Aurora, Volkswagen, and Hyundai—while we prep for CES. https://www.wired.com/story/aurora-volkswagen-tesla-news/

January 5, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart McLaren’s New 570S Convertible Makes Luxury (Kinda) Practical McLaren claims you can have your cake, and eat it too—if you can eat cake while the wind blasts you at triple-digit speeds. https://www.wired.com/story/mclaren-570s-spider-convertible/

January 4, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall An Open Source Startup Dies as Mapping Gets Hotter Than Ever The death of four-year-old Mapzen can’t cool down the blazing hot mapping space. https://www.wired.com/story/mapzen-shuts-down/

January 4, 2018 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies America’s Hottest Self-Driving Startup Hooks Up with VW and Hyundai Aurora, founded by a trio of robocar superstars, makes a big move toward commercialization. https://www.wired.com/story/aurora-urmson-volkswagen-hyundai/

January 3, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla Delays Its Model 3 Production Goals—Again But things are getting better, CEO Elon Musk swears. https://www.wired.com/story/musk-model-3-tesla-production-delays-january/

January 3, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Students Redesign Ford’s Iconic F-150 for the Future of Driving Three students have won a design competition by rethinking how America’s best-selling vehicle should adapt to advances such as electric propulsion. https://www.wired.com/story/ford-f150-pickup-student-redesign/

January 1, 2018 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The American City Survival Guide (World of Mobility Edition) A guide to making the shifting world of mobility work for everyone. https://www.wired.com/story/american-city-survival-guide/

December 31, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The World’s Fair Future of 1939 and the Quest for Our Next Utopia What the famed Futurama tells us about how to get where we’re going next. https://www.wired.com/story/worlds-fair-1939-futurama-utopia/

December 29, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall After Peak Hype, Self-Driving Cars Enter the Trough of Disillusionment Before they can change the world, driverless vehicles face a gauntlet of practical challenges. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-cars-challenges/

December 28, 2017 | Author: Andrea ValdezAndrea Valdez The Most-Read WIRED Transportation Stories of 2017 Elon Musk creations Tesla and hyperloop dominated the news cycle. https://www.wired.com/story/most-read-wired-transportation-stories-2017/

December 28, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Uber May Be Aflame, But Its Self-Driving Cars Are Getting Good Trouble abounds for the ridehailing company, but a trip to Pittsburgh reveals it’s making real progress toward driverless cars. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-self-driving-cars-pittsburgh/

December 27, 2017 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton Investigating the Mysteriously Feel-Good Texas Turnaround This sublimely forgiving bit of infrastructure is all over the Lone Star State—but why? https://www.wired.com/story/texas-turnaround-intersection/

December 26, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart At Last, the Age of the Electric Car Really Arrives National governments are done with gas and automakers are catching on. Welcome to the electric age. https://www.wired.com/story/2018-year-electric-car-video/

December 24, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Elon Musk’s Christmas Letter (Tesla Sure Is Growing Up Fast) A year in the life, from the man himself. Maybe. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-christmas-letter-satire/

December 23, 2017 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton Fixing America’s Holiday Travel Mess Might Just Ruin America How to build a transportation system that handles peak demand—and why you really really shouldn’t. https://www.wired.com/story/holiday-travel-infrastructure/

December 22, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Exploring the Factory Where Honda Builds the Private Jet of the Future We get a look at how humble Honda puts these little birds together. https://www.wired.com/story/hondajet-factory-assembly/

December 22, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Naughty or Nice? A new Jeep Wrangler, VW’s electric hippie bus, Uber’s never-ending legal hole, and more car news from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/jeep-uber-vw-roundup/

December 21, 2017 | Author: Meredith Rutland BauerMeredith Rutland Bauer The Race to Build the Hyperloop Could Fix Boring Old Planes and Trains The efforts to deliver Elon Musk’s tubular travel system are already creating solutions that could make other forms of transit faster and comfier. https://www.wired.com/story/hyperloop-spinoff-technology/

December 21, 2017 | None The Tech That’s Going to Make Air Travel Less Awful From a de-icing timing app to laser beams, these innovations will make your experience (a little bit) better https://www.wired.com/story/new-airport-tech/

December 20, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart 7 Swanky Gift Ideas for Your Favorite Auto Enthusiast Ideas for the car nerd in your life (or yourself), even if you’ve left your shopping to the last minute. https://www.wired.com/2017/12/7-swanky-gift-ideas-for-your-favorite-auto-enthusiast/

December 20, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart VW Rolls Down Electric Avenue With a Battery-Powered Microbus Shaking off the dirty diesel scandal, the German automaker is going electric as Bob Dylan at Newport with a throwback microbus concept and two other e-vehicles. https://www.wired.com/story/vw-microbus-electric-bus-video/

December 20, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The 37-Page Letter That Could Make Uber’s Problems So Much Worse How the Jacobs Letter could buoy all the federal investigations and lawsuits facing Uber right now. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-waymo-jacobs-letter/

December 20, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart 7 Swanky Gift Ideas for Your Favorite Auto Enthusiast Ideas for the car nerd in your life (or yourself), even if you’ve left your shopping to the last minute. https://www.wired.com/2017/12/7-swanky-gift-ideas-favorite-auto-enthusiast/

December 18, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies With a Whoosh, the Hyperloop Sets a New Speed Record Virgin Hyperloop One just clocked 240 mph, at its Nevada test track, putting Elon Musk in second place. https://www.wired.com/story/hyperloop-speed-record-video/

December 18, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The V-22 Osprey-Inspired Aircraft Takes Off for the First Time The Bell V-280 Valor could be the new way of getting to and from the battlefield. https://www.wired.com/story/bell-v280-valor-tiltrotor-test/

December 18, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart After a Massive Blackout, Atlanta’s Airport Faces a Logistical Nightmare The 11-hour power outage canceled more than a thousand flights; now airlines have to solve the strategic Rubik’s cube of getting everything running again. https://www.wired.com/story/atlanta-airport-blackout-flights/

December 17, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Jeep’s New Wrangler Gives Off-Roadies Everything They Want This is more than a refresh. It’s a demonstration of how all automakers should think about their cars. https://www.wired.com/story/jeep-wrangler-2018/

December 15, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall New Evidence Could Blow Open the Uber/Waymo Self-Driving Lawsuit And boy do we have questions. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-waymo-lawsuit-jacobs-letter/

December 15, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: The One About Necessity and the Mother of Invention The Ford GT supercar’s amazing new engine, Waze’s mapping problem in the Palestinian territories, McLaren’s spin on minimalism, and more car news from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/mclaren-senna-ford-gt-roundup/

December 15, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Inside Ford’s Quest to Build a New Kind of Supercar Engine When Ford decided to resurrect its famed GT supercar, it needed more than a new design. It needed a new kind of power. https://www.wired.com/story/ford-gt-supercar-engine/

December 14, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Elon Musk Reveals His Awkward Dislike of Mass Transit The man trying to build tunnels around the country is awfully unimpressed by the basic concept of shared, public transportation. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-awkward-dislike-mass-transit/

December 12, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Million-Dollar Minimalism of McLaren’s Senna Supercar You don’t get much car for your money, and that’s exactly the point. https://www.wired.com/story/mclaren-senna-supercar/

December 11, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart How to Fight the California Wildfires With a Boeing 747 Jumbo Jet The Global Supertanker is a modified Boeing 747 that drops mass quantities of fire retardant from just 200 feet above the ground. https://www.wired.com/story/southern-california-thomas-wildfire-boeing-747-global-supertanker/

December 10, 2017 | Author: Miriam BergerMiriam Berger When Waze Won’t Help, Palestinians Make Their Own Maps In a place and conflict where “facts on the ground” are endlessly contested, having access to good navigation maps and apps is more than a matter of getting there. https://www.wired.com/story/palestine-jerusalem-mapping/

December 9, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Virginia’s $40 Toll Road Better Be the Future of Driving A Virginia experiment with congestion pricing encounters speed bumps—but don’t freak out yet. https://www.wired.com/story/virginia-i66-toll-road/

December 8, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Drones Take Off in the Battle Against the Los Angeles Fires As the flames spread, the LA Fire Department tries out a new tool. https://www.wired.com/story/drones-take-off-in-the-battle-against-the-los-angeles-fires/

December 8, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: You Get What You Pay For San Francisco changes parking prices, Virginia raises tolls, and Americans start to realize how much driving really costs. https://www.wired.com/story/jaguar-i-pace-tesla-corvette-car-news/

December 7, 2017 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Checkpoints, IMAX, and Waterfalls: The Airport’s Terminal Identity Crisis Make airports somewhere again. https://www.wired.com/story/airport-design-identity-crisis/

December 6, 2017 | Author: Zachary KarabellZachary Karabell Saudi Prince Plans a ‘City of the Future.’ Don’t Bet on It The checkered history of planned cities doesn’t augur well for Saudi Arabia’s Neom. https://www.wired.com/story/saudi-prince-plans-a-city-of-the-future-dont-bet-on-it/

December 5, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart An Inside Look at Jaguar’s Bold, All-Electric I-Pace The company is starting final testing on the machine it hopes will beat Tesla and Audi, and lead the all-electric pack. https://www.wired.com/story/jaguar-electric-suv/

December 5, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart LA Auto Show Report: 9 Future-y Features Hitting the Road Driving isn’t necessarily all about being behind the wheel any more. https://www.wired.com/dummy-uri-2017/12/la-auto-show-report-futuristic-features-coming-to-cars-asap/

December 5, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart LA Auto Show Report: 9 Futuristic Features Hitting the Road Driving isn’t necessarily all about being behind the wheel any more. https://www.wired.com/2017/12/la-auto-show-report-futuristic-features-coming-to-cars-asap/

December 3, 2017 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton These Shapeshifting Metals Could Be the Future of Flight They’re lighter (and weirder) than conventional metals, and they could help airlines save on gas—and go supersonic. https://www.wired.com/story/shape-memory-alloys/

December 2, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall San Francisco’s Plan to Adjust Parking Prices Based on Demand Depending on the time of day, your meter could charge you anywhere between 50 cents and $8. https://www.wired.com/story/san-francisco-adjustable-meters/

December 1, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Speed Bumps A ride in General Motors’ safety-first autonomous vehicle, bombshell evidence in the Uber-Waymo trade secrets lawsuit, a new Infiniti revealed, and more car news from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-waymo-gm-infiniti-lucid/

December 1, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Latest Tesla Challenger Takes on the Auto Industry With a Stunning Electric Sedan “Automotive” and “startup” tend to mix poorly, but Silicon Valley–based Lucid believes it has the tools to succeed. https://www.wired.com/story/lucid-tesla-wannabe-electric-sedan/

November 30, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams You Can Finally Drive Off With Infiniti’s Crafty New Engine The redesigned QX50 crossover is the first car you can buy with a very clever variable compression engine. https://www.wired.com/story/infiniti-qx50-variable-compression-engine-nissan/

November 30, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams You’ll Love Taking Jeep’s Crazy Capable Wrangler to the Mall The latest version of the famed off-roader comes with upgraded performance, along with creature comforts. https://www.wired.com/story/jeep-wrangler-new/

November 30, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Uber-Waymo Lawsuit Gets a New Star—and Takes a Wild Turn Ric Jacobs might have been a whistle-blower. The ride-hailing giant portrays him as an extortionist. The judge remains cranky. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-waymo-richard-jacobs-lawsuit/

November 29, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall My Herky-Jerky Ride in General Motors’ Ultra-Cautious Self Driving Car GM and Cruise are testing vehicles in a chaotic city, and the tech still has a ways to go. https://www.wired.com/story/ride-general-motors-self-driving-car/

November 29, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart American Airlines’ Computer Glitch Leaves It Without Pilots Over Christmas The airline was accidentally too generous with time off over the holidays. https://www.wired.com/story/american-airlines-computer-glitch-leaves-it-without-pilots-over-christmas/

November 28, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Hidden Evidence Could Crack Open the Uber-Waymo Self-Driving Car Fight New evidence reveals that Uber had failed to disclose potentially vital evidence in its legal fight with Waymo. https://www.wired.com/story/hidden-evidence-uber-waymo-self-driving-car/

November 28, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams US Fighter Jets Are Getting the Laser Cannons They’ve Always Deserved Lockheed Martin won the $26 million contract to develop a laser system that can protect fighters from incoming missiles. https://www.wired.com/story/lockheed-martin-fighter-jets-lasers/

November 25, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Squeezed for Space, Hong Kong Converts Caverns into Real Estate In the ultra-crowded city, caverns could offer room for things like waste management and treatment, data storage, parking, and slaughterhouses. https://www.wired.com/story/hong-kong-caverns-real-estate/

November 24, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies So, BMW Wants to Build Networks of Elevated Cycling Paths The automaker has a grand vision for making cities less congested, without getting rid of all those ultimate driving machines on the ground. https://www.wired.com/story/bmw-elevated-bike-cyclist-paths-concept/

November 23, 2017 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton Why Can’t America Have a Single Tolling System? Because Bureaucracy The country’s toll operators were supposed to be running on a single national system more than a year ago. https://www.wired.com/story/national-tolling-system/

November 22, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall To See the Future of Cities, Watch the Curb. Yes, the Curb The battle for this often ignored slice of street has only just begun. https://www.wired.com/story/city-planning-curbs/

November 22, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The TSA’s New Scanners Could Make Airport Security Way Less Horrible US airports are starting trials of new CT scanners that will let TSA agents virtually unpack bags, keeping everyone safe and on the move. https://www.wired.com/story/tsa-tests-ct-scanners-airport-security/

November 21, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Aston Martin’s New Vantage Is Its Smartest ‘Affordable’ Car Yet The $150,000 sports car offers 500 horsepower and a top speed near 200 mph. https://www.wired.com/story/aston-martin-vantage-new/

November 20, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Frequent Flier Miles Are Kaput—The Game’s About Credit Cards Now You may feel betrayed, but there’s still a way to score rewards in the air. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/frequent-flier-miles-kaput-games-credit-cards-now/

November 20, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Ahoy Travelers: These Are Your Rights When Airlines Screw Up The law provides privileges to keep you safe, comfortable, and sane as you battle your way home. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/ahoy-travelers-rights-airlines-screw/

November 20, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall MIT Looks at How Humans Sorta Drive in Sorta Self-Driving Cars Researchers are launching a gigantic study to see how people interact with assisted driving systems, like Tesla’s Autopilot. https://www.wired.com/story/mit-humans-semiautonomous-car-study/

November 19, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Exploring the High-Flying Spending Spree of the Dubai Airshow A look inside the show where the world’s aviation industry just spent $113.8 billion on new hardware. https://www.wired.com/story/dubai-airshow-photos/

November 18, 2017 | Author: Elizabeth Jameson, Catherine MonahonElizabeth Jameson and Catherine Monahon Self-Driving Car Tech Can Help Another Form of Transport: Wheelchairs Opinion: The technology exists and is even affordable. The primary obstacle is a lack of investment from the tech community. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-car-tech-can-help-another-form-of-transport-wheelchairs/

November 18, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Keep on Truckin’ Tesla introduces a new sports car and a self-driving truck, Lyft heads to Canada, GM talks electric profits, and more from this week in cars. https://www.wired.com/story/this-week-in-the-future-of-cars-keep-on-truckin/

November 17, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall What Does Tesla’s Automated Truck Mean for Truckers? Well, that kind of depends on what you mean by “trucker.” https://www.wired.com/story/what-does-teslas-truck-mean-for-truckers/

November 17, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Tesla Is Reviving the Roadster and It Looks Spectacular Elon Musk is promising the quickest car ever made. And it has 600 miles of range. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-new-roadster/

November 16, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Meet the Tesla Semitruck, Elon Musk’s Most Electrifying Gamble Yet The biggest piece yet in Musk’s plan to ditch fossil fuels forever has arrived. Sort of. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-truck-revealed/

November 16, 2017 | Author: WIRED StaffWIRED Staff Elon Musk Launches Tesla’s Electric Truck: Live Coverage We’re here live to meet Tesla’s newest electric vehicle: a battery-powered semitruck. https://www.wired.com/2017/11/elon-musk-launches-teslas-electric-truck-live-coverage/

November 16, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Littler Fire Engine That Could Make Cities Safer San Francisco’s Vision Zero truck can maneuver in tighter, slower pedestrian-friendly streets. https://www.wired.com/story/sanfrancisco-smaller-firetrucks/

November 16, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Everything We Know About the Truck Tesla Will Unveil Tonight Yes, it will probably run on batteries, but what is Elon Musk going to do about charging them? https://www.wired.com/story/what-we-know-about-the-tesla-truck/

November 15, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla’s Electric Truck Is Coming—And So Are Everyone Else’s Whether they use batteries, fuel cells, or turbine engines, cleaner, quieter big rigs are about to hit the road. https://www.wired.com/story/teslas-electric-truck-is-comingand-so-are-everyone-elses/

November 14, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Brogan BamBrogan Is Taking the Hyperloop to Colorado OK, it’s not really a hyperloop, but it will get you to the airport. https://www.wired.com/story/hyperloop-arrivo-denver-colorado-brogan-bambrogan/

November 13, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Self-Driving Trucks Are Now Delivering Refrigerators Today, a human driver rides in the cab, but the ultimate goal of this (auto) pilot program is to dump the fleshbag and let the trucks rumble solo down the highway. https://www.wired.com/story/embark-self-driving-truck-deliveries/

November 10, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Trial and Error Waymo drops the driver, Congress takes aim at electric cars, a history of the self-driving car, and more. https://www.wired.com/story/waymo-self-driving-car-darpa-grand-challenge-roundup/

November 10, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Self-Driving Shuttle Buses Might Be the Future of Transportation Ignore that crash in Las Vegas, and look to the long-term. https://www.wired.com/story/las-vegas-shuttle-crash-self-driving-autonomous/

November 10, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Inside the Races That Jump-Started the Self-Driving Car The Darpa Grand Challenges did more than drive the invention of autonomous vehicles—they fostered a community that now leads the industry. https://www.wired.com/story/darpa-grand-urban-challenge-self-driving-car/

November 9, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Uber’s Plan to Launch Flying Cars in LA by 2020 Really Could Take Off Somehow, this plan isn’t quite as insane as it sounds. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-flying-cars-los-angeles/

November 8, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Keanu Reeves’ Latest Excellent Adventure: Making Motorcycles The Matrix star has spent the past few years designing custom bikes that start around $80,000. https://www.wired.com/story/keanu-reeves-latest-excellent-adventure-making-motorcycles/

November 7, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Waymo Has Taken the Human Out of Its Self-Driving Cars And in just a few months, it will invite passengers to climb aboard. https://www.wired.com/story/waymo-google-arizona-phoenix-driverless-self-driving-cars/

November 7, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Crafty Engineering Lets Porsche’s Cayenne SUV Drive Like a 911 The new generation of the SUV Porsche that purists love to hate soaks up turns like the automaker’s sports cars. https://www.wired.com/story/new-porsche-cayenne-suv-engineering/

November 7, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart How to Engineer a Car that Goes 277.9 MPH Swedish supercar maker Koenigsegg just set a new world record, thanks to some very clever engineering. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-make-the-fastest-car-in-the-world/

November 7, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall To Save the Most Lives, Deploy (Imperfect) Self-Driving Cars ASAP A new report argues robots will kill fewer people than human drivers, even if the technology isn’t foolproof yet. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-cars-rand-report/

November 5, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Why These German Researchers Became Self-Driving Cars They really want humans and autonomous vehicles to be friends. https://www.wired.com/story/moovel-self-driving-car-experiment/

November 4, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Congress’ Plan to Kill the Electric Car Tax Credit Could Kill Electric Cars And maybe split America in two in the process. https://www.wired.com/story/congress-tax-reform-electric-car-tax-credit/

November 3, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Into the Chocolate Factory Tesla misses production targets, how Waymo tests self-driving cars, and more from the week in autos. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-model-3-waymo-castle-roundup/

November 1, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Who’s Ready to Put Their Kid on a Self-Driving School Bus? A provocative design concept asks questions about burgeoning tech. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-school-bus/

October 31, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Inside the Ersatz City Where Waymo Trains Its Self-Driving Cars And all the questions we still have about how the Googley self-driving car’s path to commercialization. https://www.wired.com/story/google-waymo-self-driving-car-castle-testing/

October 30, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall How to Design Streets for Humans—and Self-Driving Cars A new blueprint from city transportation planners and engineers, who say it’s never too early to start thinking about the future. https://www.wired.com/story/nacto-streets-self-driving-cars/

October 29, 2017 | Author: Kaveh WaddellKaveh Waddell Prepping Self-Driving Cars for the World’s Most Chaotic Cities If you think driving around Silicon Valley is tough, try making a robot that can navigate a Beirut traffic jam. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-cars-chaotic-cities-traffic/

October 28, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Crazy Cute Concept Cars From the Tokyo Auto Show Japanese designers are demonstrating their own brand of flair, with vehicles that are cute and cool. https://www.wired.com/story/crazy-cute-concept-cars-from-the-tokyo-auto-show/

October 27, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Rocket-Powered Car Trying to Hit 1,000 MPH Makes Its World Debut The Bloodhound SSC is a car-plane hybrid, designed to smash the land speed record. https://www.wired.com/story/the-rocket-powered-car-trying-to-hit-1000-mph-makes-its-world-debut/

October 27, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies This Week in the Future of Cars: The Feel Good Singalong GM tests self-driving cars in NYC, Tesla’s Autopilot troubles, LA asks Uber for help, and more car news from the past week. https://www.wired.com/story/nissan-ev-tesla-autopilot-future-cars-roundup/

October 27, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies It’s Totes Normal to Crave This $9,400 Bugatti Chiron Engine Replica If you can’t afford the car itself, why not treat yourself to a 1:4 scale copy of the engine that makes it go? https://www.wired.com/story/bugatti-chiron-engine-replica-amalagam/

October 27, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall To Let Self-Driving Cars Go Anywhere, Train Them Everywhere Waymo, Alphabet’s autonomous vehicle spinoff, starts testing in Michigan. https://www.wired.com/story/waymo-self-driving-michigan-testing/

October 26, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart President Trump Moves to Fill America’s Skies with Drones The president signed a memo directing the FAA to figure out how to get commercial UAVs into American skies. https://www.wired.com/story/faa-trump-drones-regulations/

October 26, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Electric Nissan Concept Car Sings to Save Lives It might sound like the warm-up room of an ’80s synth rock convention, but the feature is meant to warn walkers that a very quiet electric car is coming. https://www.wired.com/story/electric-nissan-canto-sings/

October 25, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart These Explosions Show Why the FAA Doesn’t Want Laptops in Luggage Videos of the air regulator’s experiments show how violent a battery fire can be. https://www.wired.com/story/these-explosions-show-why-the-faa-doesnt-want-laptops-in-luggage/

October 24, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall LA Looks to Rideshare to Build the Future of Public Transit Los Angeles Metro is looking for a private company to help it design and implement an experiment in on-demand service. https://www.wired.com/story/la-rideshare-public-transit/

October 23, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Zoom Through Seattle’s Massive Tunnel Before It Finally Opens for Service Now that Bertha’s done digging, the new underground highway is nearly ready for human travelers. https://www.wired.com/story/seattle-bertha-tunnel/

October 22, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart In New York, Self-Driving Cars Get Ready to Face the Bullies Robocars headed for Manhattan will have to learn some new tricks. So will New Yorkers. https://www.wired.com/story/gm-cruise-self-driving-cars-nyc-manhattan/

October 21, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Chariot Is Suspended in San Francisco, and the Transportation Biz Is Still Hard The Golden State yanks the van commuting service’s license after failing inspections. Expect more debacles to follow. https://www.wired.com/story/chariot-suspended-transportation-hard/

October 20, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: The Human Touch Autonomous vehicle researchers iron out the vagaries of people behavior, Alphabet builds a real city on data, and more car news from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/roundup-self-driving-volvo-electric/

October 20, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams America’s Future War Trucks Don’t Need No Stinking Windows Honeywell’s new system taps augmented reality to give operators a complete sense of their surroundings. https://www.wired.com/story/honeywell-darpa-ground-vehicle-windows/

October 20, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Airbus’ New Boeing-Fighting Jet Takes Off for the First Time Now that the A330-900neo has taken to the skies, it’s time for some brutal testing. https://www.wired.com/story/airbus-a330-900-neo/

October 19, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams To Survive the Streets, Robocars Must Learn to Think Like Humans Cracking the “freezing robot” problem requires a more human-like understanding of how the world works. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-cars-freezing-robot-problem/

October 19, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Alphabet Is Trying to Reinvent the City, Starting With Toronto Google sister company Sidewalk Labs announces a plan to remake the Toronto waterfront in its data-soaked image. https://www.wired.com/story/google-sidewalk-labs-toronto-quayside/

October 17, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Volvo Prepares to Take on Tesla with a Revamped Polestar Volvo had unveiled the Polestar 1, a carbon fiber-wrapped, sleek challenge to Elon Musk. https://www.wired.com/story/volvo-polestar-1-electric/

October 15, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart How Air France Will Rescue Its A380 With a Shattered Engine The plane will need an engine swap at the remote Canadian airport where it’s stranded. https://www.wired.com/story/how-air-france-will-rescue-its-a380-with-a-shattered-engine/

October 14, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber and Lyft Haven’t Revolutionized the American City—Yet New research suggests ride-hail companies have put more cars on the road. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-and-lyft-havent-revolutionized-cities/

October 13, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart It’s the 70th Anniversary of the First Supersonic Flight Chuck Yeager broke the sound barrier in the Bell X-1 on October 14th 1947. https://www.wired.com/story/its-the-70th-anniversary-of-the-first-supersonic-flight/

October 13, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Let’s Get This Driverless Thing Moving General Motors, the state of California, and even the US Postal Service say self-driving cars are happening. https://www.wired.com/story/this-week-in-cars-driverless-moving/

October 12, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall No One Knows What a Self-Driving Car Is, And It’s Becoming a Problem A new study shows consumers have no clue how different automated features now available work. https://www.wired.com/story/no-one-knows-self-driving-car/

October 11, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Humanity Gets a Laser-Shooting, Drone-Slaying Dune Buggy Raytheon’s latest, craziest invention could keep troops safe from drone attacks. https://www.wired.com/story/raytheon-drone-laser-dune-buggy/

October 10, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Watch an Ultra-Funky Heavy Lift Ship Pick Up a Navy Destroyer After a collision at sea, the USS John S McCain needed a ride home. https://www.wired.com/story/heavy-lift-ship-john-mccain-destroyer/

October 9, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The US Postal Service Is Building a Self-Driving Mail Truck With plans to get it running rural routes by 2025. https://www.wired.com/story/postal-service-office-self-driving-mail-trucks/

October 9, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies GM Buys a Lidar Startup That Could Deliver Its Self-Driving Future The automaker and its self-driving car outfit Cruise now own Strobe, which says it drops the cost of lidar 99 percent. https://www.wired.com/story/gm-cruise-strobe-lidar/

October 8, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Maybe It’s Time to Cede US Freeways to Driverless Cars Or the carpool lanes, at least. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-cars-take-over-highways/

October 7, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Cars Are Safer Than Ever—But Traffic Deaths Are Climbing Part of the blame lays with an improving economy. https://www.wired.com/story/traffic-deaths-rise-2016/

October 6, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Things Just Got Serious The big automakers promise an electric revolution, Uber has a rough day in court, Dyson starts making cars, and more. https://www.wired.com/story/gm-ford-electric-this-week/

October 6, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Lamborghini Wants Your Supercar to Teach You How to Really Drive This is how you use artificial intelligence for good. https://www.wired.com/story/lamborghini-artificial-intelligence-self-driving/

October 5, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Top 10 Startups Racing to Remake the Auto Industry The folks addressing the most vexing and important problems standing between us and the future of transportation. https://www.wired.com/story/top-auto-transportation-startups/

October 4, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Google May Not Need a Smoking Gun to Win Its Case Against Uber But a whiff of gun powder would be nice. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-waymo-google-self-driving-trial-evidence/

October 4, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Elon Musk Finally Gets the Melancholy Theme Song He Deserves Weezer’s old bassist Matt Sharp writes a melancholy fable about everyone’s favorite CEO. https://www.wired.com/2017/10/elon-musk-rentals-song/

October 3, 2017 | Author: Aarian Marshall, Fred VogelsteinAarian Marshall and Fred Vogelstein Uber Knew Its Self-Driving Guru Had Taken Google’s Trade Secrets, Report Says The blockbuster legal battle takes another wild turn. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-waymo-google-levandowski-lawsuit-stroz-report/

October 3, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The New Ford Mustang’s Chameleonic Dashboard of the Future The guages of the classic car get a new look. https://www.wired.com/story/the-new-ford-mustangs-chameleonic-dashboard-of-the-future/

October 3, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Tricks and Treats California Can Use to Banish Fossil Fuel Cars To make an all-electric age plausible, the state must get to work, stat. https://www.wired.com/story/california-ban-fossil-fuel-cars/

October 2, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies General Motors Is Going All Electric The giant automaker will start with 20 new all-electric models by 2023. https://www.wired.com/story/general-motors-electric-cars-plan-gm/

October 1, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Dyson’s Bid to Build an Electric Car Just Might Work The vacuum and fan maker has a real chance to earn its place in a changing auto industry. https://www.wired.com/story/dyson-electric-car/

October 1, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Where Are the Drones That Could Be Saving Puerto Rico? The technology exists. Now it’s time to put it into action. https://www.wired.com/story/puerto-rico-hurricane-drones/

September 29, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Elon Musk’s Rocket Travel Plan Is Def Possible, Def Bananas The SpaceX CEO’s latest inspiration could use some reining in. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-spacex-rocket-travel-plan/

September 29, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Human-Robocar War for Jobs Is Finally On And the humans just won the first skirmish. https://www.wired.com/story/trucks-robocar-senate-war/

September 29, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies This Week in the Future of Cars: The Kids Are on Fire Ford rethinks the F-150, Toyota gets a new lidar, London battles with Uber, and car news from the past week. https://www.wired.com/story/anthony-levandowsk-austin-russel-car-news/

September 28, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Ford’s Using Augmented Reality to Design Better Cars Using Microsoft HoloLens, the automaker’s begoggled designers can now quickly evaluate and alter new car models. https://www.wired.com/story/ford-design-microsoft-hololens/

September 27, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Electric Scooter Maker Hoping to Change the World Lands in Japan Gogoro, which aims to change how humans move and consume electricity, adds another country to its list of conquests. https://www.wired.com/story/gogoro-electric-scooters-japan/

September 27, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Toyota and a Boy Wonder Team Up on Self-Driving Cars The world’s biggest automaker is now using lidar laser sensors made by the hot new startup, Luminar. https://www.wired.com/story/toyota-luminar-lidar-self-driving-car/

September 27, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall London’s Power Play Proves Cities Can Fight Uber As London gives Uber the boot, other cities see a way to flex their own muscles. https://www.wired.com/story/london-uber-cities-power/

September 25, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Ford Turns to Students for the Future of Truck Design The company wants to challenge existing notions of what makes a good pickup. https://www.wired.com/story/ford-turns-to-students-for-the-future-of-truck-design/

September 23, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies To Save Its Skin in London, Uber Rallies the People The city is threatening to boot the ridehailing company, but Uber isn’t leaving without a fight. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-london-ban-tfl/

September 22, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies This Week in the Future of Cars: Time to Problem-Solve Waymo partners with Intel, Tesla kills a Model S, a lawyer debates the trolley problem, and more. https://www.wired.com/story/waymo-intel-tesla-apple-news-roundup/

September 21, 2017 | Author: Jay DondeJay Donde Self-Driving Cars Will Kill People. Who Decides Who Dies? Opinion: The dawn of autonomous vehicles means we must solve the trolley problem. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-cars-will-kill-people-who-decides-who-dies/

September 20, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Switzerland’s Getting a Delivery Network for Blood-Toting Drones And it’s got some clever new hardware to make it work. https://www.wired.com/story/switzerlands-getting-a-delivery-network-for-blood-toting-drones/

September 20, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Live the Maddening Life of a Traffic Engineer With a $3 Game “Freeways” will drive you crazy and make you appreciate hardworking highway builders. https://www.wired.com/story/freeways-traffic-engineer-game/

September 19, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Finally, an Online Course for Aspiring Flying Car Engineers Sebastian Thrun’s online education company, Udacity, is starting the Flying Car Nanodegree Program. https://www.wired.com/story/thrun-udacity-flying-car-nanodegree/

September 19, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall With Intel’s Chips, Google Could At Last Deliver Self-Driving Cars Google self-driving car spinoff Waymo and the global chipmaker make a self-driving power couple. https://www.wired.com/story/waymo-and-intel-self-driving/

September 18, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Wanna Stop Distracted Driving? Make Cars That Watch Their Humans Researchers have developed a system that analyzes driver behavior to spot—and stop—distracted driving. https://www.wired.com/story/distracted-driving-research/

September 16, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Scope the Future of Driving With 7 Electric Concepts Coming models from BMW, Mercedes, Audi and more reveal the auto industry’s preparation for the age of electricity. https://www.wired.com/story/frankfurt-motor-show-electric-car-concepts/

September 15, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: The Grown-Ups Arrive That time the federal government got serious about autonomous vehicles. https://www.wired.com/story/future-cars-roundup-sep-15/

September 15, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Boeing Planes Could Fire Lasers From Their Noses to Spot Turbulence The lidar system could spot troublesome air pockets more than 10 miles ahead. https://www.wired.com/story/boeing-jaxa-turbulence-lidar-laser/

September 14, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies BMW at Last Unveils a Tesla-Fighting Electric Sedan The i Vision Dynamics concept is the start of an onslaught of electric cars. https://www.wired.com/story/bmw-vision-dynamics-concept-electric/

September 14, 2017 | Author: Lee SimmonsLee Simmons Forget the Driverless Future. Get Ready to Physically Merge with a Car Do we really want autonomous vehicles? Artist Jonathon Keats imagines an alternative: the driverful car. https://www.wired.com/story/forget-the-driverless-future-get-ready-to-physically-merge-with-a-car/

September 13, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Want to Teach Self-Driving Vehicles to Talk? Pretend You’re a Car Seat How else would you study how autonomous vehicles will interact with humans on the road? https://www.wired.com/story/man-dresses-car-seat-research-self-driving/

September 13, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Mercedes’ F1-Inspired Hypercar Starts at Just $2.8 Million The long awaited Project One hypercar uses Formula 1 tech to create massive power from a minuscule engine. https://www.wired.com/story/mercedes-amg-project-one-hypercar-specs-photos/

September 13, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla Bears Some Blame for Self-Driving Crash Death, Feds Say The harshest rebuke yet of an industry eager to offer drivers autonomous features that may be easily abused, with deadly consequences. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-ntsb-autopilot-crash-death/

September 11, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall GM and Cruise’s Self-Driving Car: Just Add Software General Motors says it’s ready to mass produce driverless cars. It just has to figure out how to make them work. https://www.wired.com/story/gm-cruise-generation-3-self-driving-car/

September 11, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Why Self-Driving Cars Need Superhuman Senses An Israeli startup has developed a new way for autonomous vehicles to perceive the world. https://www.wired.com/story/why-self-driving-cars-need-superhuman-senses/

September 10, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Quest to Put a 1967 Self-Balancing ‘Car’ Back on Its Feet Jeff Lane spent years reviving the gyroscopically balanced Gyro-X back to life. https://www.wired.com/story/gyro-x-lane-motor-museum/

September 8, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall 4 Maps That Show the Gigantic Hurricane Irma Evacuation Millions of people moving by plane, car, and ship. https://www.wired.com/2017/09/4-maps-show-gigantic-hurricane-irma-evacuation/

September 8, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Rebuild and Revive Nissan’s prettier Leaf, Lyft’s robot taxis, Congress gets it together, and more news you missed. https://www.wired.com/story/car-news-nissan-lamborghini-lyft/

September 8, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Jaguar Embraces Its Electric Future by Resurrecting Its Past Jaguar Land Rover unveils an all-electric E-type, and promises much more battery power in its future. https://www.wired.com/story/jaguar-land-rover-electric-e-type/

September 8, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Nissan’s New Leaf Is an OK Electric Car—and That’s a Great Thing And maybe just the thing you’re looking for. https://www.wired.com/story/nissans-new-leaf-is-an-ok-electric-carand-thats-a-great-thing/

September 7, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Devastate Your Hairdo in Lamborghini’s New $460K Aventador S Roadster Drop the top and enjoy 740 horsepower. Just remember to bring a comb. https://www.wired.com/story/lamborghini-aventador-s-roadster/

September 7, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Lyft Is Launching a Fleet of Self-Driving Cars in San Francisco Working with self-driving developer Drive.ai, the Uber rival will escort some customers in robo-taxis. https://www.wired.com/story/lyft-self-driving-cars-san-francisco-bay-area/

September 6, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall That Delta Plane Flying Straight Through Hurricane Irma Was NBD But serious props to Delta Airlines. https://www.wired.com/story/delta-plane-hurricane-irma/

September 6, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Congress Unites (Gasp) to Spread Self-Driving Cars Across America The House just passed a bipartisan bill to encourage autonomous vehicles testing. https://www.wired.com/story/congress-self-driving-car-law-bill/

September 6, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies India Just Might Be Getting a Hyperloop Hyperloop Transportation Technologies just signed a deal to build a tube-route in the southeastern state of Andhra Pradesh. https://www.wired.com/story/india-hyperloop-transportation-technologies/

September 5, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart With a Revamped Leaf, Nissan Looks to Regain Its Electric Edge The redesigned electric car is back to challenge Tesla’s Model 3 and Chevy’s Bolt EV. https://www.wired.com/story/leaf-nissan-2018-electric/

September 4, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Above Devastated Houston, Armies of Drones Prove Their Worth After the hurricane, professional drone pilots get to work. https://www.wired.com/story/houston-recovery-drones/

September 3, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Harvey Wrecks Up to a Million Cars in Car-Dependent Houston Reliable transportation is a daily, fundamental need, almost more so in the wake of a disaster. https://www.wired.com/story/harvey-houston-cars-ruined/

September 1, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Perfidious Greed News from Ford, Bentley, and Uber’s increasingly insane boardroom brawl. https://www.wired.com/story/week-future-cars-ford-uber-bmw/

August 31, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Houston’s Trucking Lifeline Rumbles Back in Harvey’s Aftermath With the worst behind it, the city looks to start rebuilding. https://www.wired.com/story/hurricane-harvey-houston-trucks-resupply/

August 31, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Students Built the World’s Fastest Hyperloop—Then Elon Musk Showed Up Teams from around the world showed there’s no wrong way to build futuristic transportation. https://www.wired.com/story/hyperloop-musk-student-competition/

August 31, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Future of Driving Looks Awfully Tiny Prepare for a future of small, electric, super cool cars. https://www.wired.com/story/smart-autonomous-vehicle-concept/

August 30, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Bentley’s New Continental GT Wraps Classy Style Around Swanky Tech The sleeker, sharper grand tourer comes packed with the latest and greatest. https://www.wired.com/story/bentley-continental-gt-new/

August 30, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Travis Kalanick’s Great Defender Writes a Hell of a Motivational Letter Shervin Pishevar, a major Uber investor and former board member, to the former CEO’s defense. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-shervin-pishevar-kalanick-letter/

August 29, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Ford’s Robocar Delivers Pizza in the Name of Science A delicious effort to understand how people interact with driverless technology. https://www.wired.com/story/ford-self-driving-pizza-delivery-dominos/

August 28, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Agony of Deciding to Evacuate a City Officials like the ones facing Hurricane Harvey in Houston have a lot to consider before they make the call. https://www.wired.com/story/hurricane-evacuation-houston-harvey/

August 27, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall What the Controlled Chaos of Burning Man Reveals About Cities And what the temporary Black Rock City settlement has to learn. https://www.wired.com/story/burning-man-reveals-chaos-cities/

August 26, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Welcome to the Concours d’Lemons, America’s Great Love Fest of Crap Cars Celebrating what humans can build when their imaginations run awry, engineering skills falter, and budgets dry up. https://www.wired.com/story/concours-dlemons-pebble-beach/

August 25, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies This Week in the Future of Cars: Back From the Fancy Past After the excesses of the Pebble Beach Concours d’Elegance, it’s back to self-driving cars. https://www.wired.com/story/autonomous-electric-cars-roundup-news/

August 24, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Elon Musk Is About to Test His Tunneling Tech Under LA Though questions abound. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-test-tunnel/

August 24, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Blood-Carrying, Life-Saving Drones Take Off for Tanzania Drone delivery startup Zipline expands its service beyond Rwanda. https://www.wired.com/story/zipline-drone-delivery-tanzania/

August 23, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Mercedes’ Outrageously Swoopy Concept Says Nein to the Pod-Car Future The Vision Mercedes-Maybach 6 Cabriolet is all about a future of elegance. https://www.wired.com/story/mercedes-vision-maybach-cabriolet-convertible-concept/

August 23, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Airbus Uses Lasers to Teach Its Flying Car to Land Taking off is easy. Landing, not so much. https://www.wired.com/story/airbus-vahana-flying-car-landings/

August 21, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The USS John S. McCain’s Crash Only Seems Familiar The collision with a tanker happened in one of the world’s most congested waterways. https://www.wired.com/story/uss-john-mccains-crash-fitzgerald/

August 21, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Driverless Cars Need Ears as Well as Eyes Humans can hear approaching sirens, autonomous cars need to, too. https://www.wired.com/story/driverless-cars-need-ears-as-well-as-eyes/

August 20, 2017 | Author: Brett BerkBrett Berk Mercedes’ $2.8 Million Hypercar Gets Huge Power From a Tiny Engine The engineering lift behind the mysterious Project One. https://www.wired.com/story/mercedes-hypercar-engine/

August 18, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies You Can Make the Best Porsche Even Better For Just $525K Guntherwerks will rebuild your beloved sports car into something truly special. https://www.wired.com/story/guntherwerks-porsche-993-400r/

August 18, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart This Lumbering Self-Driving Truck Is Designed to Get Hit Autonomous vehicles will saves lives by avoiding crashes—except this one. https://www.wired.com/story/this-lumbering-self-driving-truck-is-designed-to-get-hit/

August 18, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Old Is New Again A new breed of DeLorean, off-roaders go electric, and autonomous vehicles take to highway work zones. https://www.wired.com/story/week-in-future-cars-old-new/

August 17, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall 11 Spectacular Cars Any Billionaire Can Buy at Auction This Weekend Every year, some of the best cars in the world change hands at the Pebble Beach Concours d’Elegance. https://www.wired.com/story/pebble-beach-2017-auctions/

August 17, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Mesmerizing Timelapse Reveals How Workers Build Escalators A look inside the latest stage of London’s Crossrail project. https://www.wired.com/story/london-crossrail-escalators-construction-video-timelapse/

August 16, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Go Spend $35K on an Electric Off-Roader That Out-Torques Tanks The Nikola Zero has more power than a Mustang GT, more torque than an M1 Abrams tank, and less sense than a penny. https://www.wired.com/story/nikola-electric-utv-off-road-zero/

August 15, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Ford’s New GT Supercar Is Yet Another Homage to 1960s Glory The ’67 GT Heritage is just the latest car celebrating Ford’s dominance of the 24 Hours of Le Mans. https://www.wired.com/story/ford-gt-supercar-heritage-le-mans-edition/

August 13, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart A Flying Car From DeLorean Really Won’t Need Roads It doesn’t time travel, but it could get you where you want to go much quicker. https://www.wired.com/story/delorean-aerospace-flying-car/

August 12, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Terrifying, Ongoing Mystery of Suffocating Fighter Pilots Hypoxia has troubled pilots for decades—and now it’s appeared in the F-35. https://www.wired.com/story/hypoxia-pilots-f35/

August 11, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Week in the Future of Cars: Phoenix Rising News from Intel, Mazda, General Motors, and a man dressed as a car seat. https://www.wired.com/story/future-cars-news-roundup-august/

August 10, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Elon Musk’s Boring Company Just Hit the Boring Part More details on Elon Musk’s plan to tunnel through Los Angeles. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-boring-company-tunnels/

August 10, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies How Tesla’s Self-Driving Truck Scheme Can Dump Human Drivers A few options for cracking the hardest part of autonomous trucking. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-self-driving-truck-musk/

August 10, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Self-Driving Cars Flock to Arizona, Land of Good Weather and No Rules A nice place to settle down and get some testing done. https://www.wired.com/story/mobileye-self-driving-cars-arizona/

August 9, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies GM’s Robocar Service Drives Employees Around SF for Free Cruise, the automaker’s SF-based self-driving outfit, takes a big step forward. https://www.wired.com/story/gm-cruise-anywhere-self-driving-san-francisco/

August 9, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Mazda’s Crafty New Engine Makes More Miles From Less Fuel The Japanese automaker claims it’s the first to deliver the long-anticipated compression ignition gasoline engine. https://www.wired.com/story/mazda-injection-compression-skyactivx-engine/

August 8, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall That Guy Dressed Up as a Car Seat to Solve a Robocar Riddle A goofy way to get vital answers. https://www.wired.com/story/virginia-self-driving-car-seat-disguise-van/

August 8, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Great News for Everyone! Elon Musk Is Building a Hyperloop The Boring Company jumps into a crowded hyperloop field. https://www.wired.com/story/great-elon-musk-building-hyperloop/

August 7, 2017 | Author: Jim ResnickJim Resnick Kia’s Feisty Stinger GT Conquers the World’s Toughest Track A bold bid to challenge Germany’s dominance in the sports car market. https://www.wired.com/story/kia-stinger-gt-review-nurburgring/

August 5, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Puny Humans Still See the World Better Than Self-Driving Cars For now. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-cars-perception-humans/

August 4, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Boeing’s 787-8 Draws a Ginormous Self-Portrait Over America A tribute to the loyal #AvGeeks. https://www.wired.com/story/boeing-787-8-drawing-test-flight/

August 4, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Hosting the 2028 Olympics Could Fix Los Angeles LA can use the games as an opportunity to fulfill a long-standing goal of creating an exceptional mass-transit system. https://www.wired.com/story/2028-olympics-fix-los-angeles/

August 3, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies An Oral History of the Darpa Grand Challenge, the Grueling Robot Race That Launched the Self-Driving Car The legendary competition created the self-driving community as we know it, the men and women in too-big polo shirts who would dominate an automotive revolution. https://www.wired.com/story/darpa-grand-challenge-2004-oral-history/

August 3, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart A Powerless Plane Rides the Wind to a New Altitude Record The Perlan II glider just soared to a new world record on ‘stratospheric mountain waves’ high above the Argentine Andes. https://www.wired.com/story/the-powerless-plane-riding-the-wind-to-a-new-altitude-record/

August 2, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies A Pod Races Through the Hyperloop for the First Time Ever That creepy wail you hear might be the future of transportation. https://www.wired.com/story/hyperloop-one-test-pod-video/

August 2, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Self-Driving Cars Are Confusing Drivers—And Spooking Insurers “Autonomous ambiguity” leaves people unsure of just what their semi-autonomous cars can—and cannot—do. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-cars-insurance-ambiguity/

August 1, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart When You’ll Get Your Tesla Model 3—And How to Get It Faster Don’t feel like waiting? Get the long-range version, spring for the fancy features, skip the white interior, and make do with rear-wheel-drive. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-model-3-delivery-timeline/

August 1, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Ford’s New Mustang Comes With a Jerk-Silencing ‘Quiet’ Mode For those rare times that demand a silent start. https://www.wired.com/story/ford-mustang-jerk-silencing/

July 31, 2017 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Canceling Your Model 3 Deposit? Don’t Count on a Timely Refund Tesla is taking weeks or months longer than promised to refund Model 3 deposits. Why so long? https://www.wired.com/story/canceling-your-model-3-deposit-dont-count-on-a-timely-refund/

July 29, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Elon Musk Has Better Things to Do Than Run Tesla Musk is ill-suited to the next (boring) phase of Tesla’s expansion: being a real automaker. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-better-things-than-tesla/

July 29, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla’s Model 3 Is Here, and It’s Much More Than an Electric Car Model 3 delivery day went off without a hitch. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-model-3-more-than-electric/

July 29, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart I Drove a Tesla Model 3. Here’s What You Need to Know The company delivered the first 30 of its new “affordable” car on Friday. https://www.wired.com/story/i-drove-a-tesla-model-3/

July 28, 2017 | Author: WIRED StaffWIRED Staff Tesla Model 3 Launch: Live Coverage Today’s the day Elon Musk delivers the first new cars off the line. https://www.wired.com/2017/07/tesla-model-3-launch-live-coverage/

July 27, 2017 | Author: WIRED StaffWIRED Staff Tesla’s Model 3 Is Here: How to Watch the Big Event The long-awaited affordable electric car is finally here, for a lucky few. https://www.wired.com/story/teslas-model-3-how-to-watch/

July 27, 2017 | Author: Brett BerkBrett Berk The Rolls-Royce Phantom Personalizes Opulence The latest flagship Rolls has a new, extremely fancy way to make the dashboard extra “you.” https://www.wired.com/story/rolls-royce-phantom-personalize-opulence/

July 27, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla’s Model 3 Is Making Electric Vehicles Successful Even Before Its Launch No matter what happens with the Tesla “affordable car”, it charged the market like no other. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-model-3-electric-market/

July 27, 2017 | Author: WIRED StaffWIRED Staff The Triumphs and Blunders That Have Led to Tesla’s Model 3 Elon Musk’s master plan finally produces an affordable electric car. https://www.wired.com/story/triumphs-blunders-tesla-model-3/

July 26, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Inside Dodge’s Face-Warpingly Fast Demon Dragster How to build a production car so speedy, it’s been banned by the National Hot Rod Association. https://www.wired.com/story/dodge-face-warping-demon/

July 25, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Mexico City Is Killing Parking Spaces. Pay Attention, America One of the world’s most trafficky cities gets a parking overhaul. https://www.wired.com/story/mexico-city-killing-parking/

July 25, 2017 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Dive Into a Galaxy of Footage From NASA’s Legendary X-Plane Program The space agency has just released a trove of archival video, and it’s awesome. https://www.wired.com/story/dive-into-a-galaxy-of-footage-from-nasas-legendary-x-plane-program/

July 24, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Look Ma, No Brake! You’ll Drive Electric Cars With One Pedal Press to go, lift off to stop. https://www.wired.com/story/look-ma-no-brake-youll-drive-electric-cars-with-one-pedal/

July 21, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Lyft Says, ‘Me Too!’ and Dives Into the Self-Driving Game The ride-hail company will launch its own autonomous vehicle software and hardware. https://www.wired.com/story/lyft-self-driving-game/

July 21, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Oh, Elon. Building Infrastructure for the Hyperloop Doesn’t Work Like That Elon Musk says he has “verbal government” approval to build a hyperloop on the East Coast. Be skeptical. https://www.wired.com/story/infrastructure-hyperloop-nope/

July 20, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Waiting for the Bus Is About to Get Less Bad A collaboration between Google and transit tech company TransLoc could bring real-time transportation data to even more agencies. https://www.wired.com/story/waiting-bus-less-bad/

July 19, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Congress Finally Gets Serious About Regulating Self-Driving Cars A House subcommittee approves new federal rules, putting the country a step closer to saying bye-bye to local control of robocars. https://www.wired.com/story/congress-autonomous-self-driving-car-regulations/

July 19, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Wanna Help Self-Driving Cars? Turn on Your Phone’s Camera Recording the road will earn you a few pennies, and help create detailed maps. https://www.wired.com/story/wanna-help-self-driving-cars-turn-on-your-phones-camera/

July 18, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams A Sorta-Self-Driving Mercedes Tackles Americans’ Greatest Fear: the Roundabout The 2018 S-Class takes on more sophisticated turns and lane changes—but the system ain’t perfect. https://www.wired.com/story/sorta-self-driving-mercedes-roundabout/

July 14, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Model 3’s Success Depends Upon Tesla Building More Than a Decent Car Tesla has to ramp up the infrastructure to support its new model. https://www.wired.com/story/the-model-3s-success-depends-upon-tesla-building-more-than-a-decent-car/

July 13, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Uber v. Waymo Court Showdown Looms. Here’s What You Need to Know New legal filings reveal new dirt. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-waymo-court-showdown/

July 12, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Hyperloop’s First Real Test Is a Whooshing Success And now comes the hard part. https://www.wired.com/story/hyperloop-one-test-success/

July 12, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams New NASA Tech Kills Trespassing Drones Without Touching Them A self-destruct mode, for when your drone does something it shouldn’t. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-tech-kills-trespassing-drones/

July 11, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Audi’s New A8 Shows How Robocars Can Work With Humans A car that relies on human backup must know things no car ever has before. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-car-user-interface/

July 9, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Human Army Using Phones to Teach AI to Drive If you can’t wait for driverless cars to hit the roads, you can help train them how to drive now. https://www.wired.com/story/mighty-ai-training-self-driving-cars/

July 8, 2017 | Author: Matt HardigreeMatt Hardigree Past and Present, Volvo Has Always Been the Future of Cars To understand the industry’s past and future, look to Sweden. https://www.wired.com/story/volvo-history-future-auto-industry/

July 7, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Renault Honors a 40-Year-Old Failure With a … Fancy Teapot The French Formula 1-inspired kitchen implement you never knew you needed. https://www.wired.com/story/renault-f1-yellow-teapot/

July 7, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Why the Tesla Model S Couldn’t Ace Its Latest Crash Test The bad news comes as Tesla’s stock price plummets concerns about the Model 3. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-model-s-crash-test-safety-iihs/

July 6, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Volvo’s Electric Car Plan Isn’t as Bold or Crazy as It Seems It’s the first major automaker to announce a serious shift to electric. https://www.wired.com/story/volvos-electric-car-plan/

July 6, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart How the Ocean’s Strongest Ships Carry Anything Like It’s NBD If the damaged USS Fitzgerald needs a ride home, these are the ships to call. https://www.wired.com/story/heavy-lift-ships-fitzgerald/

July 5, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Hey NYC: Here Are Some Ideas for Fixing Your Busted Subway Taking advice from the best transit systems in the world. https://www.wired.com/story/nyc-subway-fixes/

July 5, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall To End Distracted Driving, MIT Figures Out How People Really Drive New research works to unlock human “attentional awareness.” https://www.wired.com/story/mit-distracted-driving/

July 4, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Airbus’ New Black Boxes Will Eject From Crashing Planes, So They’re Easier to Find The deployable flight data recorders will help investigators locate wreckage, and work out what happened. https://www.wired.com/story/airbus-new-black-boxes-will-eject-from-crashing-planes-so-theyre-easier-to-find/

July 3, 2017 | Author: Jack EwingJack Ewing Diesel Scandals Could Decimate the Future of Big Automakers This fallout could help set up carmakers as the next industry to be upended by Silicon Valley. https://www.wired.com/story/vw-diesel-scandal-future-automakers/

July 2, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Honda Kills the Most Annoying Thing About Front-Wheel Drive The 2018 Civic Type R has gobs of power and zero torque steer. https://www.wired.com/story/honda-civic-type-r-torque-steer/

July 2, 2017 | Author: Brett VelicovichBrett Velicovich What It’s Like to Control a Predator Drone My job was to hunt down the most dangerous terrorists in the world. If I was chasing you, you never saw me. https://www.wired.com/story/control-predator-drone-brett-velicovich/

July 1, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Want to Fix NYC’s Subway Emergency? You’ll Need More Than $1B It’s a good start. Now you just need reliable funding and years of follow-through. https://www.wired.com/story/nyc-subway-how-fix-state-emergency/

June 30, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Porsche’s Most Powerful 911 Ever Makes 700 Horsepower, Is Insane The 2018 911 GT2 RS costs $300,000. https://www.wired.com/story/2018-porsche-911-gt2-rs-specs/

June 30, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Elon Musk’s Chicago Tunnel Makes a Dumb Idea Even Dumber Airport connections to mass transit are tricky to build. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-chicago-tunnel-dumb/

June 29, 2017 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Tiny MIT Drones Show How to Deploy Flying Cars Without Chaos MIT has crafted a beautifully orchestrated framework for how a swarm of driving/flying robots might share the street/air. https://www.wired.com/story/mit-drones-flying-cars/

June 29, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Cadillac’s Self-Driving System May Be the Smartest Yet

https://www.wired.com/story/cadillac-super-cruise-self-driving-gm/

June 28, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Feds Won’t Ban Laptops, Will Make Airport Security Awful Expect more pat downs and closer inspection of all your gadgets on any flight into or out of the US. https://www.wired.com/story/dhs-tsa-laptop-ban-extra-security/

June 28, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart A Bonkers Private “Jet” Brings Electric Flight to the Rich Eviation’s Alice Commuter could be in service as soon as 2021. https://www.wired.com/story/a-bonkers-private-jet-brings-electric-flight-to-the-rich/

June 27, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Avis Won’t Be the Only Dinosaur to Survive the Robocar Revolt Companies like Avis possess expertise that remains useful in this new state of affairs. https://www.wired.com/story/waymo-avis-driving-dinosaurs/

June 26, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams To Prevent Motorcycle Crashes, Make Riders ‘Talk’ to Cars Vehicle-to-vehicle communication could alert motorcyclists to crashes before they happen. https://www.wired.com/story/prevent-motorcycle-crashes-b2v/

June 25, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Airbus Conquers Physics With a Funky Super-Fast Helicopter The “Racer” uses extra wings and propellers to fly at a heady 250 mph. https://www.wired.com/story/airbus-racer-helicopter-speed/

June 24, 2017 | Author: Brett BerkBrett Berk Supercars and Robots Push Honda Toward the Autonomous Future The Acura NSX relies on the kind of innovation that will help Honda cruise into the self-driving future. https://www.wired.com/story/acura-nsx-honda-self-driving-cars/

June 23, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Most Gasp/Hurl-Inducing Flights of the 2017 Paris Air Show From the F-35 fighter jet proving its moves to a Boeing 737 takeoff that would put you off flying for life. https://www.wired.com/story/paris-air-show-f-35-flights/

June 23, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall As Uber Flails, Its Self-Driving Tech Rolls On Not everything is going wrong for the ride-hailing giant. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-crisis-self-driving-pittsburgh/

June 22, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Can’t Decide What Kind of Flying Car to Get? Try These 10 The long-promised age of the flying car is finally here (kinda). Here are 10 of the most promising designs. https://www.wired.com/2017/06/flying-car-concepts-prototypes/

June 21, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Airbus’ Big Bet to Save Its Dying A380 Super Jumbo: Winglets Oh, and it’s shoving 80 more people inside the thing. https://www.wired.com/story/airbus-a380plus-winglets/

June 20, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams New NASA Tech Tells Drones When They’re Broken—and Helps Them Land Safe2Ditch helps drones troubleshoot problems, and gets them safely to the ground. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-drone-safe2ditch/

June 20, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The F-35 Fighter Jet Quiets Haters With a Wild Demo Flight The long-delayed, over-budget jet had a lot to prove. And it put on quite a show. https://www.wired.com/story/f-35-fighter-jet-paris-air-show-flight-video/

June 20, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies South Korea Wants to Fire Up a Hyperloop in Just 4 Years Turning a three-hour journey from Seoul to Busan into a half-hour hop. https://www.wired.com/story/hyperloop-south-korea/

June 18, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Latest Flying Car Concept Seems—Dare We Say It—Serious Time to break out the spandex suits and take off. https://www.wired.com/story/neva-airquadone-flying-cars-paris-air-show/

June 16, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies A Navy Destroyer Collided With a Container Ship—Here’s What Likely Happened The USS Fitzgerald ran into the ACX Crystal off the coast of Japan, and human error is a likely culprit. https://www.wired.com/story/uss-fitzgerald-navy-destroyer-crash-collision-japan-acx-crystal/

June 16, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Volvo Delicately Dances Into the Semi-Autonomous Future The Swedish automaker wants to avoid the space between human and robot drivers—but that may prove impossible. https://www.wired.com/story/volvo-xc-60-self-driving/

June 16, 2017 | Author: Matt HardigreeMatt Hardigree How Cars—and Drivers—Survive the Brutal 24 Hours of Le Mans The endurance race requires not just great tech, but the ability to harness it for 24 hours straight. https://www.wired.com/story/24-hours-le-mans-logistics/

June 15, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Blimp That Crashed at the US Open? It Was Just a Fancy Hot Air Balloon It’s called a “thermal airship.” https://www.wired.com/story/blimp-crash-airship-us-open/

June 14, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Meet the 89-Year-Old Reinventing the Train in His Backyard Max Schlienger wants to use vacuum power to get people where they’re going—and it has nothing to do with the hyperloop. https://www.wired.com/story/flight-rail-vectorr-atmospheric-railway-train/

June 14, 2017 | Author: Mikael Colville-AndersenMikael Colville-Andersen The 20 Most Bike-Friendly Cities in the World, From Malmö to Montreal The best urban centers in the world for those who move on two wheels. https://www.wired.com/story/world-best-cycling-cities-copenhagenize/

June 13, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber’s Culture Problems Could Sink Its Self-Driving Future Uber needs partnerships to bring in the robocars. It’s not looking like a good partner. https://www.wired.com/story/uber-ceo-travis-out/

June 11, 2017 | Author: Matt HardigreeMatt Hardigree To Drive Like a Nascar Star, Break Out the Video Games Nascar driver Parker Kligerman hones his skills with video games and high-tech simulators. https://www.wired.com/story/parker-kligerman-nascar/

June 9, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart This Could Be the First Airbag of the Self-Driving Car Era Smarter vehicles are going to need smarter safety systems. https://www.wired.com/story/self-driving-cars-airbags/

June 9, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Don’t Freak Over Boeing’s Self-Flying Plane—Robots Already Run the Skies Boeing’s working on a human-free plane, but today’s aircraft are mostly robot-controlled already. https://www.wired.com/story/boeing-autonomous-plane-autopilot/

June 9, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Apple’s Don’t Disturb While Driving Mode Is a Blunt Answer to a Nuanced Problem Distracted driving is a complex problem that may demand a more nuanced answer. https://www.wired.com/story/apple-do-not-disturb-distracted-driving-mode/

June 9, 2017 | Author: Matthew DeBordMatthew DeBord Inside Ford’s Top-Secret Campaign to Remake the Iconic GT 50 years after dominating the 24 Hours of Le Mans, Ford returned to the game with an all-new GT. https://www.wired.com/story/ford-gt-return-glory-debord/

June 8, 2017 | Author: Aarian Marshall, Alex DaviesAarian Marshall and Alex Davies The Scariest Threats to Uber’s Future, From Waymo to Money Worries Lawsuits, criminal investigations, and a toxic corporate culture. Can the ride-hail giant survive? https://www.wired.com/2017/05/scariest-threats-ubers-future-waymo-money-worries/

June 8, 2017 | Author: Jim ResnickJim Resnick Lamborghini’s New Supercar Wrangles the Wind to Conquer the Track The Italians enlist the god of wind in the supercar battle. https://www.wired.com/story/lamborghini-huracan-performante/

June 7, 2017 | Author: Matt HardigreeMatt Hardigree My Creepy Quest to Save Humanity from Robocar Commuting I spend a day in my driveway looking for answers. https://www.wired.com/2017/06/creepy-quest-save-humanity-robocar-commuting/

June 6, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla Time, and How Elon Musk Measures Everything In Dog Years We’ve analyzed Elon Musk’s deadlines, deliveries, and predictions, and concluded that one year him equals roughly eight years for the rest of us. https://www.wired.com/2017/06/tesla-time-elon-musk-measures-everything-dog-years/

June 6, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall So What’s the Deal With Air Traffic Control Reform? Breaking down the White House’s latest foray into infrastructure. https://www.wired.com/2017/06/trump-air-traffic-control-explained/

June 4, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Inside the Factory Building the World’s Smallest, Cheapest Private Jet See how the five-passenger Cirrus SF50 Vision Jet comes together. https://www.wired.com/2017/06/cirrus-sf5-vision-jet/

June 3, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Robocars Could Add $7 Trillion to the Global Economy A new report predicts a $7 trillion self-driving economy. Get some of that future cash. https://www.wired.com/2017/06/impact-of-autonomous-vehicles/

June 2, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Paul Allen Built the World’s Largest Plane to Fling Satellites Into Space The twin-hulled behemoth has a wingspan three times that of a Boeing 737, and should make space launches cheaper and more flexible. https://www.wired.com/2017/06/paul-allen-built-worlds-largest-plane-fling-satellites-space/

June 1, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Even Elon Musk May Not Be Able to Make an Electric Truck Work Battery experts have analyzed the Tesla CEO’s plans for an electric big rig, and reckon it’s a tough proposition. https://www.wired.com/2017/06/elon-musk-tesla-semi-truck-battery/

May 31, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The Age of Electric Aviation Is Just 30 Years Away Barring a miracle, chemistry takes time to advance. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/electric-airplanes-2/

May 30, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber Fired Its Robocar Guru, But Its Legal Fight With Google Goes On Dumping Anthony Levandowski, the engineer at the heart of a legal battle with Google’s Waymo, doesn’t indemnify the ridehailing giant. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/uber-fires-anthony-levandowski-waymo-google-lawsuit/

May 28, 2017 | Author: Brett BerkBrett Berk Tomorrow’s Cars Won’t Just Drive Themselves. They’ll Feel Different What you touch and feel inside the car has once again drawn the attention of the world’s designers. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/tomorrows-cars-wont-just-drive-theyll-feel-different/

May 28, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Lawyers, Not Ethicists, Will Solve the Robocar ‘Trolley Problem’ The question of whether an autonomous vehicle, faced with an impending collision, kills its passengers or someone else is moot. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/autonomous-vehicles-trolley-problem/

May 27, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart 7 Decades of Ferrari F1 Evolution in One Bellissimo GIF The key to staying relevant in F1 is to never stop evolving. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/7-decades-ferrari-f1-evolution-one-bellissimo-gif/

May 26, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Where—and When—You’ll Find America’s Worst Traffic This Memorial Day Weekend And some tips for dodging the worst of the worst. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/youll-find-americas-worst-traffic-memorial-day-weekend/

May 25, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall California’s Daunting Plan to Clean Up the Big Sur Landslide—And Stop the Next One The slides could continue. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/californias-daunting-plan-clean-big-sur-landslide-stop-next-one/

May 24, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The Only Victor in the Search for MH370? Ocean Science And if it doesn’t, it’s still good news for science. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/victor-search-mh370-ocean-science/

May 22, 2017 | Author: Matt HardigreeMatt Hardigree Ford Replacing CEO Mark Fields Doesn’t Clarify Its Hazy Future If automakers want to survive, “mobility” has to be more than a buzzword. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/ford-fields-ceo-hackett/

May 21, 2017 | Author: Brett BerkBrett Berk Prepare Yourself for the Sweet, Sweet Luxury of Riding in a Robocar The forces reshaping the nature of transportation are conspiring to shift focus away from the driver. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/prepare-sweet-sweet-luxury-riding-robocar/

May 20, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Detroit’s New Streetcar Is OK, But It Can’t Save a City The limits of public transit in a city that needs much more. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/detroits-new-streetcar-ok-cant-save-city/

May 19, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Look Out Elon—A Bunch of Students Have Set a Rocket Record The USC team built every part of its Fathom II rocket from scratch, and flew it to 144,000 feet. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/usc-students-rocket-record/

May 19, 2017 | Author: Matt JancerMatt Jancer Boeing’s New Plane Engine Is as Wide as a Fuselage Boeing built an airplane engine the size of an airplane. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/ge-turbofan-huge-jet-engine/

May 18, 2017 | Author: Henri GendreauHenri Gendreau Ubers for the 0.1 Percent When a private jet or yacht just isn’t enough. https://www.wired.com/listicle/uber-for-rich-people/

May 18, 2017 | Author: Henri GendreauHenri Gendreau Ubers for the 0.1 Percent When a private jet or yacht just isn’t enough. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/uber-for-rich-people/

May 18, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies With Uber Freight, Travis Takes on Trucking It’s like Uber, but for freight. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/uber-freight/

May 17, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart How Airbus Dreamed Up the Wild Design for Its Flying Car For once, function follows form. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/airbus-dreamed-wild-design-flying-car/

May 15, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Waymo and Lyft Join Forces in the Obsessive Pursuit of Data Their complementary sets of information on people and cars will benefit both companies. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/waymo-lyft-join-forces-obsessive-pursuit-data/

May 15, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart How LAX Is Pulling Off a Massive, Frenzied Terminal Reshuffle Delta and 20 other airlines are swapping spots at LAX—simultaneously. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/lax-pulling-off-massive-frenzied-terminal-reshuffle/

May 15, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber Scores a Win, But Its Brawl With Waymo Ain’t Over Yet But the court orders former Google engineer Anthony Levandowski, accused of stealing self-driving trade secrets, to stop working on lidar projects. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/uber-waymo-injunction/

May 13, 2017 | Author: Brett BerkBrett Berk The Unending Struggle to Make Your Car Feel Like Your Phone Mobile phones have changed your expectations of what comes in a car—and the auto industry is racing to keep up. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/unending-struggle-make-car-feel-like-phone/

May 12, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Google’s Fight Against Uber Takes a Turn for the Criminal Uber self-driving head Anthony Levandowski faces even hotter water. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/googles-fight-uber-takes-turn-criminal/

May 12, 2017 | Author: Basem WasefBasem Wasef Review: 2017 Ford GT Welcome back to the supercar game, Ford. You’ve been missed. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/review-2017-ford-gt/

May 11, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Bad News for Everyone! The 2020 Census Is Already in Trouble Getting a good count matters, if you care about things like how people live and move. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/bad-news-everyone-2020-census-already-trouble/

May 10, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Mapped: The Top 263 Companies Racing Toward Autonomous Cars The auto industry is rebuilding itself. Here’s a chart to keep you up to speed. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/mapped-top-263-companies-racing-toward-autonomous-cars/

May 9, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Icon A5 Crash Kills 2, Including the Unique Plane’s Lead Engineer The loss of Jon Karkow and Cagri Sever is a reminder that aviation remains a dangerous pursuit. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/icon-a5-crash-kills-2-including-unique-planes-lead-engineer/

May 9, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall How the Humble Gas Tax Became an American Bogeyman President Trump says he’s considering raising the tax for the first time in 23 years. Good luck to him. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/gas-tax-became-americas-infrastructure-bogeyman/

May 7, 2017 | Author: Brett BerkBrett Berk The Real Auto Revolution Is Already Happening—Inside the Car As technology races ahead, life inside the car will rapidly evolve. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/real-auto-revolution-already-happening-inside-car/

May 7, 2017 | Author: Dan SolomonDan Solomon One Year After Fleeing Austin, Uber and Lyft Prepare a Fresh Invasion Not because Austin needs them, but because it may not be able to fend them off. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/one-year-fleeing-austin-uber-lyft-prepare-fresh-invasion/

May 5, 2017 | Author: Henri GendreauHenri Gendreau The Loony ‘Circular Runway’ Will Never Happen, But Maybe It Should Maybe it is time to rethink modern aviation. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/loony-circular-runway-will-never-happen-maybe/

May 5, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Robot & Us: Self-Driving Trucks Are Coming to Save Lives and Kill Jobs Bad news for the 2.8 million drivers who work one of the most common jobs in the country, one that provides a steady middle class income. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/robot-us-self-driving-trucks-coming-save-lives-kill-jobs/

May 4, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart With the Model 3 Coming, Tesla Grapples With Quality Control And Musk’s newer customers may not be so forgiving. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/tesla-quality/

May 3, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Judge in Waymo Dispute Lets Uber’s Self-Driving Program Live—for Now The self-driving car battle enters its papers-and-lawyers phase. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/judge-waymo-dispute-lets-ubers-self-driving-program-live-now/

May 3, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams America’s Plan to Somehow Make Drones Not Ruin the Skies Lots of testing. And lots of questions to answer. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/americas-plan-somehow-make-drones-not-ruin-skies/

May 2, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart You Don’t Have to Wait for Tesla to Get Your Electric Pickup Truck Now now, stop giggling. An electric pickup makes a lot of sense. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/workhorse-group-w-15-electric-pickup-truck/

May 2, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Don’t Look Now, But Even Buses Are Going Autonomous Reno, Nevada jumps headfirst into the autonomous future—and tries to answer some big questions about public transit in the process. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/reno-nevada-autonomous-bus/

May 1, 2017 | Author: Ryan HagemannRyan Hagemann Senseless Government Rules Could Cripple the Robo-Car Revolution Opinion: The government is driving automotive innovation into the past. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/senseless-government-rules-cripple-robo-car-revolution/

May 1, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Red Light Cameras May Issue Some Tickets Using the Wrong Formula A citizen scientist points to traffic light problems that have long vexed the professionals. https://www.wired.com/2017/05/red-light-cameras-may-issuing-tickets-based-bogus-math/

April 28, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Elon Musk Layers on the Crazy With His Plan for Traffic-Killing Tunnels An appealing vision held back only by its lunacy. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/elon-musk-layers-crazy-plan-traffic-killing-tunnels/

April 28, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies A Little Fan That Fixes the Turbocharger’s Biggest Problem BorgWarner’s e-booster kills the much-hated turbo lag. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/little-fan-fixes-turbochargers-biggest-problem/

April 27, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Want Electric Airplanes? Sorry, But You Gotta Start Small and Boring After the grandeur of Solar Impulse 2’s round-the-world flight, André Borschberg is ready to start small. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/want-electric-airplanes-sorry-gotta-start-small-boring/

April 26, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Handy ‘Stress Map’ Helps Cyclists Avoid the Scariest of Streets Knowing which streets support cycling is a big step towards making safer spaces for those on two wheels. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/handy-stress-map-helps-cyclists-avoid-scariest-streets/

April 25, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Google’s Finally Offering Rides in Its Self-Driving Minivans And starts a new chapter of its autonomous saga. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/googles-finally-offering-rides-self-driving-minivans/

April 25, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Uber Really Seriously Promises Flying Cars by 2020 And it’s not that crazy a plan. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/uber-really-seriously-promises-flying-cars-2020/

April 25, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Silicon Valley Commutes Are Hell. Time for Companies to Fix That They can’t go at it alone. But with great power—oh, and money—comes great responsibility. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/silicon-valley-commutes-hell-time-companies-fix/

April 24, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Honda Will Do Nearly Anything to Get You in a Hydrogen Car The Clarity comes with years of fuel on the house, fancy features, and good lease rates. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/honda-will-nearly-anything-get-hydrogen-car/

April 23, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart In the Age of Trump, China Eyes Electric Car Dominance Now that the Trump Administration is working to shred those environmentally-focused rules, the auto industry seems to be swinging its attention east. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/age-trump-china-eyes-electric-car-dominance/

April 21, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall How San Francisco Kept Moving Through Its Massive #PowerOutage Plan for the worst, keep talking, and be prepared to slow down. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/san-francisco-kept-moving-massive-poweroutage/

April 21, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Eccentric Electrics and Hulking SUVs of the Shanghai Auto Show The Chinese government wants electrics. Consumers want SUVs. Automakers decide to build both. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/eccentric-electrics-hulking-suvs-shanghai-auto-show/

April 20, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Lilium’s Funky ‘Jet’ Could Make Our Dreams of Flying Cars Come True The electric plane just made its first flight. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/lilium-jet-first-flight-test-flying-cars/

April 19, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Toyota’s Still Serious About Hydrogen—It Built a Semi to Prove It Hydrogen has never caught on. But short-distance trucking could make it finally work. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/toyotas-still-serious-hydrogen-built-semi-prove/

April 18, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Trump’s $1 Trillion Bill Can’t Fix US Roads—These Ideas Could The future of road funding beckons. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/trumps-1-trillion-bill-cant-fix-us-roads-ideas/

April 17, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Turns Out, a Horrifying Number of People Use Their Phones While Driving Knowing the scope of the problem is one step toward finding a solution. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/turns-horrifying-number-people-use-phones-driving/

April 16, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Bask in the Glory of the Horsepower-Happy New York Auto Show From the ludicrous Dodge Demon to the new Mercedes AMG, this year’s show is all about power. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/bask-glory-horsepower-happy-new-york-auto-show/

April 14, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Cadillac Cracks a Self-Driving Puzzle by Shoving a Camera in Your Face The long awaited “Super Cruise” only works if it knows you’re watching the road. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/cadillac-cracks-self-driving-puzzle-shoving-camera-face/

April 14, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall 7 Ingenious Ways to Blunt the Horror of Modern Aviation These concepts took the top prize for aircraft interior innovation. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/7-ingenious-ways-blunt-horror-modern-aviation/

April 14, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall 7 Ingenious Ways to Blunt the Horror of Modern Aviation These concepts took the top prize for aircraft interior innovation. https://www.wired.com/listicle/7-ingenious-ways-blunt-horror-modern-aviation/

April 13, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Unlike Hyperloop, Elon Musk’s Electric Big-Rig Actually Makes Sense Making an electric semi work isn’t easy, but it’s not rocket science. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/tesla-electric-truck/

April 13, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Explore the Plane Graveyard Where Crash Investigators Train Students learn to see the clues that can stop more crashes in the future. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/explore-plane-graveyard-crash-investigators-train/

April 13, 2017 | Author: Tim WuTim Wu How United Turned the Friendly Skies Into a Flying Hellscape United’s inhumanity dates back to a 2010 business move—and the endless hunt for profits. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/uniteds-greed-turned-friendly-skies-flying-hellscape/

April 12, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Zunum’s Hybrid Jet Could Finally Make Electric Flight a Reality Zunum Aero wants to remake aviation with the Chevy Volt of planes. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/hybrid-jet-finally-make-electric-flight-reality/

April 11, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Dodge Makes a Car So Powerful, It Can Do Wheelies The 2018 Dodge Challenger SRT Demon also runs the fastest quarter mile ever. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/dodge-makes-car-powerful-can-wheelies/

April 11, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Flight Lab: The Bizarre, Beautiful New Fliers of NASA’s Famed X-Plane Program Inside the NASA lab where the future of flight takes off. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/nasa-x-plane-x57-x58-video/

April 11, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A Clever Way to Make Flying Suckier for the Rich And airlines are gonna love it. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/clever-way-make-flying-suckier-rich/

April 10, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall United and Other Airlines Overbook Flights Because It (Usually) Pays Off Despite United’s horrifying debacle, airlines are actually getting better at this. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/united-airlines-overbook-flights-usually-pays-off/

April 10, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Ford’s First Hybrid Cop Car Is One Mean, Green Machine Nice to the planet, mean to criminals. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/fords-first-hybrid-cop-car-one-mean-green-machine/

April 7, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Facing a Self-Driving Smackdown, Uber Opts for Damage Control If you can’t win outright, save what you can. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/uber-waymo-lawsuit-injunction/

April 6, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The Aviation Industry Finally Discovers Silicon Valley To move into the future, planemakers and airlines look to California. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/aviation-industry-finally-discovers-silicon-valley/

April 6, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Cities Crave Hyperloop Because It’s Shiny—and Talk Is Cheap The scope and intractability of America’s infrastructure problem makes the siren song of the hyperloop extra alluring. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/cities-crave-hyperloop-shiny-talk-cheap/

April 5, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart After 4 Years, Seattle’s Giant Tunneling Machine Finally Breaks Through After four years underground, Bertha reaches daylight. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/4-years-seattles-giant-tunneling-machine-finally-breaks/

April 5, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Airbus Plans to Stuff 80 More People Into Its Biggest Jet The good news? Airlines may not be interested. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/airbus-plans-stuff-80-people-biggest-jet/

April 5, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Flight Lab: NASA’s Global Hawk Drones Make Science, Not War NASA’s “science birds” fly high over vicious hurricanes, measure airborne pollutants, and help researchers figure out if it’s going to be an El Niño year. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/flight-lab-nasas-global-hawk-drones-make-science-not-war/

April 4, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall An Aircraft Design That’ll Make You Love the Middle Seat. No Joke Wider, deeper, softer, more entertaining. And no more fighting over the armrest. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/aircraft-design-thatll-make-love-middle-seat-no-joke/

April 4, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Mercedes Promises Self-Driving Taxis in Just Three Years The German giant joins the race. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/mercedes-promises-self-driving-taxis-just-three-years/

April 3, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Detroit Is Stomping Silicon Valley in the Self-Driving Car Race Manufacturing muscle gives old-school automakers the edge on companies like Uber and Google. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/detroit-stomping-silicon-valley-self-driving-car-race/

April 2, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Nifty MIT Software Lets You Design and Test Your Very Own Drone Anyone who knows which end of a screwdriver to hold can design a drone and test it virtually. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/nifty-mit-software-lets-design-test-drone/

March 31, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart How to Rebuild Atlanta’s Collapsed Freeway. Like, Now Money is always a good incentive … https://www.wired.com/2017/03/rebuild-atlantas-collapsed-freeway-like-now/

March 31, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Boeing’s Test Protocol for New Planes Is as Brutal As You’d Hope Today will be easy. Tomorrow, not so much. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/boeings-test-protocol-new-planes-beat-oblivion/

March 29, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla Finally Makes Its New Autopilot as Good as the Old One The reboot of the automaker’s self-driving system gets going. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/tesla-finally-makes-new-autopilot-good-old-one/

March 29, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Flight Lab: Watch as I Flunk NASA’s Brutal Test Pilot Training Course Before takeoff, NASA test pilots brave a battery of training and testing on the ground. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/flight-lab-watch-flunk-nasas-brutal-test-pilot-training-course/

March 29, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies This Delivery Robot Isn’t Just Charming. It’s Stuffed With Pizza Starship Technologies’ cooler-sized robot starts slinging the ’za. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/delivery-robot-isnt-just-charming-stuffed-pizza/

March 28, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams AI Wields the Power to Make Flying Safer—and Maybe Even Pleasant From cutting delays to cutting edge autopilot, the computers are coming to help. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/ai-wields-power-make-flying-safer-maybe-even-pleasant/

March 27, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Uber Redeploys Its Self-Driving Cars After a Wreck in Arizona The embattled ridesharing giant gets back on the road in Tempe, Pittsburgh, and San Francisco. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/uber-redeploys-self-driving-cars-wreck-arizona/

March 26, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Want Commuters to Ditch Driving? Try Giving Them Cash Money Washington, DC mulls a new way to cut down on congestion. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/want-commuters-ditch-driving-try-giving-cash-money/

March 25, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Uber’s Self-Driving Crash Proves We Need Self-Driving Cars Humans are really, truly terrible drivers, and the robots Uber is racing to build could save a whole lot of lives. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/uber-self-driving-crash-tempe-arizona/

March 25, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla’s Model 3 Is Here. Here’s What We Know Now The latest news comes from, of course, Elon Musk’s Twitter feed. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/tesla-model-3-musk-production/

March 24, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall National Noise Map Charts Americans’ Aural Misery Work from government cartograph-ears puts transportation-related noise in perspective. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/first-national-noise-map-charts-americans-aural-misery/

March 24, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Witness 60 Years of Glorious F1 Race Car Evolution From the front engined tubes to of yore to the mystic aerodynamic future. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/formula-one-f1-race-car-evolution/

March 23, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The Fight to Wrap Cheapo Cars in Luxurious Silence The joy of quiet, long reserved for the fanciest drivers, is making its way down market. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/fight-wrap-cheapo-cars-luxurious-silence/

March 22, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Flight Lab: Inside the Model Plane Shop Where NASA Flies the Future Here’s where NASA tests the next generation of aircraft—and the wings that could fly on Mars. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/flight-lab-inside-model-plane-shop-nasa-flies-future/

March 22, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart AutoX Slaps $50 Webcams on a Car to Make It Drive Itself The startup wants to prove that driverless cars can be more affordable. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/autox-slaps-50-webcams-car-make-drive/

March 22, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Google Maps Supercharges Location Sharing, Begins Drooling Over Your Data With a new feature, the mapping market heats up. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/google-maps-share-location/

March 21, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Thank These Riveting Robots for Planes That Don’t Fall Apart New robots on the Everett, Washington assembly line install the rivets that keep your plane in one piece. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/boeing-faub-assembly-robot-777/

March 21, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Keep Riding the Subway, by All Means, But Know It’s Not as Green as You Think If your goal is reducing emissions, just plopping down a subway line won’t cut it. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/keep-riding-subway-means-know-not-green-think/

March 20, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The TSA’s New Ban on Laptops in Cabins May Not Be the Worst Thing The #electronicsban bears the marks of a targeted reaction to a specific threat. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/tsas-new-ban-laptops-cabins-may-not-worst-thing/

March 20, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Running Delivery Trucks on Trolley Wires Isn’t as Crazy as It Sounds Electric trucks would cut dramatically pollution, but batteries won’t cut it. Cables strung over the highway could supply power instead. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/running-delivery-trucks-trolley-wires-isnt-crazy-sounds/

March 19, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies 5 Essentials for Your Super-Long Car Commute Your new gig’s a mega-commute from chez vous, and self-driving cars are a few years off. Here are some friends to keep you company. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/5-essentials-super-long-car-commute/

March 17, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A Simple Theory for Uber’s Waymo Mess: Plain Old Sloppiness Waymo’s lawsuit alleging an Uber employee stole its self-driving car tech could be the case of a startup acquisition gone very, very awry. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/simple-theory-ubers-waymo-mess-just-sloppy/

March 16, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Cars Now Talk to Other Cars, if You’re Into That Sort of Thing Your guide to vehicle-to-vehicle communication, and what it means for road safety. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/cars-now-talk-cars-youre-sort-thing/

March 15, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Can Trump Uncork Vehicle Emissions? It Won’t Be Easy Rolling back the fuel economy regulations will take more than a presidential decree. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/can-trump-uncork-vehicle-emissions-wont-easy/

March 15, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Flight Lab: Take a Ride in a 747 That NASA Turned Into a Huge Telescope NASA cut a giant hole in the side of a jumbo jet, and pointed a telescope the size of Hubble through it. Scientists use it to watch the birth of stars. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/flight-lab-take-ride-747-nasa-turned-huge-telescope/

March 15, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Fancy Software Brings the Panama Canal Into the 21st Century Sophisticated logistics and planning software will ensure the world’s freighters navigate the canal quickly and efficiently. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/fancy-software-brings-panama-canal-21st-century/

March 15, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Supersonic Planes Are Mounting a Comeback—Without That Earth-Shaking Boom You could be flying cross-country at better than Mach 1 within a decade. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/supersonic-planes-mounting-comeback-without-earth-shaking-boom/

March 14, 2017 | Author: Maya RockeymooreMaya Rockeymoore Cutting Social Services Only Makes the Robotic Takeover Worse Opinion: As industry embraces autonomous vehicles, drivers—and their families—may be left behind. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/cutting-social-services-makes-robotic-takeover-worse/

March 13, 2017 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon To Make Us All Safer, Robocars Will Sometimes Have to Kill Not only will robocars fail to completely end traffic deaths, but they’ll be choosing who to sacrifice—all to make the roads of tomorrow a safer place. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/make-us-safer-robocars-will-sometimes-kill/

March 12, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Most Lust-Worthy Cars Unveiled at the Geneva Motor Show The Swiss show is known for supercars, but there were a few affordable automobiles on display too. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/lust-worthy-cars-unveiled-geneva-motor-show/

March 11, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart California’s Finally Ready for Truly Driverless Cars Time to kick the human to the curb. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/californias-finally-ready-truly-driverless-cars/

March 10, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Google Tries to Run Uber Off the Road—in Court If a judge blocks Uber from using allegedly stolen autonomous driving tech, it could devastate the transportation company. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/google-tries-run-uber-off-road-permanently-court/

March 10, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Airbus Swears Its Pod/Car/Drone Is a Serious Idea Definitely The “Pop.Up” concept is a pod that can drive on wheels or fly under propellers. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/airbus-swears-podcardrone-serious-idea-definitely/

March 9, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall 11 Classic Cars to Buy Today (For Those OK With Bankruptcy) The best and shiniest of what’s on offer at the big-time auction at Amelia Island this weekend. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/11-classic-cars-buy-today-ok-bankruptcy/

March 9, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart America Gets a D Plus for Infrastructure, and a Big Bill to Fix it It’ll take more than $1 trillion to fix America’s infrastructure. A lot more. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/america-gets-d-plus-infrastructure-big-bill-fix/

March 8, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Flight Lab: Take Off in NASA’s Cold War Spy Plane—for Science! And meet the pilot who sucks goop through a straw while looking down at the curvature of the Earth. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/flight-lab-take-off-nasas-cold-war-spy-plane-science/

March 8, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Want to Gut Emission Rules? Prepare for War With California The Golden State is ready for a fight—and it’s got a well-stocked arsenal. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/want-gut-emission-rules-prepare-war-california/

March 7, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart McLaren’s New 720S Supercar Makes Any (Very Rich) Driver Feel Like a Pro Supercar buyers want cars that make them feel like racecar drivers. McLaren’s technology can deliver that experience. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/mclaren-720s-supercar-photos/

March 6, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Meet the Lamborghini Huracàn That Crushed the World’s Toughest Track The latest special edition of Lamborghini’s entry-level Huracàn is a glorified wing on wheels. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/meet-lamborghini-huracan-crushed-worlds-toughest-track/

March 6, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall How a Failed Experiment Could Still Be the Future of Public Transit A partnership between the Kansas City transportation authority and the Boston startup Bridj only looks like a flop. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/failed-experiment-still-future-public-transit/

March 5, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Mesmerizing GIFs Reveal the Frantic Shipping in the San Francisco Bay A pretty data viz of an oft-hidden world. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/gifs-shipping-san-francisco-bay/

March 3, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Uber’s Massive Crap Pile Develops Its Own Gravity If you believe there’s no such thing as bad press, invest in Uber. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/ubers-massive-crap-pile-develops-gravity/

March 3, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Ann Arbor Is Fighting Traffic With Software—and Winning Big Blue picks green over red. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/ann-arbor-fighting-traffic-software-winning/

March 2, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Cringe All You Want, Porsche’s Still Making a Station Wagon Meet the $96K Panamera Sport Turismo. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/porsche-station-wagon-panamera-turismo/

March 1, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Range Rover’s New Baby SUV Will Swaddle You for $50,000 A new “just right” option for people who think they need a luxury off-roader. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/range-rovers-new-baby-suv-will-swaddle-50000/

March 1, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Weird and Wonderful Citroën That Still Captivates, 60 Years On The 1955 DS is the auto industry’s platypus: bizarre, delightful, innovative, and, if not inimitable, never imitated. https://www.wired.com/2017/03/citroen-ds-design-video/

February 28, 2017 | Author: Basem WasefBasem Wasef Review: 2017 BMW 5 Series The once supreme sporty sedan returns to its roots, with a touch of luxury. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/review-2017-bmw-5-series/

February 28, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Google’s Robocar Lawsuit Could Kill Uber’s Future and Send Execs to Prison Financial penalties could cross the billion mark, and execs could spend years behind bars. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/googles-robocar-lawsuit-kill-ubers-future-send-execs-prison/

February 27, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Meet the Self-Driving Car Built for Human-Free Racing If it looks sci-fi, that’s on purpose. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/meet-self-driving-car-built-human-free-racing/

February 27, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Waze Digs Into Your Car’s Dashboard It will run on your in-car navigation system—and learn a lot more about you. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/waze-cars/

February 26, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Climb Inside the World’s Largest Wind Tunnel If you want to double the gas mileage of the average 18-wheeler, you have to smooth off the rough edges. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/climb-inside-worlds-largest-wind-tunnel/

February 25, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Google’s Lawsuit Against Uber Revolves Around Frickin’ Lasers Google spent years developing its lidar system—and says Uber stole the whole thing. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/googles-lawsuit-uber-revolves-around-frickin-lasers/

February 24, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart F1’s Funky New Cars Promise Faster, More Exciting Racing Speed brings spectacle, and Formula 1 definitely wants more spectacle. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/f1s-funky-new-cars-promise-faster-exciting-racing/

February 23, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Google Accuses Uber of Stealing Its Self-Driving Car Tech Until today, the race to build a self-driving car seemed to hinge on who had the best technology. Now it’s become a case of full-blown corporate intrigue. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/googles-waymo-just-dropped-explosive-lawsuit-uber-stealing-self-driving-tech/

February 23, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Why Trump’s Attack on a California Railroad Should Trouble You No matter where you live. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/trumps-attack-california-railroad-trouble/

February 21, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart A Drone-Slinging UPS Van Delivers the Future The delivery company is using drones to complement trucks, not replace them. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/drone-slinging-ups-van-delivers-future/

February 20, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies MIT’s New Wheelchair Drives Itself MIT researchers are working to change mobility for the elderly and disabled. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/mits-new-wheelchair-drives/

February 20, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall If You Love Driving in Hellish Traffic, Visit These Cities Your dreams of slogging through a commute, fulfilled. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/love-driving-hellish-traffic-visit-cities/

February 18, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams NASA Tests Plane-Guiding Tech to Shorten Your Next Flight Better data means less space between planes, and less midair congestion. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/nasa-tests-plane-guiding-tech-shorten-next-flight/

February 17, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Your Feeble Skills Can’t Handle This Amazing Sports Car You can’t afford this car. But that’s OK, because you can’t handle it, either. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/feeble-skills-cant-handle-amazing-sports-car/

February 16, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Not Even Street Closures Can Make San Francisco Traffic Any Worse If you want to make a terrible thing much worse, you’re gonna need a bigger slab of concrete. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/not-even-street-closures-can-make-san-francisco-traffic-worse/

February 16, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Ignore the Silly Name—the 812 Superfast Is the Most Powerful Ferrari Ever The latest cannon in Maranello’s canon. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/ignore-silly-name-812-superfast-powerful-ferrari-ever/

February 16, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Texting and Driving Isn’t a Millennial Problem. It’s an Engineering Problem Designers gave us smartphones. How do we take them away? https://www.wired.com/2017/02/texting-driving-isnt-millennial-problem-engineering-problem/

February 16, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The New X-Plane Flight Sim Is So Ridiculously Detailed, It Even Has Catering Trucks From Manhattan’s skyscrapers to the caterers scuttering across the tarmac, step into the skies. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/new-x-plane-flight-sim-ridiculously-detailed-even-catering-trucks/

February 15, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Grab $18 Million and Drive Home a Stunning 1950s Jaguar One of just 16 like it. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/1975-jaguar-xkss-gooding-auction/

February 15, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Congress Could Make Self-Driving Cars Happen—or Ruin Everything It’s legislation time. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/congress-give-self-driving-cars-happen-ruin-everything/

February 14, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Facing the Horror of In-Flight Phone Calls, Americans Beg the Feds for Help Nononononono, says America. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/facing-horror-flight-phone-calls-americans-beg-feds-help/

February 14, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Pagani Chops the Top Off the Huayra Supercar, Demands $2.4 Million Now you can hear the wind whistle by. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/new-pagani-huayra-roadster/

February 14, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Most Insane Yacht on Earth Just Got Even Insaner When in doubt, call on the folks who make planes. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/oracle-americas-cup-yacht/

February 13, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Mercedes Somehow Makes the Ultra-Luxe G-Wagen Even Swankier A V12 biturbo engine, more screens than you can look at, and enough leather to put cattle on the endangered species list. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/mercedes-g-class-laundaulet/

February 13, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Self-Driving Cars Won’t Just Watch the World—They’ll Watch You The more control the car has, the more it needs to know about the person sitting behind the wheel. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/self-driving-cars-wont-just-watch-world-theyll-watch/

February 11, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Dodge’s Charger Gives Cops Eyes in the Backs of Their Heads A new feature to foil cop car ambushes, before they even happen. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/dodges-charger-gives-cops-eyes-backs-heads/

February 10, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Eyeing a Self-Driving Future, Ford Drops $1B on an AI Startup Autonomous driving demands artificial intelligence. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/eyeing-self-driving-future-ford-drops-1b-ai-startup/

February 10, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Why Self-Driving Cars Can’t Even With Construction Zones Fortunately, the people hard at work on this problem are willing to cut corners. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/self-driving-cars-cant-even-construction-zones/

February 10, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The Troubled F-35 Fighter Jet Rules the Skies in Its Toughest Test Yet Notching a 15:1 kill ratio in Red Flag, though, may not forgive blown budgets and timelines. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/troubled-f-35-fighter-jet-rules-skies-toughest-test-yet/

February 9, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies A Star Engineer Just Launched His Own Hyperloop Outfit, ‘Arrivo’ It’s called Arrivo, and it plans to put you—or at least your stuff—in a working hyperloop in just three years. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/star-engineer-just-launched-hyperloop-outfit-arrivo/

February 9, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall To Win the War on Cars, San Francisco Weaponizes Real Estate New rules for developers won’t kill traffic, but should make life better. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/win-war-cars-san-francisco-weaponizes-real-estate/

February 9, 2017 | Author: Basem WasefBasem Wasef Review: 2017 Lamborghini Aventador S The range topping Lambo gets some schooling, but doesn’t lose its bite. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/review-2017-lamborghini-aventador-s/

February 8, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Inside the Pristine Factory Where Bugatti Crafts the $2.6M Chiron They spend days just polishing the damn thing. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/inside-pristine-factory-bugatti-crafts-2-6m-chiron/

February 7, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies See the Evolution of the Famed Porsche 911 in 7 Photos How the German sports car met modernity without ditching the past. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/porsche-911-ulf-poschardt/

February 7, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Watch Darpa’s Creepy ‘Project SideArm’ Pluck a Drone Out of the Air Instead of relying on heavy infrastructure, deploy drones out the back of a truck. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/watch-darpas-creepy-project-sidearm-pluck-drone-air/

February 6, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Hot-Swappable Airplane Interiors Might Make Flying Not Suck They even ran an experiment at San Francisco’s legendary Crissy Field. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/airbus-kinda-serious-swappable-plane-interiors-cafes-spas/

February 4, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart How Military Pilots Keep Rogue Planes Out of No-Fly Zones Like the Super Bowl And how to keep them from hitting you with a missile. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/air-force-fighters-keep-rogue-pilots-no-fly-zones/

February 3, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Secret Uber Data That Could Fix Your Commute More data means better decisions for everyone—and NYC is finally getting its hands on some. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/ubers-coughing-data-nyc-fix-commute/

February 3, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Watch How Terrifyingly Bad Car Safety Was Just 20 Years Ago Maybe it’s time to get a new car. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/watch-terrifyingly-bad-car-safety-just-20-years-ago/

February 2, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Rock Out in a Perfectly Restored Range Rover for Just $170K Time to reconnect with the past—and probably your mechanic. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/rock-perfectly-restored-range-rover-just-170k/

February 2, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Drive a Car Like You’d Fly an F-35 With Augmented Reality A new way of seeing things will change the way you move. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/drive-car-like-youd-fly-f-35-augmented-reality/

February 1, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Numbers Don’t Lie: Self-Driving Cars Are Getting Good Just a few caveats. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/california-dmv-autonomous-car-disengagement/

February 1, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Uber’s Mercedes Alliance Is a Clever New Route to Self-Driving Dominance Uber leverages its power to turn rivals into teammates. https://www.wired.com/2017/02/ubers-mercedes-alliance-clever-new-route-self-driving-dominance/

January 31, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Meet the Students Racing to Make Elon Musk’s Hyperloop a Reality Hanging out with the young minds building the transportation of the future. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/meet-students-racing-make-elon-musks-hyperloop-reality/

January 30, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Inside the ‘Tunnel’ Elon Musk Is Already Digging Under Los Angeles “We have no idea what we’re doing—I want to be clear about that.” https://www.wired.com/2017/01/inside-tunnel-elon-musk-already-digging-los-angeles/

January 30, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall How Not to Screw Up Spending $1 Trillion on US Infrastructure Focus on repairs, plan for the future, and listen to the locals. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/not-screw-spending-1-trillion-us-infrastructure/

January 29, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Aston Martin’s New Vanquish Volante S Is V Pretty, Supes Powerful Try nearly 600 horsepower. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/aston-martins-new-vanquish-volante-s-v-pretty-supes-powerful/

January 27, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Mercedes Now Makes an Insane Car for ‘Everyone’ Here’s what to expect from the latest lineup. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/mercedes-now-makes-insane-car-everyone/

January 27, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Mercedes Now Makes an Insane Car for ‘Everyone’ Here’s what to expect from the latest lineup. https://www.wired.com/listicle/mercedes-now-makes-insane-car-everyone/

January 27, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Volvo’s Cars Now Spot Moose and Hit the Brakes for You The latest advance for the safety-obsessed Swedes. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/volvos-cars-now-spot-moose-hit-brakes/

January 26, 2017 | Author: Joshua BatemanJoshua Bateman China’s Launching Drones to Fight Back Against Earthquakes Flying high makes disaster response faster and more effective. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/chinas-launching-drones-fight-back-earthquakes/

January 26, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Rural Millennials Still Dig Driving. Well, They Have No Choice A new survey shows young people prefer the comfort of a car to cycling, walking, or mass transit. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/rural-millennials-still-dig-driving-well-no-choice/

January 25, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Elon Musk’s Plan to Tunnel Under LA Is Misguided Nonsense Nope nope nope. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/elon-musks-plan-tunnel-la-misguided-nonsense/

January 25, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Audi’s Ferocious New R8 Spyder Puts Your Ears Closer to Heaven The convertible lets you hear the naturally aspirated V10 all the better. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/audis-ferocious-new-r8-spyder-puts-ears-closer-heaven/

January 25, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Inside the Shop Turning Ancient Rides into Sleeper Supercars Jonathan Ward’s ICON takes out the engine, leaves the patina. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/icon-jonathan-ward-2/

January 25, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies A Très Dinky Self-Driving Shuttle Nudges Paris Into the Future The world of self-driving cars has to start somewhere. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/tres-dinky-self-driving-shuttle-nudges-paris-future/

January 24, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla’s New ‘Autopilot’ Is Just the Start of a Critical Reboot Think of it like an origin story. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/teslas-new-autopilot-may-seem-lame-critical-reboot/

January 23, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Inside the Torture Chamber Where Trains Prove They’ll Weather Anything Snow, heat, wind, rain—all indoors. Welcome to the climatic wind tunnel. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/inside-torture-chamber-trains-prove-theyll-weather-anything/

January 21, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies 11 Outrageously Fancy Cars You Can Buy This Weekend Fire up your private jet and hustle down to Arizona. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/11-outrageously-fancy-cars-can-buy-weekend/

January 20, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart After Probing Tesla’s Deadly Crash, Feds Say Yay to Self-Driving Tesla’s Autopilot system isn’t defective, investigators say—and it’s stopping crashes. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/probing-teslas-deadly-crash-feds-say-yay-self-driving/

January 20, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Whirling Ballet of the Presidential Motorcade The most complex of safety dances. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/whirling-ballet-presidential-motorcade/

January 19, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Slovakia’s Hyperloop Moves a Step Closer to Not Being a Joke Hyperloop Transportation Technologies strikes a deal to explore extending its plans to the Czech Republic. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/slovakias-hyperloop-moves-step-closer-not-joke/

January 18, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Out of Places to Stick Diamonds, Rolls-Royce Starts Infusing Cars With Gold Built to ferry guests around Macau, these Phantoms are stuffed with Au. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/places-stick-diamonds-rolls-royce-starts-infusing-cars-gold/

January 18, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Designers Reinvent the (Steering) Wheel for the Age of Autonomy 10 and 2 may not matter anymore, but the wheel is still the interlocutor between human and machine just yet. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/designers-reinvent-steering-wheel-age-autonomy/

January 17, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Ford’s 2018 Mustang Gets Shapelier and High-Techier Better aero, smarter computer. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/fords-2018-mustang-gets-shapelier-high-techier/

January 17, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Darpa’s Off-Roaders Ditch Windows for a Digital World View The inside of the tank of the future will feel a lot more like a video game. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/darpas-off-roaders-ditch-windows-digital-world-view/

January 15, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart As Self-Driving Cars Approach, the Auto Industry Races to Rebuild A new kind of car demands a new kind of car industry. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/self-driving-cars-approach-auto-industry-races-rebuild/

January 14, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies 10 Outstanding Rides 2017 Has Already Given the World With CES and the Detroit auto show already behind it, the auto industry’s off to a great year. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/10-outstanding-rides-2017-already-given-world/

January 13, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies EPA Locks in Fuel Economy Rules So Trump Can’t Rip Them Up With a week left in charge, the EPA makes a change that’ll be hard to undo. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/epa-locks-fuel-economy-rules-trump-cant-rip/

January 13, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart BlackBerry Plunges Into the Self-Driving Car Biz (Yes, That Blackberry) In an age where software defines cars, BlackBerry’s eyeing a new opportunity. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/blackberry-plunges-self-driving-car-biz-yes-blackberry/

January 12, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Here We Go Again: EPA Accuses Fiat Chrysler of Selling Dirty Diesels Another day, another automaker in trouble with the EPA. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/epa-now-accusing-fiat-chrysler-selling-dirty-diesels/

January 12, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Take a Close Look at Faraday Future’s (Supposed) Tesla-Killer You have many reasons to be skeptical that this company will change transportation. But the fact remains, its car is hot. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/video-faraday-future/

January 12, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Too Bad Audi’s Swanky New Headlights Aren’t Allowed in the US Stodgy regulations mean US drivers don’t get headlights that can spell out messages and spotlight pedestrians. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/bad-audis-swanky-new-headlights-arent-allowed-us/

January 12, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Dirty Diesels Could Cost VW Execs Decades in Prison Six indicted employees face serious charges, and they won’t be the last ones. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/dirty-diesels-cost-vw-execs-decades-prison/

January 11, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Next Transportation Secretary Seems Pretty Down With Self-Driving Cars Elaine Chao’s confirmation hearing offered subtle assurances that autonomous advocates would have an ally at the top. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/elaine-chao-confirmation-hearing/

January 11, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Gaze Upon the Coolest Cars at This Year’s Detroit Auto Show Motown is still the center of the American auto industry, and it’s got plenty to show you. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/gaze-upon-coolest-cars-years-detroit-auto-show/

January 10, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall 3 Key Questions Senators Must Ask Elaine Chao, Trump’s Transport Pick The way Americans move is changing fast—and Chao will have a lot to say about it. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/3-key-questions-senators-must-ask-elaine-chao-trumps-transport-pick/

January 10, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Car Dealers Are Dangerously Uneducated About New Safety Features A new report says that’s a big problem for safety. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/car-dealers-dangerously-uneducated-new-safety-features/

January 9, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Drone-Slinging Concept Is Like a Bond Car for Photojournalists User experience is the new black, says its college junior designer. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/drone-slinging-concept-like-bond-car-photojournalists/

January 8, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Uber’s Mildly Helpful Data Tool Could Help Cities Fix Streets “Uber Movement” is a free tool for city planners, but it could be so much more. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/uber-movement-traffic-data-tool/

January 8, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The Navy’s New Robot Boats Swarm the Enemy on Their Own Like a swarm of bees, these boats work together to defend their territory. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/navys-new-robot-boats-swarm-enemy/

January 6, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Bentley Rolls Out the World’s Fastest Four-Seater The Continental Supersports will also be the most powerful Bentley ever. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/bentley-continental-supersports/

January 6, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Honda’s Self-Balancing Motorcycle Is Perfect for Noobs No more tipping over as you pull up to the light. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/hondas-self-balancing-motorcycle-perfect-noobs/

January 5, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Nissan’s Path to Self-Driving Cars? Humans in Call Centers Remote operators could be the simple, scaleable answer to what Nissan says is an unsolvable problem: making robot drivers do everything humans can. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/nissans-self-driving-teleoperation/

January 5, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Swarms of Drones Will Black Out the Sun Drones promise to change the world: beaming the internet everywhere, accelerating warfare, and, yes, shuttling impulse buys to our doorsteps. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/swarms-drones-will-black-sun/

January 5, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Let’s Face It: The American Way of Driving Is Over For decades, the car has been the all-American signifier of who you are, a place where you are master. Now technology is taking the wheel. Enjoy the ride. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/lets-face-american-way-driving/

January 4, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Toyota’s Concept-i Envisions an Autonomous Future That’s Actually Fun The Concept-i, unveiled at CES, is designed to show that Toyota is serious about making driving fun in the future. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/toyota-concept-i/

January 4, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Take a Spin in Hyundai’s Ioniq, the Driverless Car for the Masses Cheaper sensors and less computing power add up to an autonomous car you might call affordable—if Hyundai ever builds it. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/take-spin-hyundais-ioniq-driverless-car-masses/

January 3, 2017 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Faraday Future’s ‘Tesla Beater’ Debut Doesn’t Go Quite As Planned Erstwhile Tesla competitor Faraday Future finally has a car. Well, 12 of them. Whether they can build enough for everyone is the next bump in the road. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/farraday-futures-tesla-beater-debut-doesnt-go-quite-planned-aw/

January 3, 2017 | Author: Issie Lapowsky, Aarian MarshallIssie Lapowsky and Aarian Marshall Ford’s US Expansion Is a Victory for Trump’s Trolling Tactics Trump’s, um, unique strategy pays off as Ford pours $700 million into an electric and autonomous vehicle plant in Michigan. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/fords-us-expansion-victory-trumps-trolling-tactics/

January 3, 2017 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Chrysler’s ‘Portal’ Concept Minivan Is for … Millennials? People say a lot of things about millennials—but if it’s true that they only hate driving a little bit and don’t mind minivans, Chrysler has some ideas. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/chryslers-portal-concept-minivan-millennials/

January 3, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The 7 Most Majestic Infrastructure Projects of 2016 And one more to look forward to in 2017. https://www.wired.com/listicle/7-majestic-infrastructure-projects-2016/

January 3, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The 7 Most Majestic Infrastructure Projects of 2016 And one more to look forward to in 2017. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/7-majestic-infrastructure-projects-2016/

January 2, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Coming Innovations That Will Make Flying Economy (Mostly) Better Even economy class will someday feel a bit softer, a bit warmer, a bit faster, a bit easier to sleep in. Mostly. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/coming-innovations-will-make-flying-economy-mostly-better/

January 2, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Coming Innovations That Will Make Flying Economy (Mostly) Better Even economy class will someday feel a bit softer, a bit warmer, a bit faster, a bit easier to sleep in. Mostly. https://www.wired.com/listicle/coming-innovations-will-make-flying-economy-mostly-better/

January 2, 2017 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Coming Innovations That Will Make Flying Economy (Mostly) Better Even economy class will someday feel a bit softer, a bit warmer, a bit faster, a bit easier to sleep in. Mostly. https://www.wired.com/dummy-identifier-2017/01/coming-innovations-will-make-flying-economy-mostly-better/

January 1, 2017 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Very Human Problem Blocking the Path to Self-Driving Cars New opportunities and unexpected problems are driving big automakers to reconsider how they approach autonomy. https://www.wired.com/2017/01/human-problem-blocking-path-self-driving-cars/

December 31, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The 11 Most Expensive Cars Sold at Auction in 2016 Ogle the $35.7 million Ferrari here, cause it’s the closest you’ll ever get. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/11-expensive-cars-sold-auction-2016/

December 30, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart 2017 Will Be the Year Tesla Reigns Supreme—Or Finally Flops It’s time for Elon Musk to take his game to the main stage. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/2017-will-year-tesla-reigns-supreme-finally-flops/

December 29, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies 2016’s Top 5 Moments in the World of Transportation From self-driving cars to high-flying drones. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/2016s-top-5-moments-world-transportation/

December 27, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart 7 ‘Last Mile’ Solutions That Don’t Look Unacceptably Stupid The best ways to get you out of your car. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/7-last-mile-solutions-dont-look-unacceptably-stupid/

December 27, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart 7 ‘Last Mile’ Solutions That Don’t Look Unacceptably Stupid The best ways to get you out of your car. https://www.wired.com/listicle/7-last-mile-solutions-dont-look-unacceptably-stupid/

December 26, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Our 11 Favorite Video Stories From the World of Transportation in 2016 Everything from extreme street design to a shape-changing car, from a blind man “driving” to a truck hauling beer all by itself. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/11-favorite-video-stories-world-transportation-2016/

December 26, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Our 11 Favorite Video Stories From the World of Transportation in 2016 Everything from extreme street design to a shape-changing car, from a blind man “driving” to a truck hauling beer all by itself. https://www.wired.com/listicle/11-favorite-video-stories-world-transportation-2016/

December 22, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies 2016 Was the Year Self-Driving Cars Took the Wheel And made clear they’re on the way to dominance. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/2016-year-self-driving-cars-took-wheel/

December 21, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber Bows Before California’s Power and Parks Its Robo-Cars The DMW revoked the registrations for Uber’s self-driving cars, forcing the company to sideline its fleet. For now. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/uber-parks-its-robo-cars/

December 21, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Google and Honda Are Teaming Up on Self-Driving Cars The idea is to match the companies’ areas of expertise. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/google-honda-waymo-on-self-driving-cars/

December 21, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Take a Chilling 360-Degree Tour of NASA’s Glacier-Spying Plane Explore the 1966 Lockheed P-3 that helps with Operation Icebridge. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/take-chilling-360-degree-tour-nasas-glacier-spying-plane/

December 21, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart We Take Hyundai’s Iron Man-Inspired Exoskeletons for a Spin A self-driving car’s no good for someone who can’t get to the curb. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/hyundai-exoskeletons/

December 20, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Where to Find America’s 20 Worst Holiday Traffic Jams Stretches of road to avoid if you value your time and sanity in this most wonderful time of the year. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/find-americas-20-worst-holiday-traffic-jams/

December 20, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Peep These Ancient Treasures Dug Up With London’s New Train Tunnels So many old-timey pots. Also lots of dead people. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/peep-ancient-treasures-dug-londons-new-train-tunnels/

December 19, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Google’s Latest Self-Driving Car? It’s a Minivan The newly created Waymo is working with Fiat Chrysler to build self-driving Pacifica minivans. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/googles-latest-self-driving-car-minivan/

December 19, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Lamborghini Adds Extra ‘Sport’ To Its Aventador Supercar The new take on the flagship supercar cuts through air like a deli slicer through Spam. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/lamborghini-adds-extra-sport-aventador-supercar/

December 19, 2016 | Author: Zoe MendelsonZoe Mendelson Gennady Podolsky Is No Mere Travel Agent. He’ll Get You Anywhere—Anyhow Gennady Podolsky’s clients include beef moguls, fashion photographers, and chess champs. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/gennady-podolsky-travel-agent-profile/

December 17, 2016 | Author: Charles BombardierCharles Bombardier Dodge the TSA in a Concept Van That’s Also a Security Checkpoint This self-driving van would scan passengers and bags, then drop them off past security. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/bombardier-nexus-airport-van-concept/

December 16, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Uber Refuses to Stop Self-Driving in SF, Setting Up a Legal Showdown Come at me, bros. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/uber-refuses-stop-self-driving-sf-setting-legal-showdown/

December 16, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Step Aboard the Original Air Force One for a Fascinating 3D Tour The Boeing 707 that served Eisenhower, JFK, LBJ, and Nixon is spartan by modern standards. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/step-aboard-original-air-force-one-fascinating-3d-tour/

December 16, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Your (Just a Bit Illegal) Cheat Sheet for Hacking Safer Streets Citizens! Grab your pitchforks and your paint rollers! There is DIY infrastructure to build! https://www.wired.com/2016/12/just-bit-illegal-cheat-sheet-hacking-safer-streets/

December 15, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall London’s New Way to Count Tube Riders? Tracking Their Phones London’s watching riders in a bid to improve service. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/londons-new-way-count-tube-riders-tracking-phones/

December 14, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies As Uber Launches Self-Driving in SF, Regulators Shut It Down Uber’s self-driving car ran a red light in San Francisco’s SOMA neighborhood. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/ubers-self-driving-car-ran-red-light-san-francisco/

December 14, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The US Doesn’t Want Drone Deliveries—So Amazon Took Them to England As Amazon takes off in the UK, strict rules bar similar moves in American skies. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/us-doesnt-want-drone-deliveries-amazon-took-england/

December 14, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Uber’s Robo-Car Test in SF Is a Middle Finger to Regulators Uber’s self-driving cars are cruising San Francisco, while regulators protest they have no right to do so. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/legal-loophole-lets-uber-test-self-driving-cars-california/

December 13, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Google’s Self-Driving Car Company Is Finally Here With a new company called Waymo, Google is finally taking its technology to market. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/google-self-driving-car-waymo/

December 13, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Airbus’ New Jet Concept Features Swappable Spas and Cafes Airbus has a modular plan to put glamor and flexibility back into the sky. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/airbus-new-jet-concept-features-swappable-spas-cafes/

December 12, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams A Stronger, Faster Predator Drone Could Soon Prowl Europe’s Airspace General Atomic’s new deadly drone will have the right to fly over civilian airspace. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/stronger-faster-predator-drone-soon-prowl-europes-airspace/

December 10, 2016 | Author: Charles BombardierCharles Bombardier Let’s Make Morphing Cars That Double as SUVs What if, instead of choosing one kind of car, you could simply extend your truck or SUV at the touch of a button? https://www.wired.com/2016/12/lets-make-morphing-cars-that-double-as-suvs/

December 9, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Michigan Just Embraced the Driverless Future The state passes the most Detroit-friendly regulations yet. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/michigan-just-embraced-driverless-future/

December 8, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber May Have Just Driven Itself Out of a Big Loophole Millions of dollars hinge on the definition of a “van.” https://www.wired.com/2016/12/uber-may-just-driven-big-loophole/

December 8, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Ignoring Fare Evaders Can Make Mass Transit Faster—And Richer More and more cities are emphasizing ease of access over making every last rider pay. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/ignoring-fare-evaders-can-make-mass-transit-faster-richer/

December 7, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies United Won’t Be the Last Airline to Charge for Overhead Bin Space “One gets away with something and they all pile on.” https://www.wired.com/2016/12/united-wont-last-airline-charge-overhead-bin-space/

December 7, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Plan to Remake the American Port With Better Data The Port of LA is working with GE to make everything it does more efficient. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/ges-plan-remake-american-port-better-data/

December 6, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Mr. Trump: Here’s Why You Really Want to Spend $4 Billion on Air Force One If you want a plane that can survive just about anything, open your wallet. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/mr-trump-heres-really-want-spend-4-billion-air-force-one/

December 6, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies A Tesla-Inspired Truck Might Actually Make Hydrogen Power Happen Nikola’s fuel cell powered 18-wheeler comes with a national infrastructure of fueling stations. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/tesla-inspired-truck-might-actually-make-hydrogen-power-happen/

December 3, 2016 | Author: Charles BombardierCharles Bombardier Let’s Fight Poaching With Robotic Rhinos To save these animals’ lives, I propose the Ramakera: a robotic rhinoceros designed to monitor and protect the herd from poachers. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/lets-fight-poaching-robotic-rhinos/

December 2, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Horrifying VR Film Puts You Inside a Drunk Driving Crash “Decisions” is a four-minute video that makes the terror of a deadly crash frighteningly intimate. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/horrifying-vr-film-puts-inside-drunk-driving-crash/

December 2, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Mesmerizing Commute Maps Reveal We All Live in Mega-Regions, Not Cities So it’s too bad the US is no good at planning regionally. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/mesmerizing-commute-maps-reveal-live-mega-regions-not-cities/

December 1, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall All Aboard Volvo’s Very, Very Long Bus. Like, All of You But don’t expect to see this nearly 100-foot monstrosity in your favorite American city. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/aboard-volvos-long-bus-like/

December 1, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart How a 70-Year-Old Idea Could Make Engines Way More Efficient Achates Power is reviving the long-abandoned opposed piston layout to make gas-powered cars more efficient. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/70-year-old-idea-make-engines-way-efficient/

December 1, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies We Made The Grand Tour Guys Race Each Other With Toy Cars We set Jeremy Clarkson, James May, and Richard Hammond against each other in a miniature race. https://www.wired.com/2016/12/top-gear-grand-tour/

November 30, 2016 | Author: Seth BirnbaumSeth Birnbaum You Should Have the Right to Inspect Google’s Robo-Car Tests Opinion: Tests of self-driving cars should be made public so consumers can monitor safety. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/right-inspect-googles-robo-car-tests/

November 30, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Hidden Task Ahead of Trump’s Transport Chief President-Elect Donald Trump nominates former labor head Ellen Chao to head up the department at a vital moment for autonomous tech. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/elaine-chao-secretary-transportation-self-driving-cars/

November 29, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Acura’s Concept Cockpit Envisions the Age of Autonomy The “Precision Cockpit” is all about communication with the human. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/acuras-concept-cockpit-envisions-age-autonomy/

November 28, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart SF’s Transit Hack Could’ve Been Way Worse—And Cities Must Prepare But many transit systems can barely keep trains running, let alone pay for security upgrades. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/sfs-transit-hack-couldve-way-worse-cities-must-prepare/

November 28, 2016 | Author: David R. MartinDavid R. Martin Car Insurance Pricing Is Broken, But Your Phone Could Fix It Opinion: When car insurance companies base pricing on telematics rather than demographics, everybody wins. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/car-insurance-pricing-broken-phone-fix/

November 28, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies 10 Perfect Gifts for Your Favorite Long-Haul Traveler Make their big journey home more fun, memorable, and comfortable. https://www.wired.com/listicle/10-perfect-gifts-favorite-long-haul-traveler/

November 28, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies 10 Perfect Gifts for Your Favorite Long-Haul Traveler Make their big journey home more fun, memorable, and comfortable. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/10-perfect-gifts-favorite-long-haul-traveler/

November 27, 2016 | Author: Jennifer ChausseeJennifer Chaussee The Evolution of Airline Cooking Tech, From Quicklime to Sous Vide If you think sitting in a metal tube at 30,000 feet is hard, try cooking a steak up there. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/evolution-airline-cooking-tech-quicklime-sous-vide/

November 27, 2016 | Author: Charles BombardierCharles Bombardier Flee Your Family Aboard This Flying Saucer Concept Or, someday, use it for your commute. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/flee-family-aboard-flying-saucer-concept/

November 23, 2016 | Author: Charley LockeCharley Locke Land Mines, Axes, and Other Ridiculous Things the TSA Has Confiscated Leave your Batarangs and lipstick stun guns at home. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/ridiculous-prohibited-items-found-tsa/

November 22, 2016 | Author: Alex Davies, Aarian MarshallAlex Davies and Aarian Marshall Self-Driving Cars Will Love the Driving Hell That Is Boston Hellish traffic and atrocious drivers make it a perfect proving ground for autonomous vehicles. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/nutonomy-autonomous-cars-boston/

November 21, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Feds Finally Make Safety Rules for High Speed Rail And it’s good news for anyone hoping to hop a bullet train. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/feds-finally-make-safety-rules-high-speed-rail/

November 21, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Plane Truth: Private Jet Vs. Commercial Airliner As the Gulfstream set gets sweeter amenities, some of those perks do trickle down to us peons smooshed in row 97. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/plane-truth-private-jet-vs-commercial-airliner/

November 21, 2016 | Author: Brendan I. KoernerBrendan I. Koerner 7 Vehicles—and Fellow Passengers—of the Future Better methods of travel will emerge soon. But no matter the vehicle’s greatness, you’ll still have to battle seatmates for total armrest domination. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/7-vehicles-fellow-passengers-future/

November 21, 2016 | Author: Joseph Bien-KahnJoseph Bien-Kahn Follow the Robot in the Airport of the Future We searched terminals around the world for the smartest innovations and mashed them all into one. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/follow-robot-airport-future/

November 20, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The 11 Hottest Rides Driving This Year’s LA Auto Show New SUVS from Alfa Romeo and Jaguar, Porsche’s latest racer, McLaren’s new supercar, and more. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/11-hottest-rides-driving-years-la-auto-show/

November 18, 2016 | Author: Charles BombardierCharles Bombardier It’s Time to Replace Meter Maids With Riderless Motorcycles Brigade is a concept designed to keep the peace and keep human officers doing more important work. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/charles-bombardier-brigade/

November 18, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies So, Nobody Knows How Much Self-Driving Cars Will Pollute It could be really good! Or also maybe terrible. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/nobody-knows-much-self-driving-cars-will-pollute/

November 17, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart McLaren Has Big Plans for Another Utterly Insane Supercar McLaren is bringing back that driver-first layout in a “Hyper-GT” car it has codenamed the BP23. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/mclaren-bp23/

November 17, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Self-Flying Choppers Fight Wildfires So Humans Don’t Have To Two helicopters, with help from two drones, join forces to fight fires and save lives. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/lockheed-martin-kmax-sara-indago-firefighting-drones/

November 16, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Nexar’s AI Dashcam Could Stop Your Next Crash—and Definitely Collect Your Data The startup Nexar unlocks its vehicle-to-vehicle network. Your car is about to get a lot smarter. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/nexars-ai-dashcam-stop-next-crash-definitely-collect-data/

November 16, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Alfa Romeo Joins the Luxury SUV Madness The Italian brand continues its comeback with a handsome, future-facing SUV. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/alfa-romeo-stelvio-suv/

November 15, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart I Used Only My Mind to Fly a Plane Around Seattle With no flight experience and 15 minutes of training, I use my thoughts and a brain-computer interface to swoop through the air. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/used-mind-fly-plane-around-seattle/

November 15, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Chrysler’s Electric Pacifica Minivan Is Legit. Wait—Why Are You Laughing The Chrysler Pacifica Hybrid is an electric car that can fit the whole family. https://www.wired.com/listicle/chryslers-electric-pacifica-minivan-everyman/

November 15, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Chrysler’s Electric Pacifica Minivan Is Legit. Wait—Why Are You Laughing The Chrysler Pacifica Hybrid is an electric car that can fit the whole family. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/chryslers-electric-pacifica-minivan-everyman/

November 14, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Jaguar’s Electric I-Pace Concept Is One Fancy (and Zippy) SUV Every luxury automaker’s making an electric SUV, and Jaguar just joined the fray. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/jaguar-i-pace-electric-concept-suv/

November 14, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Former Top Gear Guys Show Us the Last Things on Their Phones Before Amazon’s ‘The Grand Tour’ premieres, judge the men themselves. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/top-gear-grand-tour-clarkson-hammond-may/

November 13, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies On His Way Out, US Transportation Chief Anthony Foxx Sets Drones Free Closing out his four-year term, Foxx is hustling to push emerging tech forward as much as he can. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/way-us-transportation-chief-anthony-foxx-sets-drones-free/

November 11, 2016 | Author: Charles BombardierCharles Bombardier Forget Supersonic—Let’s Make a Sea-Skimming Cargo Jet The Pelagor is a concept ground effect seaplane designed to haul cargo short distances. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/forget-supersonic-lets-make-sea-skimming-cargo-jet/

November 11, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Art of Perfectly Reviving Decades-Old Land Cruisers The FJ Company turns aging Toyotas into modern-day beauties. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/art-perfectly-reviving-decades-old-land-cruisers/

November 10, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall US Cities, Spurned by Washington, Fund Transit Themselves “There is no cavalry coming.” https://www.wired.com/2016/11/us-cities-spurned-washington-fund-transit/

November 10, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Trump’s Infrastructure Fix: Let Somebody Else Spend $1 Trillion The president-elect hopes to trigger private spending to fix America’s crumbling roads. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/trumps-plan-american-infrastructure-get-people-spend-trillion-dollars/

November 8, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Today in LOLOL: Hyperloop Pods That ‘Hyperjump’ Out of the Tube Hyperloop One’s pods will double as self-driving cars, somehow. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/today-lolol-hyperloop-pods-hyperjump-tube/

November 8, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall With Trump and Clinton Both in NYC, Cue the (Managed) Mayhem Reliably blue New York is going deep red—on the traffic maps. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/trump-clinton-nyc-cue-managed-mayhem/

November 7, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart As Tesla Grows Up, It Gives Up on Free Charging This is Tesla maturing, along with the American electric vehicle industry. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/tesla-grows-gives-free-charging/

November 7, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams China’s New Fighter Jet Can’t Touch the US Planes It Rips Off But hey, it doesn’t need to. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/china-j-20-fighter-jet/

November 4, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart NASA’s Mighty Morphing Wings Make for More Efficient Flying A new kind of wing could make aircraft fly smoother, quieter, and more efficiently. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/nasas-mighty-morphing-wings-make-efficient-flying/

November 4, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Obama Caps Off His EV Legacy by Electrifying American Highways The feds are rolling out 25,000 miles of “electric vehicle charging corridors.” https://www.wired.com/2016/11/obama-caps-off-ev-legacy-electrifying-american-highways/

November 4, 2016 | Author: Charles BombardierCharles Bombardier Let’s Help Cops With a Roaming Network of Crime-Spotting Trikes The Prowler can deter crime, or at least mitigate its effects, until the police arrive. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/lets-help-cops-roaming-network-crime-spotting-trikes/

November 4, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Hidden Art of Designing Trains for Anti-Social Commuters How BART’s designers create train cars with your needs in mind. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/hidden-art-designing-trains-anti-social-commuters/

November 3, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Uber’s Discrimination Problem Is Bad News for Public Transit Government alliances make the sharing economy’s implicit bias problem a much bigger deal. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/ubers-discrimination-problem-bad-news-public-transit/

November 3, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Cadillac’s All-Seeing Rearview Mirror Peers Into the Future of Cars The digital display rethinks and improves how the driver interacts with and sees the world around him. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/cadillac-ct6-rearview-mirror-camera/

November 2, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Inside Darpa’s Plan to Make Old Aircraft Autonomous With Robot Arms How else do you fit advanced software into planes built around cables and pulleys? https://www.wired.com/2016/11/darpa-alias-autonomous-aircraft-aurora-sikorsky/

November 2, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall It’s Time to Think About Living in Parking Garages Sustainability-minded architects prep for the future parking structures that could, one day, house humans. https://www.wired.com/2016/11/time-think-living-old-parking-garages/

October 31, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Henrik Fisker’s Back (Again) With a Tesla Rival (Again) Once again, the Danish designer has plans for a luxury electric that’ll change the industry. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/henrik-fiskers-back-tesla-rival/

October 31, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall How to Craft the Perfect Street for Trick-or-Treaters Separate the walkable neighborhoods from the pretenders on the darkest and spookiest of eves. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/craft-perfect-street-trick-treaters/

October 30, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall EnLighten App Uses AI to Predict When Lights Will Turn Green Does more information mean safer and environmentally-friendly driving? https://www.wired.com/2016/10/enlighten-app-uses-ai-predict-lights-will-turn-green/

October 28, 2016 | Author: Charles BombardierCharles Bombardier Here’s an Idea: Give Special Forces Some Flying Motorcycles The Zaxon is a tactical vehicle that uses that technology to deploy special forces. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/heres-idea-give-special-forces-flying-motorcycles/

October 28, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Step Into the Garage Where Robots Do All the Parking When it comes to storing cars efficiently, robots rule. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/step-garage-robots-parking/

October 28, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Drones May Be Cool, But the Air Force Isn’t Done With Humans To train the next generation of human pilots, the Air Force is looking for a new jet. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/drones-may-cool-air-force-isnt-done-humans/

October 27, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Inside Uber’s Plan to Take Over the Skies With Flying Cars Within a decade, ‘Uber Elevate’ could provide network of on demand, fully electric aircraft. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/uber-flying-cars-elevate-plan/

October 27, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall It’s Not Just Clean Air: Electric Cars Can Save the US Billions The healthcare and climate costs add up to $37 billion a year—for just 10 states. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/not-just-clean-air-electric-cars-can-save-us-billions/

October 25, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Uber’s Self-Driving Truck Makes Its First Delivery: 50,000 Beers Uber-owned startup Otto just sent an autonomous truck on a two-hour, 120-mile journey. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/ubers-self-driving-truck-makes-first-delivery-50000-beers/

October 25, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart In the Self-Driving Future, Cars Are the New Arcades This future presents opportunities to entertain passengers—and to sell them stuff. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/self-driving-future-means-lotsa-new-ways-sell-stuff/

October 24, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla’s Self-Driving Car Plan Seems Insane, But It Just Might Work Elon Musk promises a Tesla that can drive itself from Los Angeles to New York City, no human needed, by next year. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/teslas-self-driving-car-plan-seems-insane-just-might-work/

October 21, 2016 | Author: Charles BombardierCharles Bombardier This Beefed Up SeaDoo Could Someday Save Imperiled Surfers This concept combines the classic vehicle with a hull made to take on the rigors of the ocean. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/beefed-seadoo-someday-save-imperiled-surfers/

October 21, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Techies Don’t Think Trump Could Drive the Self-Driving Car With the vital exception of venture capitalist Peter Thiel, tomorrow-focused Silicon Valley tends to see Donald Trump as the candidate of yesterday. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/techies-dont-think-trump-drive-self-driving-car/

October 19, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Elon Musk Says Every New Tesla Can Drive Itself … But won’t, until at least the end of 2017. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/elon-musk-says-every-new-tesla-can-drive/

October 19, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Meet the Giant Robot That Builds Boeing’s Wings Boeing’s PAL will help the plane maker assemble wings twice as quickly. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/meet-giant-robot-builds-boeings-wings/

October 18, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Lamborghini, Never Subtle, Looks 1,000 Years Into the Future The Italian automaker enlists MIT’s help in pondering the supercar of the third millennium. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/lamborghini-never-subtle-looks-1000-years-future/

October 18, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Germany Says ‘Nein’ to Tesla Calling Its Tech ‘Autopilot’ As automakers brand autonomous tech, regulators push back and consumers get confused. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/germany-tesla-autopilot/

October 18, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The German Auto Industry Is Finally (Maybe) Done With Gas BMW, VW, and Mercedes promise they’re serious about electric cars, but are moving slowly. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/german-auto-industry-finally-maybe-done-gas/

October 17, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies VW’s $15B Diesel Settlement Might Actually Hurt Electric Cars Some worry forcing VW to invest in charging infrastructure could hurt the nascent market. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/vws-15b-diesel-settlement-might-actually-hurt-electric-cars/

October 16, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Xerox—Yeah, Xerox—Has Found a Way to Bust Carpool Lane Cheaters The roadside tool nabs 95 percent of folks who don’t deserve the left-most lane. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/xerox-yeah-xerox-found-way-bust-carpool-lane-cheaters/

October 14, 2016 | Author: Charles BombardierCharles Bombardier Clean Up Summer With a Self-Driving Roomba for Your Pool Like a whale, the Moobi sucks down water, filtering out waste as if it were tasty plankton. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/clean-summer-self-driving-roomba-pool/

October 14, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart How Airbus Went From Boeing Wannabe to High-Flying Legend Half a century on, Airbus can take credit for some of aviation’s most notable developments. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/airbus-went-boeing-wannabe-high-flying-innovator/

October 14, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart How Airbus Went From Boeing Wannabe to High-Flying Legend Half a century on, Airbus can take credit for some of aviation’s most notable developments. https://www.wired.com/listicle/airbus-went-boeing-wannabe-high-flying-innovator/

October 13, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall NY’s So Pumped for Cash-Free Tolls, It’s (Kinda) OK If You Don’t Pay Whatever: the long-term benefits outweigh any money lost to driving delinquents. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/nys-pumped-cash-free-tolls-kinda-ok-dont-pay/

October 12, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart BMW’s Motorcycle of Tomorrow Is All About the Feels In BMW Motorrad’s vision of the future, technology will protect the rider from crashes, but bikes won’t be totally autonomous. https://www.wired.com/listicle/bmws-motorcycle-tomorrow-feels/

October 12, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart BMW’s Motorcycle of Tomorrow Is All About the Feels In BMW Motorrad’s vision of the future, technology will protect the rider from crashes, but bikes won’t be totally autonomous. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/bmws-motorcycle-tomorrow-feels/

October 12, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Obama: The Feds Must Guarantee Self-Driving Cars Work for Everybody As humans give up the wheel, Obama says technology’s benefits must be fairly distributed. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/obama-feds-must-guarantee-self-driving-cars-work-everybody/

October 11, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Finally, Someone Adds Extra Ferrari to the $320K F12berlinetta Bengala Automotive’s F12 Caballería adds GT3 racecar styling to the Ferrari flagship. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/bengala-f12-caballeria-ferrari-f12berlinetta/

October 10, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Forget Hyperloop: This Awful-Looking Thing Can Move Your Stuff It doesn’t travel at 700 mph, but exists right now, today. Freight, climb aboard. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/forget-hyperloop-awful-looking-thing-can-move-stuff/

October 9, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Software to Make Airports Less Miserable Finally Hits the US NYC’s JFK uses the predictive power of software to monitor and forecast passenger numbers. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/software-make-airports-less-miserable-finally-hits-us/

October 7, 2016 | Author: Charles BombardierCharles Bombardier Let’s Patrol Our Pools With Aquatic Drone Lifeguards The Otari is a small submarine drone to help anyone at risk of drowning in a pool. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/lets-patrol-pools-aquatic-drone-lifeguards/

October 7, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Lockheed’s Hybrid Airship Is Part Blimp, Part Hovercraft, No Hot Air The Hybrid Airship combines the upsides of the airship with the ability of a hovercraft. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/lockheeds-hybrid-airship-part-blimp-part-hovercraft-no-hot-air/

October 6, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Inside the 737 Test Plane That Boeing Beats the Bejesus Out Of Before airlines can cram you into the new 737 MAX, Boeing’s got to prove it’s airworthy in just about any situation. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/inside-737-test-plane-boeing-beats-bejesus/

October 6, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart This New Form of Parking Enforcement Sucks. Like, Actually Sucks Imagine how you’d feel finding a six square foot block of yellow plastic splayed across your windshield, rendering it impossible to see a thing. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/parking-enforcement-barnacle-boot/

October 5, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies 50 Years of Making Hydrogen Cars, and Still No One Cares For all that time and money, the automaker has made effectively zero progress getting humanity to ditch fossil fuels for hydrogen. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/50-years-making-hydrogen-cars-still-no-one-cares/

October 5, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Google’s Robo-Cars Hit 2M Miles, Confirm Driving Is Dadgum Tricky Google doesn’t have any public plans to deploy its robo-rides, but it’s steadily gathering crucial expertise. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/googles-robo-cars-hit-2m-miles-confirm-driving-dadgum-tricky/

October 4, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart This Year’s Paris Auto Show is Très Électrisant Car makers are using the French motor show to demonstrate their latest electric automotive technology. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/years-paris-auto-show-tres-electrisante/

October 4, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart This Year’s Paris Auto Show is Très Électrisant Car makers are using the French motor show to demonstrate their latest electric automotive technology. https://www.wired.com/listicle/years-paris-auto-show-tres-electrisante/

October 4, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies This Canadian Hyperloop Concept Features a Faux Sunroof Toronto startup Transpod reveals its concept version of a pod for traveling through the still-theoretical Hyperloop. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/hyperloop-transpod-concept-canada/

October 3, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Chevy’s Making a Hydrogen-Powered Pickup for the US Army GM and the US Army are working together on a hydrogen-powered pickup truck. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/chevys-making-hydrogen-powered-pickup-us-army/

October 3, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The Painstaking Process of Building a Porsche Panamera From the quality control room to the paint shop to the test track, here’s how Porsche builds the Panamera. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/painstaking-process-building-porsche-panamera/

October 3, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The Painstaking Process of Building a Porsche Panamera From the quality control room to the paint shop to the test track, here’s how Porsche builds the Panamera. https://www.wired.com/listicle/painstaking-process-building-porsche-panamera/

September 30, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Commuter Gondolas Are Coming to America. Probably. Maybe? Austin gets weird in a brand new way. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/commuter-gondolas-coming-america-probably-maybe/

September 30, 2016 | Author: WIRED StaffWIRED Staff This Concept Drone Will Drive You Up the Wall—Literally The Ventooz is a wall-climbing, person-carrying robot. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/concept-drone-will-drive-wall-seriously/

September 30, 2016 | Author: Robin WashingtonRobin Washington Autonomous Vehicles Will Mean the End of Traffic Stops Self-driving cars will mean an end to traffic stops and chases, push-button arrests—and new tricks for terrorists. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/autonomous-vehicles-will-mean-end-traffic-stops/

September 29, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Hoboken Train Crash: Here’s What Comes Next The investigations begins, as do the renewed calls for technology that could prevent train crashes. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/hoboken-train-crash-heres-comes-next/

September 29, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Your Car Is Watching You—and Wants to Sell You Stuff Automakers just need to figure out how to handle an amazingly thick stream of car data. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/car-watching-wants-sell-stuff/

September 29, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Electric Bicycles Sure Look Dopey. But Not This Beauty Who says an e-bike has to look like a bike? https://www.wired.com/2016/09/tempus-electric-bikes-cr-t1/

September 28, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The War on City Parking Just Got Serious The White House deals a (symbolic) blow to neighborhoods hoping to keep precious spots all to themselves. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/war-parking-just-got-real-serious/

September 27, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart How Boeing Builds a 737 in Just 9 Days Boeing’s Renton plant builds 737 narrow-body jets at the rate of 42 per month, and climbing. Here’s how. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/boeing-builds-737-just-nine-days/

September 26, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Good News: The Tech to Change Your Grandma’s Life Is Already Here Now won’t somebody lead the mobility revolution? https://www.wired.com/2016/09/ridesharing-paratransit-seniors/

September 25, 2016 | Author: Charles BombardierCharles Bombardier Forget VR. The Future of Roller Coasters Is About Maglev What if there was no friction at all? What if electro magnets propelled the cars? This is the idea behind the Sfrear Mountain Coaster. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/forget-vr-future-roller-coasters-maglev/

September 21, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Apple’s Probably Not Gonna Buy McLaren, But It Should The British automaker and racing outfit has the engineering expertise that could get Apple’s software on the road. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/apple-mclaren-deal/

September 21, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Review: 2017 Porsche Panamera The new Panamera deserves your respect, if not your love. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/review-2017-porsche-panamera/

September 20, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Ignore Trump: Ford’s Move to Mexico Is Good for US Workers The best jobs are staying in the US. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/ignore-trump-fords-move-mexico-good-us-workers/

September 19, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Feds Just Got Real About Self-Driving Cars (It’s About Time) Federal regulators have announced guidelines that define a new approach to regulating, and encouraging, self-driving cars. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/feds-just-got-real-self-driving-cars-time/

September 19, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall NYC’s Subway Gridlock Could Trigger a Transit Renaissance Massive transportation disruptions might be your city’s gain. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/nycs-subway-apocalypse-trigger-transit-renaissance/

September 16, 2016 | Author: Charles BombardierCharles Bombardier Hey, Why Don’t We Just Propel Luxury Yachts With Whale Tails The real draw of the Seataci is the panoramic windows in the lower tail section of the main hull, providing an impressive view of the underwater world. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/hey-dont-just-propel-luxury-yachts-whale-tails/

September 16, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Baffling View of London’s Tube Proves Transit Maps Are (Helpful) Lies Geographic accuracy versus readability. What wins? https://www.wired.com/2016/09/baffling-view-londons-tube-proves-transit-maps-helpful-lies/

September 15, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart How This Magic Machine Tricks You Into Seeing Any Car It Wants We go hands-on with the Blackbird, an electric vehicle decked out for movie—or advertising—magic. This ugly duckling can become any automotive swan. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/magic-machine-tricks-seeing-car-wants/

September 14, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies We Take a Ride in the Self-Driving Uber Now Roaming Pittsburgh Starting this morning, pre-selected Uber users in a 12-square-mile chunk of downtown Pittsburgh will have the option to ride in a self-driving car. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/self-driving-autonomous-uber-pittsburgh/

September 13, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies A $2,400 Class to Make Anyone a Self-Driving Car Engineer Online educator Udacity is launching a 27-week, $2,400 course that promises to turn anyone with basic coding experience into a deep learning connoisseur. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/udacity-self-driving-car-engineer-nanodegree-program-thrun/

September 13, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies We Drive the $30K Chevy Bolt, GM’s Tesla-Walloping Electric Car GM says the Chevy Bolt goes 238 miles on a charge. We put it to the test. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/chevrolet-bolt-range-epa-rating/

September 12, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This New Electric Bus Can Drive 350 Miles on One Charge Proterra’s Catalyst E2 Series is aimed squarely at city public transit. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/new-electric-bus-can-drive-350-miles-one-charge/

September 11, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla’s Self-Driving Software Gets a Major Update Version 8.0 of “Autopilot” juices up the electric car’s radar to avoid crashes. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/teslas-self-driving-software-gets-major-update/

September 10, 2016 | Author: Charles BombardierCharles Bombardier Electric Bicycles Are So 2016—We Want an E-Bike Built for Two A cross between a BMW and a fat bike, the Duovelo uses a sliding mechanism to reveal a second seat for a passenger. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/electric-bicycles-2016-want-e-bike-built-two/

September 9, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Why Winnipeg’s Transit System Revived the Old-Timey Token Winnipeg Transit makes a most unusual decision. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/winnipegs-transit-system-revived-old-timey-token/

September 8, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall 3 Tips for a Hot, Sexy, Long-Lasting Relationship With a Private Mobility Company Public transportation agencies’ secrets—revealed! https://www.wired.com/2016/09/3-tips-hot-sexy-long-lasting-relationship-private-mobility-company/

September 8, 2016 | Author: Brett BerkBrett Berk Legendary Designer Tom Tjaarda on the Eternal Beauty of Italian Cars Famed car designer Tom Tjaarda reveals his favorite designs from a half century of work. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/tom-tjaarda-italian-car-design/

September 7, 2016 | Author: Laura MalloneeLaura Mallonee Thank the Flying Spaghetti Monster This Airport Isn’t Real Photographer Cassio Vasconcellos creates aerial scenes choked with planes, cars, and motorcycles. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/absolutely-miss-flight-insanely-crowded-airport/

September 6, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams To Make Drone Deliveries Work, AT&T Is Tapping Into the Cell Network Qualcomm and AT&T are collaborating to make wide-ranging drone operations reliable and safe, using current 4G LTE and future 5G networks. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/make-drone-deliveries-work-att-tapping-cell-network/

September 2, 2016 | Author: Jennifer ChausseeJennifer Chaussee Inside JetBlue’s Quest to Make Plane Food Great Again Yes, tasty airplane food exists, but not for the masses (yet). https://www.wired.com/2016/09/inside-jetblues-quest-make-plane-food-great/

September 2, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies That Shipping Giant’s Collapse Is No Reason to Become a Pirate The bankruptcy of Korean shipping giant Hanjin will make life on the high seas a bit more expensive and a bunch more complicated. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/hanjin-bankruptcy-shipping-economy/

September 2, 2016 | Author: Charles BombardierCharles Bombardier How About a Self-Driving Car That Folds Up When You’re Done Driving? The Swing is an autonomous car that can alter its seating setup and shape depending on where you are, what you’re doing, and how you feel. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/self-driving-car-folds-youre-done-driving/

September 2, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Four-Year Fight to Make San Francisco’s Subway Stop Screaming This is what it takes to make your commute quieter. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/three-year-fight-make-san-franciscos-subway-stop-screaming/

September 1, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Somehow, Way Too Many Americans Still Aren’t Wearing Seat Belts New federal data shows that nearly half of the people killed in cars last year decided to forego that buckling up thing. https://www.wired.com/2016/09/somehow-way-many-americans-still-arent-wearing-seat-belts/

August 31, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies That Crazy Hyperloop Lawsuit Just Got Even Nastier The wild legal battle between the founders of the company leading the race to build Elon Musk’s Hyperloop took a nasty turn today. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/hyperloop-one-lawsuit-bambrogan-pishevar/

August 31, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies One Guy’s Years-Long Quest to Turn a Wrecked Classic Into a Racecar Dave Hogye spent four and a half years turning a rusted out 1959 Triumph into a racecar. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/one-guys-years-long-quest-turn-wrecked-classic-racecar/

August 30, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall How to Ace the FAA’s New Test and Become a Pro Drone Pilot Drone regulations kicked in yesterday, and the first ones to pass have spoken. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/ace-faas-new-test-become-pro-drone-pilot/

August 30, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Plan to Make Self-Driving Cars Speak Human Startup Drive.ai wants to make fully autonomous cars that speak with the drivers, pedestrians, and cyclists around them. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/driveai-autonomous-self-driving-cars/

August 29, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall London’s Subway Now Runs All Night, So Why Doesn’t Yours? Seven excuses, from money to a lack of creativity. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/londons-subway-now-runs-night-doesnt/

August 28, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Meet the Swankiest People of America’s Swankiest Car Competition The annual Pebble Beach Concours d’Elegance is a fierce car competition, but also a place to see and be seen. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/among-classy-crowds-americas-swankiest-car-competition/

August 27, 2016 | Author: Charles BombardierCharles Bombardier Forget Self-Driving Cars. Let’s Make Self-Driving Living Rooms The Tridika works like a self-driving car you can literally park alongside your apartment and use as an additional room. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/forget-self-driving-cars-lets-make-self-driving-living-rooms/

August 26, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Feds Just Gave Amtrak $2.4 Billion. This Is Why It Needs the Money How to spend a few billion on railroads like an old-timey tycoon. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/feds-just-gave-amtrak-2-4-billion-needs-money/

August 26, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Everyone Wants a Level 5 Self-Driving Car—Here’s What That Means As cars that drive themselves evolve and spread over the coming years, here’s a guide for understanding what’s left for you to do. https://www.wired.com/listicle/self-driving-car-levels-sae-nhtsa/

August 26, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Everyone Wants a Level 5 Self-Driving Car—Here’s What That Means As cars that drive themselves evolve and spread over the coming years, here’s a guide for understanding what’s left for you to do. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/self-driving-car-levels-sae-nhtsa/

August 26, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Why It’s Taking Fooorever to Get Countdown Clocks in NYC’s Subway The long, tumultuous nightmare that is updating a 100-year-old subway system. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/taking-fooorever-get-countdown-clocks-nycs-subway/

August 25, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Flying Bum Just Crashed—So Why Are We Building Airships? Turns out this may be the—second—age of the dirigible. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/airlander-flying-bum-crash-airships-advantages/

August 25, 2016 | Author: Laura BlissLaura Bliss You Have No Idea How Hard It Is to Waterproof NYC’s Subway Thanks to a $4 billion federal fix, MTA is testing out space-age flood barriers and “tunnel plugs.” https://www.wired.com/2016/08/no-idea-hard-waterproof-nycs-subway/

August 24, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Germany’s NASA Crashes a Train to Keep You Safe New frontiers in the art of the crumple zone. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/germanys-nasa-crashes-train-keep-safe/

August 24, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Lazy Automakers Can Just Buy Self-Driving Cars From Delphi Technology suppliers Mobileye and Delphi announce a big-deal partnership. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/lazy-automakers-can-just-buy-self-driving-cars-delphi/

August 23, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Tesla’s Model S Now Does an Even Loonier 60 MPH in 2.5 Seconds Tesla Motors announced today that the new Model S P100D model will hit 60 mph in 2.5 seconds, thanks to a bigger, 100-kWh battery. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/tesla-model-s-ludicrous-100-battery-news/

August 23, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies 5 Spectacular Cars That Just Sold for Millions Gooding and Company just auctioned off 114 cars for an average of $1.1 million a pop. Here are five of the coolest cars that crossed the block. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/5-spectacular-cars-just-sold-millions/

August 22, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Airplane Tires Don’t Explode on Landing Because They Are Pumped! They’re like the tires on your car—but way stronger. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/airplane-tires/

August 22, 2016 | Author: Charley LockeCharley Locke Inside the Crazy ‘Sport’ Where Rich Kids Drift and Crash SUVs The rules of hajwalah are easy to understand, if not execute. The more reckless you are, the better. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/inside-crazy-sport-rich-kids-recklessly-race-suvs/

August 21, 2016 | Author: Charles BombardierCharles Bombardier Get to Know Each Other Aboard This Self-Driving Motorcycle The Cyclotron, an imagined enclosed driverless motorcycle, would accommodate two passengers facing each other. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/get-know-aboard-self-driving-motorcycle/

August 20, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies You Will Now Ogle 30 Lamborghini Miuras in One Place To mark the half century since Lamborghini justified its existence, drivers from all over the US brought their Miuras to Monterey. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/will-now-ogle-30-lamborghini-miuras-one-place/

August 19, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Mercedes’ New Concept Is a Maybach for the Electric Age The Vision Mercedes-Maybach 6 concept is nearly 20 feet long and packs a battery of swanky, futuristic features. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/mercedes-new-concept-maybach-electric-age/

August 19, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The British Sports Car That Became Ford’s Famed GT40 The Lola Mk 6 is the little known basis for Ford’s famed GT. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/lola-mark-6-ford-gt40/

August 19, 2016 | Author: Aarian Marshall, Alex DaviesAarian Marshall and Alex Davies How Pittsburgh Birthed the Age of the Self-Driving Car Uber’s launching a fleet of self-driving cars in the Steel City, starting in a few weeks. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/pittsburgh-birthed-age-self-driving-car/

August 19, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Inside the Fisker Karma’s Impossible Return From Automotive Hell An exclusive look at how Karma Automotive brought the lovely, doomed Fisker Karma back to life. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/fisker-karma-automotive-revero/

August 18, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall 12 Outrageous Cars You Can Buy This Weekend if You’re a Bajillionaire These gorgeous vehicles are actually up for sale during the Pebble Beach Concours d’Elegance festivities. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/pebble-beach-auctions-cars-2016/

August 17, 2016 | Author: WIRED StaffWIRED Staff US vs. UK Live Debate! What’s the Right Kind of Intersection? We’re hashing out the best way to move people quickly and safely through a city. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/live-debate-whats-right-kind-intersection/

August 17, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla’s Cars Have Driven 140M Miles on Autopilot. Here’s How Everything you ever wanted to know about how Elon Musk’s cars drive themselves https://www.wired.com/2016/08/how-tesla-autopilot-works/

August 16, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Transit Pros Rebuild the NYC Subway—in an Online Game We asked transportation experts to take their (digital) shovels to NYC’s subway system. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/transit-pros-rebuild-nyc-subway-online-game/

August 16, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Transit Pros Rebuild the NYC Subway—in an Online Game We asked transportation experts to take their (digital) shovels to NYC’s subway system. https://www.wired.com/listicle/transit-pros-rebuild-nyc-subway-online-game/

August 16, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Ford Says It’ll Have a Fleet of Fully Autonomous Cars in Just 5 Years The automaker promises to have a fleet of hundreds of fully autonomous cars in service in five years. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/ford-autonomous-vehicles-2021/

August 16, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Nissan’s Crafty Engine Ends a Century of Compromise Nissan has finally figured out the variable compression ratio engine, and it means you get more power from less fuel. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/nissans-crafty-engine-ends-century-compromise/

August 15, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Custom Jalopies That Move Travelers Across Continents Trucks, vans, and cycles customized for adventure. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/custom-jalopies-move-travelers-across-continents/

August 14, 2016 | Author: Charles BombardierCharles Bombardier It’s Time for Fancy Apartments to Offer Balconies for Drone Landings Drones are coming, and they’re going to change a lot of things about how we shape our lives. So why shouldn’t we change how we shape our buildings? https://www.wired.com/2016/08/time-fancy-apartments-offer-balconies-drone-landings/

August 13, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Downtown Manhattan Is the New Frontier of the Car-Free City How a brief experiment in car-free living could change the city for the better and for good. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/downtown-manhattan-new-frontier-car-free-city/

August 12, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart How to Fight the Turbulence That Just Injured 24 JetBlue Fliers A Jet Blue plane hit turbulence so severe, it ripped the toilet off its housing, knocked a flight attendant into the ceiling, and injured 24 people. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/turbulence-jetblue-flight-429-injuries/

August 12, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams What It Takes to Make a Motorcycle Hit 400MPH Triumph built the Streamliner to do one thing: top 376.363 mph on the Bonneville Salt Flats to become the fastest motorcycle on the planet. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/make-motorcycle-go-400mph-make-25-feet-long/

August 11, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Electric Fisker Karma Is Back—And This Time It Works The newly christened Karma Revero looks a lot like the old Fisker, but with a year’s worth of engineering upgrades. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/karma-revero-fisker-electric-photos/

August 11, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Startup That Could Help GM Beat Google to the Self-Driving Car Four months after General Motors bought Cruise Automation, the San Francisco-based startup is racing Google to build fully autonomous cars. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/gm-cruise-automation-self-driving-vogt/

August 10, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Drop the Jackhammer and Fix Your Bridge With This Giant Waterpik Hydro demolition is a faster, easier, cheaper way to scrape away old concrete. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/drop-jackhammer-fix-bridge-giant-waterpik/

August 8, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart How a Computer Outage Can Take Down a Whole Airline A computer outage in Atlanta forced Delta to cancel more than 650 flights all over the world. How can that happen? https://www.wired.com/2016/08/computer-outage-can-take-whole-airline/

August 8, 2016 | Author: WIRED StaffWIRED Staff Flight Mode: The Quest to Make Flying Safer, Faster, and Comfier To get a look at how the industry’s pushing forward, we ventured beyond the locked doors of the airport. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/flight-mode-quest-make-flying-safer-faster-comfier/

August 8, 2016 | Author: WIRED StaffWIRED Staff Flight Mode: The Quest to Make Flying Safer, Faster, and Comfier To get a look at how the industry’s pushing forward, we ventured beyond the locked doors of the airport. https://www.wired.com/listicle/flight-mode-quest-make-flying-safer-faster-comfier/

August 8, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Crafty Ideas to Make Drone Deliveries Work for Everybody Airbus and Local Motors sponsored a contest to create a deliver drone that works for a variety of users, not just corporate players. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/crafty-ideas-make-drone-deliveries-work-everybody/

August 7, 2016 | Author: Charles BombardierCharles Bombardier You Could Roll on Land or the Seafloor in This Fanciful Concept Car The Libelule is spherical vehicle with two large wheels that allow it to travel almost anywhere. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/roll-land-seafloor-fanciful-concept-car/

August 7, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall How to Host the Olympics and Actually Improve Your City’s Transit The games may seem like a great way to spark transit improvements, but making that work isn’t easy. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/host-olympics-actually-improve-citys-transit/

August 5, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Too Bad You’ll Never Drive Nissan’s Razor-Like Electric Concept Nissan’s BladeGlider concept is for those who like their cars lean, green, and byzantine. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/bad-youll-never-drive-nissans-razor-like-electric-concept/

August 5, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Swap Those Plastic Buttons for $385 Cufflinks Made From a Bugatti Veyron TMB Art Metal makes the snazzy accessories from the damaged front wheel of a Veyron. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/bugatti-veyron-cufflinks-tmb-metal/

August 4, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall So, a Few Concerns About China’s Traffic-Slaying ‘Straddling Bus’ Including, is this really a bus? https://www.wired.com/2016/08/concerns-chinas-traffic-slaying-straddling-bus/

August 4, 2016 | Author: Basem WasefBasem Wasef Review: 2017 Aston Martin DB11 The DB11 is a much needed redefinition of what makes an Aston an Aston. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/review-2017-aston-martin-db11/

August 4, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart It’s No Miracle Everyone Escaped That Fiery Dubai Plane Crash The evacuation of Emirates flight EK521 is a reminder of how well modern aviation safety standards can work. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/dubai-plane-crash-emirates-flight-ek521/

August 3, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Brilliant Sorcery of England’s 7-Circle Magic Roundabout Swindon’s “magic roundabout” is a mystifying but brilliant traffic solution. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/brilliant-sorcery-englands-7-circle-magic-roundabout/

August 3, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Berliners Can Now Share Gogoro’s Swanky Electric Scooters Gogoro’s sleek but pricey Smartscooter is the launch vehicle for Berlin’s latest scooter sharing service. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/gogoro-electric-scooters-coup-berlin/

August 2, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams New Navy Tech Makes It Easy to Land on a Carrier. Yes, Easy The “Magic Carpet” reduces pilot strain, saves money, and marks the US military’s greatest acronym yet. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/new-navy-tech-makes-landing-aircraft-carrier-breeze/

August 1, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Aston Martin’s $3M Hypercar Takes F1 Performance to the Road Making a car that can keep up with Formula 1 racers on a track, and be an enjoyable street ride is nearly impossible. But there is a precedent. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/aston-martins-new-hypercar-clever-3m-beast/

August 1, 2016 | Author: Laura MalloneeLaura Mallonee Train With the Men of Russia’s Fighter Pilot Academy When the Soviet Union collapsed, it took the air force with it. Today, Russia is slowly building it back. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/maxim-babenko-russian-fighter-pilots/

July 31, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Crime Alerts Come to Brazilian Waze, Just in Time for the Olympics But will they actually keep people safe? https://www.wired.com/2016/07/crime-alerts-come-brazilian-waze-just-time-olympics/

July 30, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Live Out All Your Racing Dreams With … Magnets? On a fridge. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/blipshift-formula-fridge-magnets/

July 29, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Watch an Electric Corvette Obliterate Its Own Speed Record Setting the world record for an all electric, street legal vehicle wasn’t enough for Genovation. They wanted to break it. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/watch-electric-corvette-obliterate-speed-record/

July 29, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall So Digital Billboard Ads Change With the Speed of Traffic Now A little traffic data creates big opportunities for people selling yogurt. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/digital-billboard-ads-change-speed-traffic-now/

July 28, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Fancy Tech Pilots Use to Keep Your Flight Turbulence-Free Bumpy violent air is more than just annoying for passengers, it’s damaging and expensive for airlines. But new cockpit tech is helping pilots avoid it. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/fancy-tech-pilots-use-keep-flight-turbulence-free/

July 28, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Car Ads Didn’t Used to Be So Bleh. They Were Serious Art Take a trip back to the golden age of beautiful cars—and the brochures that sold them. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/car-ads-didnt-used-bleh-serious-art/

July 27, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart This Is the Enormous Gigafactory, Where Tesla Will Build Its Future By 2020 Tesla plans to consume more batteries than the rest of the world combined. This is where it will make them. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/tesla-gigafactory-elon-musk/

July 26, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall You Don’t Like Sharing Your Car. But Can Elon Musk Change Your Mind? Big-time automakers puzzle out the future of ownership. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/dont-like-sharing-car-can-elon-musk-change-mind/

July 25, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Solar Impulse Just Completed Its Momentous Flight Around the World The Rocky of sun-powered airplanes beats the odds. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/solar-impulse-just-completed-momentous-flight-around-world/

July 25, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart An Electric Corvette Could Destroy a World Record—Again The makers of an electric Corvette aren’t content with holding the speed record at 186.8mph. They want to go faster. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/electric-corvette-destroy-world-record/

July 22, 2016 | Author: Basem WasefBasem Wasef Review: Energica Eva Electric Sportbike The Energica Eva may be the world’s easiest to ride sportbike, but it’s not cheap, and it’s no lightweight. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/review-energica-eva-electric-sportbike/

July 21, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart What It’s Like to Narrowly Avert Disaster in an $18M Airliner Sim Pilots spend hours in multimillion-dollar simulators, preparing for the worst-case scenario. So if it happens in real life, they’ll be ready. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/like-narrowly-avert-disaster-18m-airliner-sim/

July 20, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla’s Plan for World Domination Includes Buses and Semis Tesla’s plans just got way bigger. In a blog post Elon Musk announced a new range of vehicles and ride-sharing. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/teslas-plan-world-domination-includes-buses-semis/

July 20, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The US May Finally Get a Cheap Alternative to the $70 Million V-22 Osprey For less than a third the price of each $70 million Osprey, the Army will get nearly the same performance from the V-280 Valor. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/bell-v280-valor-v22-osprey-replacement/

July 19, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Boy, the GOP’s Platform Really Rails on Public Transit Goodbye subways! Goodbye bikes! Goodbye pedestrians strolling at night! https://www.wired.com/2016/07/gop-republican-platform-infrastructure-public-transportation/

July 19, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Hyperloop One Fires Back With Its Own Wild Lawsuit The countersuit fires back at each allegation with a different side of the story. And that was a lasso, not a noose. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/hyperloop-one-fires-back-wild-lawsuit/

July 19, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The NYC Subway’s Getting a Much-Needed Facelift These are some attractive quick fixes for a transportation network stretched well beyond its capacity. https://www.wired.com/listicle/nyc-mta-subway-train-station-car-upgrades/

July 19, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The NYC Subway’s Getting a Much-Needed Facelift These are some attractive quick fixes for a transportation network stretched well beyond its capacity. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/nyc-mta-subway-train-station-car-upgrades/

July 19, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The EPA’s Fuel Efficiency Testing May Not Work. Like, at All The EPA’s test to make sure automakers are hitting their CAFE fuel requirements numbers may not work at all. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/epa-testing-broken-heres-fix/

July 18, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Russia’s New Jet for Athletes Definitely Won’t Have a Doping Room Sukhoi Civil Aircraft just unveiled the first-of-its-kind “SportJet” model filled with massage tables, fitness equipment, and more. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/russias-new-jet-athletes-definitely-wont-doping-room/

July 17, 2016 | Author: Rachel Stohl, Shannon DickRachel Stohl and Shannon Dick The Feds Just Put the US Back in the Global Drone Race New drone guidelines will catalyze American innovation in the global marketplace, but there’s work left to do. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/feds-just-put-us-back-global-drone-race/

July 16, 2016 | Author: Charles BombardierCharles Bombardier This Drone Would Swim Through Lava—if Someone Could Build It To develop a vehicle capable of clawing into the heart of our planet, start by designing and testing such a vehicle in lakes of lava near volcanoes. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/drone-swim-lava-someone-build/

July 15, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies So Ford Didn’t Quite Finish Reading Old Yeller This Ole Yeller is actually a Shelby GT350 Mustang, powered by a 5.2-liter V8 engine that barks out 526 horsepower and 429 pound-paws of torque. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/ford-didnt-quite-finish-reading-old-yeller/

July 15, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Happy 100th Birthday, Boeing: This Is Your Life The world’s largest aerospace company is 100 years old. Over the last century its planes have transformed our world and the way we move around it. https://www.wired.com/listicle/greatest-feats-inventions-100-years-boeing/

July 15, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Happy 100th Birthday, Boeing: This Is Your Life The world’s largest aerospace company is 100 years old. Over the last century its planes have transformed our world and the way we move around it. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/greatest-feats-inventions-100-years-boeing/

July 15, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Clever AI Turns a World of Lasers Into Maps for Self-Driving Cars With a fresh pile of cash, startup Civil Maps is racing Google, Here, and others to teach self-driving cars to see and understand their world. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/civil-maps-self-driving-car-autonomous-mapping-lidar/

July 14, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Your Luggage’s Grand Robotic Adventure From Check-In to the Clouds To reach your plane at the same time you do, your bag flies through the bowels of the airport on a roller coaster ride that would make Six Flags jealous. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/where-checked-bags-go-airport/

July 14, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Yes, a ‘Submerged Floating Bridge’ Is a Reasonable Way to Cross a Fjord The first one in the world, maybe coming to a fjord near you. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/submerged-floating-bridge-isnt-worst-idea-norways-ever/

July 13, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Mercedes Just Made the Coolest Golf Cart of All Time, Because Sure Mercedes wants to do for golf carts what Tesla did for EVs, which used to be compared to … golf carts. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/mercedes-just-made-coolest-golf-cart-time-sure/

July 13, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies GM’s Roboglove Will Turn Workers Into Cyborgs GM’s building a power-assisted glove that will make spinning a wrench a whole lot easier. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/gm-nasa-roboglove-robonaut/

July 12, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies This Hyperloop Lawsuit Is Insane The co-founders of Hyperloop One are suing each other, and the details involve a suspiciously overpaid fiancée, an attempted coup, and a noose. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/hyperloop-lawsuit-brogan-bambrogan-shervin-pishevar/

July 12, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Public Transit Riders Want Better Service, Not Free WiFi Surprise—people care more about reliability and practicality than frills. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/public-transit-riders-want-better-service-not-free-wifi/

July 12, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Cash-Strapped Towns Are Un-Paving Roads They Can’t Afford to Fix Rural areas all over the country are embracing this kind of strategic retreat. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/cash-strapped-towns-un-paving-roads-cant-afford-fix/

July 11, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart A Tesla Co-Founder Is Making Electric Garbage Trucks With Jet Tech, and Why Not Ian Wright is using turbine engines to keep electric garbage trucks on the road. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/tesla-co-founder-making-electric-garbage-trucks-jet-tech-not/

July 9, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Brutally Secretive Life of the Racing Tire In the world of motorsports, even things as seemingly simple as tires are worth serious protection. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/motorsports-f1-indy-tire-development-secrecy/

July 8, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Watch London Get Its Shiny New Crossrail Tunnels Ready for Action 1,200 workers are spending 24 hours a day converting the underground tunnels, some of them 130 feet below the surface, into actual train tracks. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/london-crossrail-construction-photos-video/

July 8, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Army’s Self-Driving Trucks Hit the Highway to Prepare for Battle Semi-autonomous trucks take to the interstate. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/armys-self-driving-trucks-hit-highway-prepare-battle/

July 8, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Grab a Barf Bag and Watch Boeing’s 787-9 Fly Like a Fighter Jet This test flight was a chance for the captains to have some fun, and practice ahead of their upcoming technical demonstration at the Farnborough International Airshow next week. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/boeing-dreamliner-787-9-demonstration-flight-video/

July 7, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies VW’s Dune Beetle Is a City Car Raring for a Road Trip This unassuming droptop bug offers a convincing blend of everything a car should be: It’s handsome, affordable, efficient, practical, and fun. https://www.wired.com/listicle/vw-dune-beetle-review/

July 7, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies VW’s Dune Beetle Is a City Car Raring for a Road Trip This unassuming droptop bug offers a convincing blend of everything a car should be: It’s handsome, affordable, efficient, practical, and fun. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/vw-dune-beetle-review/

July 7, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart A Rare Look Inside the Vault Where Rebuilt Jet Engines Prove They Can Fly We take you inside Delta’s tech ops facility, where engineers tear down engines, put them back together, then run a battery of tests on them. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/rare-look-inside-vault-rebuilt-jet-engines-prove-can-fly/

July 6, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The LaFerrari Supercar Convertible Is the New Best Way to Burn $1M The roofless version of the LaFerrari is on its way. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/ferrari-laferrari-spider-convertible-photos-specs/

July 6, 2016 | Author: Hélène BauerHélène Bauer Paris Opens the First Stretch of Its 28-Mile Bike Superhighway Part of the city’s plans to reduce air pollution, the first leg of the new system debuted last May. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/paris-opens-first-stretch-28-mile-bike-superhighway/

July 5, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall There Are Better Ways to Kill Traffic Than Lying to Waze There are ways to banish the traffic outside your door. Your just have to shell out some cold, hard cash. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/better-ways-kill-traffic-lying-waze/

July 4, 2016 | Author: Charles BombardierCharles Bombardier Travel the Solar System Aboard a Train That Never Stops The Solar Express is a conceptual space train that would ferry humans, supplies, and minerals around our solar system. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/travel-solar-system-aboard-train-never-stops/

July 3, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Gawk at the Inner Workings of France’s Pre-War Classic Cars The Mullin Automotive Museum invited visitors to gawk at the inner workings of its collection of French vehicles. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/gawk-inner-workings-frances-pre-war-classic-cars/

July 2, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall This Go-Kart Modeled After a 1923 Racecar Revs Our Engines Built from ultra-light materials and a father’s love. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/go-kart-modeled-1923-racecar-revs-engines/

July 1, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall BMW’s Bold Plan to Make a Fully Self-Driving Car by 2021 A partnership between the German carmaker and tech companies promises a totally autonomous car by 2021. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/bmws-bold-plan-make-fully-self-driving-car-2021/

July 1, 2016 | Author: WIRED StaffWIRED Staff Venture Inside the Command Center of the World’s Largest Airline In the first installment of our series Flight Mode, we visit Delta mission control, where 300 people watch thousands of planes to keep everything running smoothly. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/wired-flight-mode/

June 30, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Tesla’s Autopilot Has Had Its First Deadly Crash Tesla’s Autopilot has been involved in its first deadly crash, and the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration is investigating. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/teslas-autopilot-first-deadly-crash/

June 30, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies VW’s $15B Diesel Apology Could Finally Push EVs Mainstream Now that VW’s sins have generated a huge windfall, America’s chances of accelerating away from driving on compressed dinosaurs are looking pretty good. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/vws-15b-diesel-apology-finally-push-evs-mainstream/

June 29, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Happy 60th Birthday, Interstate Highway System! You Look Awful A three-step intervention for a middle-aged infrastructure project. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/happy-60th-birthday-interstate-highway-system-look-awful/

June 29, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Porsche’s New Panamera Is Your Family-Friendly Supercar The new Panamera is sleeker and more refined, with enough enhancements to push it into the supercar stratosphere. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/porsches-new-panamera-family-friendly-supercar/

June 28, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Here’s How to Cash in on VW’s Dirty Diesel Settlement If you own, lease, or have owned or leased a definitely not clean diesels, here’s how to get your restitution. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/heres-cash-vws-dirty-diesel-settlement/

June 28, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Rio Spends $600M to Make Its Airport More Bearable Before the Olympics The airport gets a tech makeover, right in time for the Olympics. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/rios-airport-gets-much-needed-digital-makeover-just-time-olympics/

June 27, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Ford’s Extra Special GT Supercar Is a Rolling Ode to American Dominance The 2017 Ford GT ’66 Heritage Edition is a dressed up homage to the beast that won the 24 Hours of Le Mans outright 50 years ago. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/fords-extra-special-gt-supercar-rolling-ode-american-dominance/

June 27, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies VW’s Gonna Drop $15B to Clean Up Its Diesel Mess in the US Volkswagen will pay more than $15 billion to atone for its diesel cheating scandal in the United States. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/vws-gonna-drop-15b-clean-diesel-mess-us/

June 27, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Mercedes’s New E-Class Kinda Drives Itself—And It’s Kinda Confusing The 2017 E-Class does many things well, but its new interface doesn’t match up to its autonomous capabilities. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/mercedess-new-e-class-kinda-drives-kinda-confusing/

June 26, 2016 | Author: Jonathan WelshJonathan Welsh This $15K Electric Motorcycle Made Me Love Riding in NYC Alta Motors’ electric RedShift SM may be the ultimate commuter bike. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/15k-electric-motorcycle-made-love-riding-nyc/

June 24, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Aston Martin’s Custom-Made Roadster Is Most Certainly Not for You The Brits based this special roadster on the GT12 Coupe, voting to ditch the roof hear the naturally aspirated 6.0-liter V12 roar. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/aston-martins-custom-made-roadster-certainly-not/

June 24, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Climb Into the Cockpits of History’s Greatest Warplanes, From WWI to Today See the pilot’s view of everything from the Bristol F.2B to the B-17 to the long-awaited F-35. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/fighting-cockpits-donald-nijboer/

June 24, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Maglev Elevator Also Goes Sideways, Straight Up Willy Wonka Style Willy Wonka goes subway, for accessibility’s sake. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/maglev-elevator-also-goes-sideways-straight-willy-wonka-style/

June 23, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart People Want Self-Driving Cars That Save Lives. Especially Theirs A new study in Science finds people want self-driving cars that serve the greater good—until they’re the passenger. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/people-want-self-driving-cars-save-lives-especially/

June 23, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Columbus Just Won $50 Million to Become the City of the Future The Ohio city wins the Department of Transportation’s $50 million challenge. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/columbus-wins-50-million-become-city-future/

June 23, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla’s Done Being an Automaker—It’s Now an Energy Company Forget “well to wheels.” Tesla’s talking generation to acceleration. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/tesla-solar-city-elon-musk/

June 23, 2016 | Author: Amelia RinaAmelia Rina Claustrophobic Photos Go Inside Manila’s Traffic Nightmare Manila was crowned “worst traffic in the world.” These fisheye photos stick you into the cramped taxis, buses and trains that gridlock the city. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/lawrence-sumulong-bottleneck/

June 22, 2016 | Author: WIRED StaffWIRED Staff 24 Vehicles We’d Rather Meet in Traffic Than a Dodge Viper The biggest problem with the hard to drive, easy to spin Viper has always been the person who said “I want that car, and I’m gonna drive it to work.” https://www.wired.com/dummy-identifier-2016/06/24-vehicles-wed-rather-meet-traffic-dodge-viper/

June 22, 2016 | Author: WIRED StaffWIRED Staff 24 Vehicles We’d Rather Meet in Traffic Than a Dodge Viper The biggest problem with the hard to drive, easy to spin Viper has always been the person who said “I want that car, and I’m gonna drive it to work.” https://www.wired.com/2016/06/24-vehicles-wed-rather-meet-traffic-dodge-viper/

June 22, 2016 | Author: WIRED StaffWIRED Staff 24 Vehicles We’d Rather Meet in Traffic Than a Dodge Viper The biggest problem with the hard to drive, easy to spin Viper has always been the person who said “I want that car, and I’m gonna drive it to work.” https://www.wired.com/listicle/24-vehicles-wed-rather-meet-traffic-dodge-viper/

June 22, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Drones Are Now Inspecting NYC’s Famed Steam System Con Ed wants to replace human inspections of its steam boilers with carbon fiber-armored drones. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/drones-now-inspecting-nycs-famed-steam-system/

June 21, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Feds Just Made It Way Easier to Use Drones for Profit The Federal Aviation Administration today announced rules that will encourage but rein in commercial drone operations. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/faa-drones-rules-regulations-commercial-use/

June 21, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Apple Alums Dream Up a $500 Backup Camera For Any Car Pearl’s after-market wireless rearview camera is simple, elegant setup great for anybody with $500, a smartphone, and a screwdriver. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/apple-pearl-backup-rearview-camera/

June 20, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Most Ultimate Driving Machine (That You’ll Never Drive) The BMW group is releasing some insane concepts. From them, we can glean what they have planned for future cars. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/bmw-vision-next-100-concept/

June 20, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Most Ultimate Driving Machine (That You’ll Never Drive) The BMW group is releasing some insane concepts. From them, we can glean what they have planned for future cars. https://www.wired.com/listicle/bmw-vision-next-100-concept/

June 17, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Step Into the Huge Factory Forging America’s Fancy New Trains Inside the Siemens factory that’s making the rolling stock for Florida’s privately-funded intercity rail system. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/siemens-brightline-florida-factory-trains/

June 17, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Most Over-the-Top Features in Today’s Fanciest Cars Mercedes, BMW, Audi, and others endlessly one-up each other with fancy features, whether cool, helpful, or useless. https://www.wired.com/listicle/top-features-todays-fanciest-cars/

June 17, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Most Over-the-Top Features in Today’s Fanciest Cars Mercedes, BMW, Audi, and others endlessly one-up each other with fancy features, whether cool, helpful, or useless. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/top-features-todays-fanciest-cars/

June 16, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Rolls-Royce’s Ridiculous New Concept Hails the 22nd-Century Oligarch The “Rolls-Royce VISION NEXT 100” imagines and satisfies the self-glorifying demands of the 22nd century oligarch. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/rolls-royces-ridiculous-new-concept-hails-22nd-century-oligarch/

June 16, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies IBM’s Watson Lets You Talk to Your Self-Driving Car The 3-D printed autonomous van can chat with passengers, a novel way to establish human trust in the robots that will soon take over our roads. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/ibms-using-watson-make-self-driving-cars-talk-humans/

June 16, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Get Ready for Quieter NYC Subway Stations (Yes, It’s Possible) The Second Avenue subway is coming—for real this time. This is how New York acoustic engineers will muffle its roar. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/get-ready-quieter-nyc-subway-stations-yes-possible/

June 15, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Search Party Finds the Wreckage of EgyptAir Flight 804 The real key is that the jet’s black boxes are likely to be in the vicinity. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/wreckage-egyptair-flight-804-found/

June 15, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams This Bizarre Private Jet Concept Might Fly—But It Won’t Take You Far Lilium Aviation’s electric, fan-powered vertical takeoff and landing commuter aircraft resembles a football glued onto a harmonica. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/lilium-electric-personal-jet-concept/

June 15, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Inside China’s Plan to Beat America to the Self-Driving Car Despite monstrous traffic and crazy roads, China has the right factors to host the first commercially available driverless cars. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/chinas-plan-first-country-self-driving-cars/

June 14, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart A Powerful Yet Tiny Engine Inches Closer to Powering EVs and Drones Today, the X Mini rotary engine powers a go-kart. Tomorrow, it could power everything from drones to electric cars. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/tiny-engine-one-step-closer-powering-drones-electric-cars/

June 13, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies At Last: Maserati Brings the Quattroporte Into the 21st Century Maserati’s flagship sedan finally gets tech features to match those of its German competitors. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/last-maserati-brings-quattroporte-21st-century/

June 13, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Acura Electrifies Its NSX Supercar to Take on a Brutal Mountain Race Two new variants of the NSX hybrid will race Pikes Peak, along with an all-electric version that could obliterate the Colorado mountain. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/acura-electric-supercar-nsx-pikes-peak/

June 10, 2016 | Author: Zoe MendelsonZoe Mendelson That Time an Astronaut Lost His Wedding Ring in Space A lost wedding ring may be the only sort of challenge astronauts in the Apollo program didn’t train for. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/time-astronaut-lost-wedding-ring-space/

June 10, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Lonely Transatlantic Journey of a Self-Sailing Solar Ship Solar Voyager is an 18-foot, self-sailing, sun-powered boat headed for Portugal. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/lonely-transatlantic-journey-self-sailing-solar-ship/

June 10, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Nice Minnesotans Don’t Get the Cruelly Efficient Zipper Merge Minnesota has been trying to get its famously nice drivers to zipper merge for more than five years. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/nice-minnesotans-dont-get-cruelly-efficient-zipper-merge/

June 10, 2016 | Author: Tim MoynihanTim Moynihan It’s a Good Thing the F-35’s $400K Helmet Is Stupid Cool With a state-of-the-art helmet and an airframe packed with intelligent sensors, augmented reality is a major part of the F-35 fighter jet. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/course-f-35-comes-400000-augmented-reality-helmet/

June 10, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Tesla’s Plan to Rule the Auto Industry? In-App Purchases Tesla’s new, cheaper Model S is actually part of a long-running plan to keep revenue flowing in. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/teslas-plan-rule-auto-industry-app-purchases/

June 9, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Tesla’s Cheaper Model S Is a Taste of the Model 3 Tesla will introduce a Model S with a less powerful 60 kilowatt-hour battery pack, at a base price of $66,000. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/teslas-cheaper-model-s-taste-model-3/

June 8, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies McLaren’s 675LT Supercar Somehow Gets Even MOAR Carbon Fiber The McLaren Special Operations Carbon Series LT is a special version of the 675LT Spider supercar. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/mclarens-675lt-supercar-somehow-gets-even-moar-carbon-fiber/

June 8, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies LA’s Using Energy Savings From LED Streetlights to Charge Electric Vehicles Los Angeles is using electricity saved by LEDs to power up electric cars. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/las-using-energy-savings-led-streetlights-charge-electric-vehicles/

June 7, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Transit Nerds Get a Handy New Tool for Easily Turning Data Into Apps A new open source mapping and routing tool gives developers a chance to lead a grassroots transit revolution. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/transit-nerds-get-handy-new-tool-easily-turning-data-apps/

June 7, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams 8 Lessons for Fixing the Cities of the Future The world’s transportation experts gathered in Germany last month—here’s the best of their shared wisdom. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/8-lessons-fixing-cities-future/

June 7, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams 8 Lessons for Fixing the Cities of the Future The world’s transportation experts gathered in Germany last month—here’s the best of their shared wisdom. https://www.wired.com/listicle/8-lessons-fixing-cities-future/

June 6, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Logistical Miracle of Cramming 80,000 People Into Bonnaroo The tiny town of Manchester, Tennessee suddenly gains 80,000 people. Here’s how they handle all that traffic. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/bonnaroo-traffic-planning/

June 6, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Parking a Truck Is a Pain in the Butt. Tech to the Rescue! But Minnesota has a high-tech solution a low-tech problem: Finding a place to sleep. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/parking-truck-pain-butt-tech-rescue/

June 5, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Inside Top Gear’s Wild Race Through the Desert in an Ariel Nomad Behind the scenes of Matt LeBlanc’s romp through the Moroccan desert in an Ariel Nomad. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/top-gear-raced-wild-ariel-nomad-desert/

June 3, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Morgan’s Wooden Three-Wheeler Is the Eccentric’s Electric The EV3 is an eccentric contribution to the auto industry’s shift away from internal combustion engine. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/morgans-wooden-three-wheeler-eccentrics-electric/

June 2, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies It’s Actually NBD Automakers Still Use Airbags the Feds Will Recall—For Now A new report says some automakers are still using Takata airbags on new cars, but they’re not dangerous just yet. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/automakers-still-using-takata-air-bags-the-feds-will-recall-but-its-ok/

June 1, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Airbus Wants to Replace Satellites With High-Flying Drones Airbus is just one of several companies racing to produce high-flying, long duration drones that can replace satellites without going into space. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/airbus-new-drones-actually-high-flying-pseudo-satellites/

June 1, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Best Way Through the Alps Is the World’s Longest Rail Tunnel After 17 years in the making, the Gotthard Base Tunnel opens to train traffic today. https://www.wired.com/listicle/switzerlands-35-mile-tunnel-alps-finally-opens-business/

June 1, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Best Way Through the Alps Is the World’s Longest Rail Tunnel After 17 years in the making, the Gotthard Base Tunnel opens to train traffic today. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/switzerlands-35-mile-tunnel-alps-finally-opens-business/

May 31, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall 10 Instagram Accounts to Feed Your Inner Transportation Nerd All the big, beautiful trains, planes, buses, and infrastructure projects worthy of your perfectly-curated feed. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/10-instagram-follows-feed-inner-transportation-nerd/

May 31, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall 10 Instagram Accounts to Feed Your Inner Transportation Nerd All the big, beautiful trains, planes, buses, and infrastructure projects worthy of your perfectly-curated feed. https://www.wired.com/listicle/10-instagram-follows-feed-inner-transportation-nerd/

May 31, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall 10 Instagram Accounts to Feed Your Inner Transportation Nerd All the big, beautiful trains, planes, buses, and infrastructure projects worthy of your perfectly-curated feed. https://www.wired.com/dummy-identifier-2016/05/10-instagram-follows-feed-inner-transportation-nerd/

May 30, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Bruges Built an Underground Beer Pipeline to Improve Traffic A challenging task in a city that’s designated a UNESCO World Heritage site. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/bruges-built-underground-beer-pipeline-improve-traffic/

May 29, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies One of the World’s First Aircraft Comes Back to Life (Bowtie Included) German researchers have recreated the glider flown by aviation pioneer Otto Lilienthal. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/researchers-rebuild-otto-lilienthal-glider/

May 28, 2016 | Author: Jonathan WelshJonathan Welsh In a World of Self-Driving Cars, We’ll Still Need the Miata What will you do when driving becomes a pastime instead of a necessity? https://www.wired.com/2016/05/world-self-driving-cars-well-still-need-miatas/

May 27, 2016 | Author: Emma Grey EllisEmma Grey Ellis 8 Wild Ideas That Debuted at the Indy 500, From Seat Belts to Mirrors If you think the Indy 500 hasn’t impacted your life, pump your brakes, buckle your seat belt, or look in your rearview mirror. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/8-wild-ideas-debuted-indy-500-seat-belts-mirrors/

May 27, 2016 | Author: Emma Grey EllisEmma Grey Ellis 8 Wild Ideas That Debuted at the Indy 500, From Seat Belts to Mirrors If you think the Indy 500 hasn’t impacted your life, pump your brakes, buckle your seat belt, or look in your rearview mirror. https://www.wired.com/listicle/8-wild-ideas-debuted-indy-500-seat-belts-mirrors/

May 27, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Detroit’s Grand Plan to Lead the Self-Driving Revolution Proposed legislation could make Michigan the best place in the country to test and commercialize autonomous vehicles. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/detroit-wants-go-spot-self-driving-tech-big-automakers/

May 26, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Woeful TSA Doesn’t Need More Staff. It Needs This Tech Incorporating the latest technology and a better understanding of human behavior could eliminate the worst parts of passing through airport security. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/forget-extra-staffers-fix-tsa-technologies/

May 25, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall A Clever New Kind of Intersection Kicks Risky Left Turns to the Curb The diverging diamond interchange is having a moment. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/clever-new-intersection-kicks-risky-left-turns-curb/

May 25, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Matt LeBlanc (Yes, Joey From Friends) Is Just the Guy to Resurrect Top Gear Can the sitcom star take the place of the much-loved Jeremy Clarkson? https://www.wired.com/2016/05/matt-leblanc-joey-friends-just-guy-make-love-cars/

May 24, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart We Drive an All-Electric Ferrari, The Car that Shouldn’t Exist With three motors instead of a V8, this 1978 Ferrari 308GTS runs on nothing but electricity. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/drive-electric-ferrari-car-shouldnt-exist/

May 23, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Bell’s Moto Helmet Fits All the Funny-Shaped Heads Out There Bell Helmets takes data from customer head scans to offer better fitting helmets. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/challenge-making-motorcycle-helmet-thatll-fit-anyone/

May 23, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall America’s Heinous Commutes, Mapped in Pretty GIFs Some commutes are hellish. Some are delightful. On this map, they’re all beautiful. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/maps-turn-terrible-commutes-mesmerizing-gifs/

May 20, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Google’s Got Better Ways to Protect Pedestrians Than Glue-Covered Cars Google engineers believe coating the front of a car with adhesive could improve road safety, but it’s not the best way to tackle the problem. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/googles-got-better-ways-protect-pedestrians-glue-covered-cars/

May 20, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall LA’s New Metro Line Won’t Reduce Traffic—And That’s OK There are plenty of other reasons to get behind public transit. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/las-new-metro-line-wont-reduce-traffic-thats-ok/

May 20, 2016 | Author: Earl BlumenauerEarl Blumenauer Let’s Use Self-Driving Cars to Fix America’s Busted Infrastructure The death spiral of the gas tax demands we reform federal transportation funding, harness emerging technology, and guide the autonomous vehicle revolution. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/lets-use-self-driving-cars-fix-americas-busted-infrastructure/

May 19, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Here’s How Experts Will Investigate EgyptAir 804’s Crash While none of these situations are alike, the investigation follows a set playbook, written to make sure all potential evidence is found and considered. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/heres-experts-will-investigate-egyptair-804s-crash/

May 19, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams DHL’s Tilt-Rotor ‘Parcelcopter’ Is Both Awesome and Actually Useful In a three-month test earlier this year, DHL used a drone to move more than 100 packages between towns in the Bavarian Alps. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/dhls-new-drone-can-ship-packages-around-alps/

May 18, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Hoverboard Has Arrived. If Only Someone Could Make It Useful Unless you’re Justin Bieber, you may never get your hoverboard. And that’s okay. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/hoverboard-just-not-useful-yet/

May 18, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The Obsessive, Secretive Race to Make the Perfect Tire for Electric Cars Designing tires for electric vehicles is extra complicated, because they demand more of everything. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/hidden-battle-make-perfect-tires-electric-car-divas/

May 17, 2016 | Author: WIRED StaffWIRED Staff Watch the World’s Most Jumbo-Est Jet Take Off. Barely. The massive Antonov An-225 caused a stir in Australia this week when it touched down in Perth. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/antonov-225-mirya-perth-australia-traffic/

May 17, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Private Jets Get the Door-Sized Windows They Always Needed Embraer business jet customers can now orders windows the size of standard exit door. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/private-jets-get-door-sized-windows-always-needed/

May 17, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart $30K Retrofit Turns Dumb Semis Into Self-Driving Robots A new startup called Otto is promising an autonomous kit than can make existing trucks drive themselves. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/otto-retrofit-autonomous-self-driving-trucks/

May 16, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Darpa Wants an Underwater GPS System for Seafaring Robots GPS doesn’t penetrate the briny deep, so Darpa wants a system that will keep the its ocean-exploring robots on the map. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/darpa-wants-underwater-gps-system-seafaring-robots/

May 16, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Forget Elon’s Batteries—Fix the Grid With a Rock-Filled Train on a Hill The Advanced Rail Energy Storage is a 19th century solution for a 21st century problem. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/forget-elons-batteries-fix-grid-rock-filled-train-hill/

May 13, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Feds Are Arming Themselves to Drive Drones Out of Airports The feds are trying out different drone detection systems airports could use to keep the pesky UAVs away from passenger planes. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/feds-arming-drive-drones-airports/

May 12, 2016 | Author: Lawrence GoldstoneLawrence Goldstone The Tale of a Wild Coast-to-Coast Road Trip … in 1903 In 1903, two men spent 71 days driving a Packard Model F across the US—before most of the West even had paved roads. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/tale-epic-coast-coast-road-trip-1903/

May 12, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Peek Inside London’s Epic New Train System Before It Opens A $21 billion infrastructure project is starting to look real. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/peek-inside-londons-epic-new-train-system-opens/

May 12, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Age of the Hyperloop Has Arrived. Well, for the Most Part The futuristic transportation of tomorrow that billionaire rocketeer Elon Musk dreamed up in 2012 passed its first test Wednesday. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/age-hyperloop-arrived-well-part/

May 11, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Adorable, Mildly Confused Seniors Love This Self-Driving Car A group of seniors got to test drive a self-driving car at the University of California San Diego campus. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/adorable-mildly-confused-seniors-love-self-driving-car/

May 11, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Sticking Two Elevators in One Shaft Is Totally Safe—And a Great Idea Thyssenkrupp’s Twin system packs twice the number of cabins into your standard human chute. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/thyssenkrup-twin-elevator/

May 11, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Logitech Finally Made a Useful, Sexy Phone Dash-Mount LogiTech’s new phone mount and app make any vehicle with a dashboard a connected car. https://www.wired.com/listicle/logitech-finally-made-useful-sexy-phone-dash-mount/

May 11, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Logitech Finally Made a Useful, Sexy Phone Dash-Mount LogiTech’s new phone mount and app make any vehicle with a dashboard a connected car. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/logitech-finally-made-useful-sexy-phone-dash-mount/

May 10, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Why Only Israel Can Customize America’s F-35 (At Least for Now) The US doesn’t want other countries messing with the F-35—but Israel gets special privileges. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/israel-can-customize-americas-f-35-least-now/

May 10, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart The Elegant Tech That May Make the Hyperloop a Reality A company trying to build the Hyperloop has dusted off an old, little known technology that’s key to levitation. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/elegant-tech-may-make-hyperloop-reality/

May 9, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart This Startup Wants to Use Drones to Drop Blood, Not Bombs A California startup is deploying a fleet of UAVs to deliver blood and other medical supplies in rural Rwanda. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/zipline-drones-rwanda/

May 6, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Fly Through the Massive Tunnel They’re Carving Under Seattle Some progress on the notorious infrastructure project carving its way under Seattle. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/fly-massive-tunnel-theyre-carving-seattle/

May 5, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Tesla Just Made Its Huge Model 3 Challenge Even Huger Tesla faces a huge challenge when it starts making the Model 3, but Musk and Company are on the right track so far. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/tesla-just-made-huge-model-3-challenge-even-huger/

May 5, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Porsche Embraces Satan, Goes Full-Tilt With Turbochargers In giving up natural aspiration, Porsche’s engineers took on the challenge of history. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/porsche-embraces-satan-goes-full-tilt-turbochargers/

May 4, 2016 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Google’s Self-Driving Minivan Could Bring Autonomy to Us All Google’s going to turn Chrysler’s new minivan into an autonomous test mule. And not just for parents. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/google-self-driving-minivans/

May 4, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Raising Speed Limits Is Irresponsible, But States Keep Doing It Anyway And research estimates more people might die because of it. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/raising-speed-limits-irresponsible-states-keep-anyway/

May 3, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Ford’s New Raptor Is a Dirt-Shredding, Turbocharged Monster If you thought the civilian version of the Ford F-150 was a bit much, it’s time you met the Raptor. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/fords-new-raptor-dirt-shredding-turbocharged-monster/

May 3, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Self-Driving Car of the Future Comes With … a Bookshelf In the “Etos” concept, Harman and Rinspeed explore what the inside of a car looks like when the human’s no longer needed. https://www.wired.com/listicle/self-driving-car-future-comes-bookshelf/

May 3, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Self-Driving Car of the Future Comes With … a Bookshelf In the “Etos” concept, Harman and Rinspeed explore what the inside of a car looks like when the human’s no longer needed. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/self-driving-car-future-comes-bookshelf/

May 2, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Plan to ‘Textalyze’ Distracted Drivers’ Phones Is Dumb and Doomed Not everything that worked against drunk driving can help solve the problem of distracted driving. https://www.wired.com/2016/05/plan-textalyze-distracted-drivers-phones-dumb-doomed/

April 28, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Insane ‘Swooping’ Skydiving Makes Your Tandem Jump Look Lame In canopy piloting, the goal isn’t to get to the ground safely. It’s to get there as quickly as possible. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/insane-swooping-skydiving-makes-tandem-jump-look-lame/

April 28, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The World’s Hugest Jet Engine Is Wider Than a 737’s Fuselage With the GE9X, General Electric proves size matters. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/worlds-hugest-jet-engine-wider-737s-fuselage/

April 28, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Kansas’ Roads Are All Goofy Because Nature Always Pwns Logic Early surveyors in the Midwest relied on straight lines that intersect at 90-degree angles, forming the Midwest’s grid. But the world is not flat. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/kansas-roads-goofy-nature-always-pwns-logic/

April 27, 2016 | Author: April GlaserApril Glaser Autonomous Tech Could Make Driving Semi-Trucks Even Less Fun In 10 years, truckers could find themselves handling customer service calls for Postmates or Mechanical Turk-ing for Amazon from the cab of their semis. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/autonomous-tech-make-driving-semi-trucks-even-less-fun/

April 26, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies What It’s like to Fly a Solar Plane With a Coffin-Sized Cockpit Pilots Bertrand Piccard and André Borschberg show off the massive solar panel-covered wings of the Solar Impulse 2 plane and inside its cramped cockpit. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/solar-impulse-2-discomforts-and-thrills-of-flying-a-solar-powered-plane/

April 26, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla’s Model X Has Bigger Problems Than Faulty Falcon Doors Tesla’s famed for its rapidly satisfied customers, but complaints about the Model X SUV are piling up. https://www.wired.com/dummy-identifier-2016/04/teslas-model-x-bigger-problems-faulty-falcon-doors/

April 26, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla’s Model X Has Bigger Problems Than Faulty Falcon Doors Tesla’s famed for its rapidly satisfied customers, but complaints about the Model X SUV are piling up. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/teslas-model-x-bigger-problems-faulty-falcon-doors/

April 26, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla’s Model X Has Bigger Problems Than Faulty Falcon Doors Tesla’s famed for its rapidly satisfied customers, but complaints about the Model X SUV are piling up. https://www.wired.com/listicle/teslas-model-x-bigger-problems-faulty-falcon-doors/

April 25, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Widening Highways Never Fixes Traffic. But Darnit, It Did in Texas Expanding highways is rarely the answer. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/widening-highways-never-fixes-traffic-darnit-texas/

April 23, 2016 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton VW’s Bleak Options for Dealing With 500,000 Recalled Diesels Emissions cheat Volkswagon is recalling nearly 500,000 cars, most of which will need to be broken down and scrapped for parts. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/vws-bleak-options-dealing-500000-recalled-diesels/

April 22, 2016 | Author: Madison KotackMadison Kotack Don’t Text and Drive, or the Feds Will Slide Into Your DMs The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration has been reprimanding the distracted drivers of Twitter all month–and people are actually listening. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/dont-text-drive-feds-will-slide-dms/

April 22, 2016 | Author: Ben CollinsBen Collins Top Gear’s Stig Schools Us in Racing With … a Go-Kart Former Top Gear Stig Ben Collins lays out his wisdom in a new book, and on the go-kart track. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/top-gears-stig-schools-us-racing-go-kart/

April 21, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The Totally Unnecessary Elegance of Rolls-Royce’s Silent Roof The drop top on the new Dawn is the epitome of Rolls-Royce: a robustly engineered system that feels as though it’s not even there. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/totally-unnecessary-elegance-rolls-royces-silent-roof/

April 21, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall See How Your Town’s Transit Stacks Up to Hundreds of Other Cities An unprecedentedly large and national transit data set takes the temperature of your local transit agencies. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/see-towns-transit-stacks-hundreds-cities/

April 20, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies VW Will Buy Back Your Cheating, Polluting Diesel Volkswagen will offer to buy back the nearly 500,000 diesel cars it illegally programmed to cheat on emissions tests, Reuters reports. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/vw-will-offer-buy-back-cheating-polluting-diesels/

April 19, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall What It Takes to Keep a 7,700-Foot Floating Bridge From Doom The science of floating concrete bridges, courtesy of the people who do it best. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/takes-keep-7700-foot-floating-bridge-doom/

April 19, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams How on God’s Green Earth Is the B-52 Still in Service? The B-52’s now in action fighting ISIS—and could spend another 40 years in the air. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/gods-green-earth-b-52-still-service/

April 18, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Tesla’s Self-Driving Heroics Aren’t Special—They’re Normal The really remarkable news is that this technology will be far from miraculous in just a few short years. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/tesla-autopilots-hero-moment-just-taste-whats-come/

April 18, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Please Let These Meganormous Screens Be the Future of Flying Thales’ “Digital Sky” concept uses Tesla-inspired screens to make flying economy more bearable. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/please-let-meganormous-screens-future-flying/

April 17, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Photos: Revel in the Evolution of Porsche’s Iconic Turbo Since the 1970s, Porsche has used turbochargers to dominate the track and the street. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/photos-revel-evolution-porsches-iconic-turbo/

April 15, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall ESPN Has Decided Drone Racing Is a Sport Because Internet By taking on drone racing, ESPN makes a bet on the digital generation. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/espn-decided-drone-racing-sport-internet/

April 15, 2016 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Want a Bike-Friendly City? Get Ready to Fail Until It Works How to do the unthinkable: fast-track an infrastructure project in your city. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/how-to-make-bike-friendly-city/

April 15, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies After a Long Delay, Solar Impulse 2 Is Ready to Finish Its Round-the-World Flight The sun-powered Solar Impulse 2 is back in action after a nine-month break for technical repairs. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/long-delay-solar-impulse-2-ready-finish-round-world-flight/

April 14, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies A Clever Headrest That Could Make Flying Actually Bearable The simple, folding headrest creates an instant hammock to keep you from drooling on your neighbors. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/clever-headrest-make-flying-actually-bearable/

April 13, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Darpa’s Developing Tiny Drones That Swarm to and From Motherships Darpa’s new “Gremlins” program will create swarms of drones that will be dropped off and picked up by other planes. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/darpas-developing-tiny-drones-swarm-motherships/

April 13, 2016 | Author: Laura MalloneeLaura Mallonee People Sure Get Creative With the Space Under Highway Overpasses For most people, highways and bridges are just a way to get from Point A to Point B. Nobody thinks about what’s underneath. Except Gisela Erlacher. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/gisela-erlacherthe-skies-of-concrete-unique-urban-spaces-underneath-the-worlds-highways/

April 13, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies How Tesla Keeps Changing the Model S—And Making It Pricier Since the luxury electric sedan hit the market in 2012, it’s changed in lots of ways, and not purely for the better. https://www.wired.com/listicle/tesla-keeps-making-model-s-better-better-pricier/

April 13, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies How Tesla Keeps Changing the Model S—And Making It Pricier Since the luxury electric sedan hit the market in 2012, it’s changed in lots of ways, and not purely for the better. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/tesla-keeps-making-model-s-better-better-pricier/

April 13, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies How Tesla Keeps Changing the Model S—And Making It Pricier Since the luxury electric sedan hit the market in 2012, it’s changed in lots of ways, and not purely for the better. https://www.wired.com/dummy-identifier-2016/04/tesla-keeps-making-model-s-better-better-pricier/

April 12, 2016 | Author: Edward HumesEdward Humes Your iPhone’s 500,000-Mile Journey to Your Pocket That iPhone you just bought has a transportation footprint at least as great as a 240,000-mile trip to the moon, and most or all of the way back. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/iphones-500000-mile-journey-pocket/

April 11, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies 8 Smart Ways to Make Flying Less Sucky This year’s Crystal Cabin Awards point to some exciting developments for everyone who flies, economy or otherwise. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/crystal-cabin-awards/

April 11, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies 8 Smart Ways to Make Flying Less Sucky This year’s Crystal Cabin Awards point to some exciting developments for everyone who flies, economy or otherwise. https://www.wired.com/listicle/crystal-cabin-awards/

April 8, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Shades Are So 2015. These Airplane Windows Tint Themselves Plastic shades are for lameoids—the real way to block the sun is with a window that goes from transparent to opaque using microscopic particles. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/shades-2015-airplane-windows-tint/

April 6, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies 100 Lucky Drivers in China Will Get to Test Volvo’s Self-Driving Cars Volvo plans to put 100 Chinese customers into its self-driving cars for a longterm beta test. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/volvos-gonna-put-chinese-customers-self-driving-cars/

April 6, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams American Cities Are Nowhere Near Ready for Self-Driving Cars Researchers think self-driving cars are going to change everything about urban living, and they’re trying to make sure we’re ready. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/american-cities-nowhere-near-ready-self-driving-cars/

April 5, 2016 | Author: Jenna GarrettJenna Garrett Elefantentreffen Is the Most Bizarre Motorcycle Rally You’ve Never Heard Of Each year, thousands of motorcycle riders descend upon a clearing the middle of the Bavarian Forest for a three-day extravaganza. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/alessandro-dangelo-elefantentreffen-bizarre-motorcycle-rally-youve-never-heard/

March 31, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Meet Tesla’s Model 3, Its Long-Awaited Car for the Masses The Model 3—the most important car in the brief, volatile history of Tesla Motors—has arrived. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/meet-teslas-model-3-long-awaited-car-masses/

March 31, 2016 | Author: WIRED StaffWIRED Staff Liveblog: Tesla Unveils the Model 3, Its Much-Anticipated $30k EV We’re live in Hawthorne, CA as Tesla CEO Elon Musk unveils his sub-$30,000 electric car, the Model 3. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/liveblog-get-first-glimpse-teslas-30000-model-3/

March 31, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Sorry, But Don’t Expect Your Tesla Model 3 to Cost Under $30K If you’re planning to preorder a Tesla Model 3, here’s what you should know. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/sorry-dont-expect-tesla-model-3-cost-30k/

March 30, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Roborace’s Self-Driving Race Car Is Every Kind of Absurd Roborace has unveiled a race car that’s as crazy as its dream of autonomous car racing. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/crazy-self-driving-racing-series-deserves-crazy-car/

March 28, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Steve Urkel’s Isetta Finds Second Life as a Teensy Electric Car A Swiss scooter company redesigned the funky Isetta as a 21st-century urban dwelling EV. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/microlino-modern-bmw-isetta/

March 25, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams 10 Outstanding Cars That Stole the New York Auto Show From hyper-efficient sedans to high-performance machines, these are the best cars to see at the New York International Auto Show. https://www.wired.com/listicle/10-outstanding-cars-stole-new-york-auto-show/

March 25, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams 10 Outstanding Cars That Stole the New York Auto Show From hyper-efficient sedans to high-performance machines, these are the best cars to see at the New York International Auto Show. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/10-outstanding-cars-stole-new-york-auto-show/

March 24, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Lincoln’s Yacht-Sized Concept SUV Has a Closet and Staircase If you want to see the future of luxury cars, Ford’s packed them all into this enormous truck. https://www.wired.com/listicle/lincolns-yacht-sized-concept-suv-closet-staircase/

March 24, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Lincoln’s Yacht-Sized Concept SUV Has a Closet and Staircase If you want to see the future of luxury cars, Ford’s packed them all into this enormous truck. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/lincolns-yacht-sized-concept-suv-closet-staircase/

March 23, 2016 | Author: Ashley NunesAshley Nunes Fantastic Tech Is Making Pilot Fatigue Even More Perplexing Fatigue remains a problem for pilots and a risk to the flying public, but incomplete science and the positive effect of aviation technology make the best solutions hard to see. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/fantastic-tech-making-pilot-fatigue-even-perplexing/

March 21, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Boeing’s Monstrous Underwater Robot Can Wander the Ocean for 6 Months Boeing’s Echo Voyager can spend six months at sea by itself, with 7,500 miles of range. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/boeings-monstrous-underwater-robot-can-wander-ocean-6-months/

March 18, 2016 | Author: Missy CummingsMissy Cummings America, Regulate Drones Now or Get Left Behind To reap the benefits of the drone boom boom, and ward off its downsides, American regulators must produce clear and directed policies. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/america-regulate-drones-now-get-left-behind/

March 18, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Google and the Feds Team Up to Build the City of the Future The DOT and Sidewalk Labs are creating a data platform to help cities and urban dwellers move more efficiently. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/google-feds-team-build-city-future/

March 17, 2016 | Author: Davey AlbaDavey Alba BART’s Righteous Tweetstorm Reminds Us Its Problems Are Our Fault And we should own up to it. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/barts-righteous-tweetstorm-reminds-us-problems-fault/

March 17, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Uber Actually Makes Public Transit Better, But Mostly for the Rich Uber or Lyft clearly help riders who can afford them, but it’s not clear how to extend those advantages to the poor, the elderly, or those with disabilities. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/uber-actually-makes-public-transit-better-youre-rich/

March 17, 2016 | Author: WIRED StaffWIRED Staff Go Inside the Factory Where Acura Builds the NSX Supercar We stepped inside Acura’s new plant to see how it builds the new NSX supercar. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/go-inside-factory-acura-builds-nsx-supercar/

March 17, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Step Inside the Factory Where Acura Crafts the NSX Supercar Before making the NSX supercar, Acura made an achingly bright, eat off the robots clean, assembly line in Marysville, Ohio. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/step-inside-factory-acura-crafts-nsx-supercar/

March 17, 2016 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams Step Inside the Factory Where Acura Crafts the NSX Supercar Before making the NSX supercar, Acura made an achingly bright, eat off the robots clean, assembly line in Marysville, Ohio. https://www.wired.com/listicle/step-inside-factory-acura-crafts-nsx-supercar/

March 16, 2016 | Author: Jenna GarrettJenna Garrett Dreamy Portraits of LA’s Cars as They Sleep at Night There are some 7.5 million vehicles in Los Angeles. Photographer Gerd Ludwig captures them when they’re all asleep. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/gerd-ludwig-sleeping-cars/

March 15, 2016 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler DC’s Metro Shutdown Is Mortifying, But at Least No One Will Die DC’s subway system is about to close for 29 hours, but don’t panic. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/dcs-metro-shutdown-mortifying-least-no-one-will-die/

March 15, 2016 | Author: Andrew Ng, Yuanqing LinAndrew Ng and Yuanqing Lin Self-Driving Cars Won’t Work Until We Change Our Roads—And Attitudes We should make modest changes to our infrastructure, emphasize predictable behavior, and teach the public new ways to interact with autonomous vehicles. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/self-driving-cars-wont-work-change-roads-attitudes/

March 14, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies This Guy’s Gonna Use Jets to Ski at 156 MPH. And No, He Isn’t Wile E. Coyote Former Olympian Graham Bell wants to hit 156 mph on skis, thanks to jet power. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/guys-gonna-use-jets-ski-156-mph-no-isnt-wile-e-coyote/

March 11, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies GM Takes Another Smart Step Toward Autonomous Robo-Cars GM is acquiring Cruise Automation to help it make truly autonomous driving happen. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/gm-takes-another-smart-step-toward-autonomous-robo-cars/

March 11, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Slovakia Is a Natural First Stop for the Hyperloop—No Joke Despite what Elon Musk has said, running from San Francisco to Los Angeles would be a terrible way to start building the Hyperloop. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/slovakia-great-first-stop-hyperloop-no-joke/

March 10, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Tesla’s Summon Feature Is Like Knight Rider. Kinda Summon is fundamental to Tesla’s goal of making its cars drive themselves, and it won’t stay a party trick forever. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/teslas-summon-feature-like-knight-rider-kinda/

March 9, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Ford Reckons Your Self-Driving Car Needs a Movie Projector Ford received a patent this week for an “autonomous vehicle entertainment system” that’s basically a big projector screen. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/ford-reckons-self-driving-car-needs-movie-projector/

March 8, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Everything We Know About MH370 Two years ago, Malaysia Airlines Flight 370 vanished. History’s largest and costliest search has also been among its most frustrating and beguiling. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/everything-know-mh370/

March 8, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Two Pilots Say They Can Find MH370. All They Need Is $5 Million The man with a theory of what happened to Malaysia Airlines flight 370 thinks he knows where it crashed, and he’s starting a private effort to go get it. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/pilots-say-know-mh370-need-5-million/

March 4, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Boeing’s Self-Cleaning Bathroom Would Nuke Germs With UV Rays Boeing has made a prototype bathroom that uses ultraviolet light to zap 99.99 percent of germs your fellow flyers leave behind, in just three seconds. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/boeings-self-cleaning-bathroom-nuke-germs-uv-rays/

March 3, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies These Are the 11 Most Ridiculous Cars at the Geneva Motor Show Geneva’s always about excessive supercars, but this year was something else entirely. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/11-coolest-cars-geneva-motor-show/

March 2, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Looks Like They Found Another Piece of MH370 Officials believe a piece of debris that washed up on the shores of Mozambique this weekend belongs to Malaysia Airlines Flight 370. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/looks-like-found-another-piece-mh370/

March 2, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The DB11 Is the Car That Could Save Aston Martin The DB9 successor spearheads the brand’s “second century plan,” which is all about investing to stay competitive. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/aston-martins-new-db11-important-car-ever/

March 1, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies How Bugatti Crafted the Chiron, the World’s Last Truly Great Car The Chiron represents a new summit, but it’s not a peak others are pursuing anymore. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/bugatti-crafted-chiron-worlds-last-truly-great-car/

March 1, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Lamborghini Centenario Celebrates 100 Years of Obscenity the $1.9 million, limited editions supercar carries the most powerful engine the brand’s ever produced. https://www.wired.com/2016/03/lamborghini-centenario-celebrates-100-years-obscenity/

February 29, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Google’s Self-Driving Car Caused Its First Crash Google’s self-driving car appears to have caused its first crash on February 14, when it changed lanes and put itself in the path of an oncoming bus. https://www.wired.com/2016/02/googles-self-driving-car-may-caused-first-crash/

February 26, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies America’s Next Great Boondoggle—Er, Bomber—Is on Its Way The B-21 bomber has been officially revealed. https://www.wired.com/2016/02/americas-next-great-boondoggle-er-bomber-way/

February 26, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Relentless Tinkering That Makes F1 Cars Look So Funky The technical head of Mercedes’ championship-winning F1 team shows us how that evolution happens. https://www.wired.com/2016/02/relentless-tinkering-makes-f1-cars-look-funky/

February 25, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Electric Car Revolution Is Now Scheduled for 2022 A new study says that in just six years, battery-powered cars will be as affordable as their gas-guzzling counterparts. https://www.wired.com/2016/02/electric-car-revolution-now-scheduled-2022/

February 24, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies McLaren’s New 570GT Is a Comfier Supercar for an Oligarch on a Budget The new 570GT is the third model in McLaren’s Sports Series, the brand’s more affordable cars that aren’t quite as ludicrous as its most powerful products. https://www.wired.com/2016/02/mclarens-new-570gt-comfier-supercar-oligarch-budget/

February 23, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Bench Seating Is the Latest Idea to Make Flying Even More Horrible Airbus just patented a reconfigurable bench seat to make airplane seating more flexible. https://www.wired.com/2016/02/bench-seating-is-the-latest-idea-to-make-flying-even-more-horrible/

February 23, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Google’s City-Fixing ‘Sidewalk Labs’ Is Finally Getting to Work Nearly a year after launching, Google’s urban-facing initiative has hired a team and is getting to work. https://www.wired.com/2016/02/googles-city-fixing-sidewalk-labs-is-finally-getting-to-work/

February 22, 2016 | Author: Jordan CrucchiolaJordan Crucchiola Ford’s ‘Diabolical’ Testing Grounds Feature Potholes From Around the World Americans are spending $3 billion each year on damage caused by potholes. That likely won’t get better soon. https://www.wired.com/2016/02/fords-diabolical-testing-grounds-feature-potholes-from-around-the-world/

February 21, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Volvo Ditches the Car Key to Make Way for the Future By moving the key’s functions onto the phone, Volvo has further cleared the path for the future of cars. https://www.wired.com/2016/02/volvo-kills-the-car-key-to-make-way-for-the-future/

February 19, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Formula One Is Talking About Closing the Cockpit (Again) A new design from Red Bull is the latest salvo in the debate over whether to give up one a hallmarks of F1: the use of open cockpit cars. https://www.wired.com/2016/02/formula-one-is-talking-about-closing-the-cockpit-again/

February 18, 2016 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Copenhagen’s New Traffic Lights Recognize and Favor Cyclists By the end of this year, Copenhagen wants to cut down bus travel times by five to 20 percent, and cycling travel times by 10 percent. https://www.wired.com/2016/02/copenhagens-new-traffic-lights-recognize-and-favor-cyclists/